FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Gourmet! Coral Lobsters
The plan to steal the African Star,
worth several million dollars.
No good.
The Inca treasure,
Mermaid's Tear, also failed.
Ruby chandelier and
Yang Guifei's eyes also failed.
Even though we've made
so many plans, they all failed!
This is no time for taking a nap.
If you don't get serious,
we're going back to being pirates.
You startled me!
I'm awake and now I'm hungry.
I feel like eating some fresh
and delicious lobster.
Hey, let's not joke like that.
I want higher pay
and more interesting work.
That's 20 to 30 million
pounds worth of lobsters.
Just follow me!
Is he still dreaming?
Why would lobster be worth so much?
How's it going?
I'm done here.
Oh, you fixed it.
I just finished now.
Thank you for everything.
All right then.
Wait just a minute.
What's in here?
Nothing!
Excuse me, but I have to make sure.
Make sure?
Oh, make sure.
I'm ticklish.
Is something wrong
with the both of you?
Well, not really.
We're both just highly ticklish people.
Yes, yes we are.
Well, see you.
If Mrs. Hudson hadn't insisted,
we'd never have gone so far as this.
I can see Mr. Bridon's house now.
By the way, did you know Mrs. Hudson's
friend is a marine biologist?
Of course.
And he's also a jewellery collector.
Wonderful, this collection is
far more grand than I'd heard.
But, despite their great value...
is there anyone really
interested in stealing fish?
Look at these.
It's all crafted with
rubies and emeralds.
They're all valued
at several million pounds.
Several million pounds?
These are...
Ocean Princess lobsters from Spain.
These lobsters are worth
20 to 30 million pounds.
20 to 30 million pounds?
Their bodies are all made of coral and
each of the eyes is a five-carat diamond.
I see. Now I understand why you set
up such an advanced alarm system.
That's right. This is the first alarm
system of its kind in England.
From the criminologist perspective...
I'd like both of you to check and
see if this system is flawless.
Is this worth 20 to 30 million pounds?
Ouch!
The system reacts to even subtle
changes in water temperature.
I'm surprised.
If this system was adopted across
England, the crime rate might...
It can't be!
Oh, what?
Yes, what?
I don't believe it,
but I just saw it move.
They're alive!
They're all ordinary lobsters!
Your security system
wasn't perfect after all.
Ordinary lobsters!
Delicious! Delicious!
Having lobster after five years...
tastes really good!
Get 20 or 30 million pounds
by eating lobster!
What?
It's not worth showing
this to you guys.
Oh, I'm very hungry.
Hey, we want to eat lobster, too.
We want lobster!
Lobster!
No!
How come?
Who could have broken
into this secure room?
They came down from there.
It can't be!
If they drop them in the ocean,
they'll be difficult to find.
Won't they?
Yes.
This is paint.
Paint? What do you mean?
Maybe they put duplicate lobsters
in a small box...
and then brought them
through this window.
A small box might float.
Did you notice anything unusual
after you set up the alarm system?
Did anybody come through?
I remember electricians came by
to fix the chandelier this morning.
Electricians?
But when they left, I checked
their clothes and tools thoroughly.
Why did you wake me up
so early in the morning?
It's Holmes' prototype Benz!
Everybody!
Work harder and don't let Holmes
get ahead of us!
Yes, sir!
Inspector, we can't find them
anywhere in the mansion.
Ouch!
Idiots!
What are you looking at?!
Be serious!
We checked the garbage cans in the
kitchen and the bathroom, too!
That's not enough!
Check under the roof
and look under the floor!
I still haven't eaten breakfast.
Since we haven't been able
to find them here...
I assume they've already been
taken out of the mansion.
But this place is on a sharp cliff.
Inspector, no one can
enter through iron bars.
Look.
If someone could enter
the room from the sky...
Ouch!
Outrageous!
Hey!
Come back here!
Damn it!
Somebody, please pull me in!
My head is stuck.
Ouch! Ouch!
Idiots!
My head will come off!
Take your hands off of me!
What is it?
I think this must be it.
This paint was on the iron bars.
Is that a piece of a balloon?
Correct. They thought this out.
The suspect must have used this box.
Inspector! Please come with me!
Shoot!
Somebody tied up the electricians
and then dressed up like them.
The only person capable
of something like this is...
Moriarty.
Him?! It must be him!
If that's true,
we just have to arrest him!
Follow me!
What route do you think
Moriarty took to get away?
The problem is how did they get
through the police roadblocks...
and then carry the lobsters
all the way to London.
I don't know.
No suspicious ships came though.
Oh, there was one man who
came to rent a fishing boat.
A fishing boat?
But he came back
without catching any fish.
He bought some lobsters
to bring home with him.
Lobsters?
He bought enough
to fill a horse carriage.
To fill a horse carriage?
He bought that much?
Yes, he picked up a barrel
and put them inside.
I sent it to Torkey
with the other shipments.
That's it. I'm sure that's the one.
What are you talking about?
I think he put them in the barrel
with the real lobsters.
And ran away empty handed,
but very comfortable.
He thought it out well.
I see.
Professor, is this all right,
taking it so easy?
Yes, I wonder if the luggage
will arrive safely.
All the past failures were because
I didn't eat my favourite lobsters.
What?
It's been five years...
I get nutrition by eating lobster.
My brain is working perfectly now.
Is that true?
I didn't eat.
It's time.
Let's go.
Yes, Sir.
Thank you.
Inspector!
What's your status?
Did you find any suspicious people?
Nothing strange at the moment.
Excuse me, but they might have
escaped a long time ago.
You fool!
We closed all the routes
going to London!
Not even a baby could get through.
Hey, is there some
restaurant around here?
There's one close by.
Breakfast!
Inspector! Holmes just went there!
Stop!
Holmes?
And he went to Torkey station,
after that.
Why didn't you say so
in the first place?!
Because, Holmes isn't a suspect.
You!
I assume that a lobster
cargo arrived here.
Yes.
Please wait.
Hey, can you take care of this?
Yes, sir.
It's lobster.
Then, they're in several of these.
If we make this an issue,
we could cause more damage.
Let's choose the right place.
What has Holmes found out?
Start searching, quickly!
Oh, rats!
Professor.
Calm down! They won't find out.
How did they know about this place?
Professor, it's gonna be a problem
if they check the cargo.
It's finished.
Let's go!
You're Smiley!
And you're!
Smiley! Hurry up!
Here!
It's them!
Don't let them go!
Giddy up! Giddy up! Giddy up!
After five years without lobster!
I'll get them no matter what!
Giddy up! Giddy up!
Fool! Be more careful
and go faster!
I can't do that!
We're being chased!
Giddy up!
If you bite off your tongue,
you can't eat lobster!
Hang on tight!
Giddy up! Giddy up!
Giddy up!
We can get ahead of them
by using a different route.
Let's go!
All right!
Go! Go!
We are almost there!
This is bad!
I'm really getting hungry.
Can't you drive with
a little more manners?
You don't need good manners
in front of criminals!
Here we go!
Oops!
Push them over the edge!
They'll fall!
Take that!
Ah! Oh, no!
Hey!
Todd, watch out!
Back up!
Hey, stay back!
Hey, didn't they recognize us?
Look, Watson!
Huh?
See!
There is no doubt we'll be
successful this time.
Where did they go?!
Let's get back to our hideout
before they can catch us.
What?!
They came by sea!
All right!
Go!
Get them this time!
Oh, my precious lobsters!
Oh! Lobsters!
Food!
You fools!
The criminals are over there!
What are you doing?!
Get back quickly!
Ugh, you are all fools!
Get back here now!
Take the land route
and wait for them!
We should chase them, too!
I'm going to send a telegraph.
To where?
What are you trying to do, Professor?
They must have headed to Payneton.
So, if we double back,
nobody will be there.
I see. That's a good idea.
That means you ate lobster again
while I wasn't looking?
You dolt!
My brain is superior to Lestrade's.
Now you can't get to the ocean.
Holmes!
He's nothing like Lestrade.
That's right.
Even better than you, Professor.
Take this!
Now!
Holmes!
Is the telegraph that
I received from Payneton true?
Of course, Moriarty
came back here.
All right!
He's as good as in my hands.
Holmes, over there!
I found you!
Prepare yourself!
I'm always prepared!
Wait!
There!
I'll never forgive you!
I won't let you go!
You obsessive rat!
Take this!
Whoops!
Nyah! Nayh!
Oh shoot!
Professor!
Millions of pounds, gone!
I should have eaten more lobster.
Then this wouldn't have happened!
I can't stand it!
Oh, lobster!
I wanted to eat them!
So many lobsters!
It looks delicious!
Ouch!
I see.
Very well made.
Oh, lobster!
Professor, we're hungry!
We want lobster!
Shut up!!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Professor Moriarty stole gold bullion
from the bank's underground safe.
He wants to make a shining statue
in his own bad taste.
Meanwhile, Holmes is looking
for a missing sculptor.
Can he crush the Professor's scheme?
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Did You See!? The Big Shining Thief