FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Targeted Giant Coin Bank
I don't feel like doing this.
Gilmore is a man who is famous
for being greedy and cruel.
Besides, this letter doesn't
even explain what the case is.
Let's save the fun
until after we arrive.
That appears to be our destination...
the Valley of Gilmore.
Does he really own all of this?
What a dirty city this is!
No one looks very happy.
That's a huge cannon.
A product of the Gilmore Company.
I hear he's exporting
them all over the world.
Oh! What?
Oh, no...
Well, let's get out and push.
What is this?
Let's get started.
Push!
Here we go!
The more we push, the deeper it sinks.
Hey! You guys!
Grab this rope!
Everybody, please help!
Let's do it.
It really is a bad road.
Heave-ho!
Everybody, pull hard!
Well, you really saved us.
It's fortunate you guys
brought extra clothes.
I'll wash these for you.
Why don't you stop by
here on the way back.
Thank you.
But we didn't bring extra hats.
Everyone from out of town
falls in the mud.
We want to fix this road but...
Although, the road is really bad,
the people in this town are very nice.
By the way, is this the road
to the Gilmore's mansion?
You're visiting that mansion?
Yes, we are.
Then wash these yourself?
Don't worry Michael.
It's not your fault.
What's going on?
Suddenly, everyone's...
Did we say something wrong?
You guys!
Looking for the Gilmore mansion,
it's over there!
My goodness.
What is that light?
Brother! Brother!
What is it?
Holmes!
What?!
You're right.
He really is a great detective.
He's already detected us here.
Stupid! Don't admire him!
Ignore him. Just ignore him.
Brother, he came back.
Hello!
What's this contraption for?!
Are you digging a well or something?!
That's right!
Good cover.
Don't laugh!
Since there is so much soil,
it must be a very deep well.
The water level is
very low around here.
I see.
Thanks, sorry to have bothered you.
Let's go to the mansion.
We have to tell the Professor.
Damn!
Loafing at work again, I see!
Professor!
It's Holmes! Holmes is here!
What? Holmes?!
I'm sure he knows already.
Do you want to stop digging?
We've been losing to him recently.
Why you!
How can we stop after
digging so much already!
Stop complaining and get to work!
Yes Sir...
My plan is flawless!
Curse you Holmes!
What is he doing here?
Please wait a moment.
Very well.
I see.
This is the source of the light.
Oh, good boy.
Is this gold plated?
Watson! Watch out!
What are you doing?!
Stop it!
Watson!
Ouch! Ouch! Ouch!
This isn't good!
Holmes!
He must be the
security for this statue.
Mr. Holmes, I presume?
You must be Mr. Gilmore.
It looks just like him.
I called you regarding this coin bank.
Is this statue a coin bank?
Here, I'll show you.
You have quite an interesting hobby.
I know.
This special coin bank is
the most unique in the world.
However...
on the one day of the year,
when I happily count the money...
346,768... 346,769... 346...
Oh, no more!
I'm short of gold coins!
Unbelievably, I was
twenty coins short!
But you're only twenty coins
short out of 300,000 coins...
346,789!
Since then I've done nothing
but worry and I've hardly slept!
I feel very sorry about that.
But I think I'd rather go home.
Wait.
This is an interesting story.
Let me give it a try.
Oh, why?
He only carries gold coins.
He won't even take
food from strangers.
Oh, that makes me even
more curious about this.
Is there anybody else who
is friendly with this bird?
There's only my son, Michael.
I would like to talk to him.
Would you ask him to come?
Be quiet!
Michael is out right now.
He went out?
Is he wandering
around downtown again?
Mr. Gilmore, please understand
Michael's feelings a little more.
I feel sorry for him.
Don't speak so rudely to me!
You are merely his private tutor!
Bring him back here at once!
The detective wants to meet with him!
I'm Holmes.
I'll talk to Michael later.
You can go back now.
Is that downtown over there?
I have been calling
that place downtown.
Everything you can see below
this mansion is all my property.
The town, the factory, the river,
the road are all mine.
And it would become
Michael's property in the future.
But he is really troublesome.
He always supports the poor people.
When did they start digging the well?
Two weeks ago.
Two weeks...
I see.
He's Mr. Gilmore's son, Michael.
Stop that!
It must be fun.
He's different from his father.
He's a good son.
I don't think he's a suspect.
Teacher!
Jim said he has a stomach-ache.
He is not eating.
You have a little fever.
Excuse me.
I may not look like it,
but I'm a doctor.
Do you have a stomach-ache?
Open your mouth and say "Ahhh".
A little more.
You should put him to bed.
Come this way.
Are you going to give Jim a shot?
No, he has to drink bitter medicine.
No! I don't want medicine!
I'm okay now!
My medicine is even
sweeter than honey.
What?! Jim's lucky!
Your friend really helped us.
Please bring my bag.
Yes.
Does Michael visit here often?
Yes, he helps me a lot.
He is a very sweet boy.
It's an honourable job, but it
must be difficult to manage.
No, there's a god who forsakes us
and a god who saves us.
But some stranger donated
twenty pounds recently.
Really? Twenty sovereign gold coins?
Yes, he asked, in a letter, that we
use the money for this place.
That sounds great.
Holmes.
Would you go on back by yourself?
I will stay for a while
and check on his condition.
All right. Please do so.
How is my new invention?
It's twice as faster than before.
But it makes me three
times more tired.
What are you saying?
The whole fun of treasure hunting
is the hard work you do to get it.
Five meters till we
reach the gold statue.
Great! 30 cm per hour!
Oh, it suddenly got easy!
Stop!
Continue.
I worry too much
just waiting like this!
Don't you have any
idea about the thief?!
Mr. Gilmore, what do
you think of this equation?
If you have to dig out soil,
and the height is 10 meters...
and the diameter is 20 meters...
how many meters do you have
to dig to make a tunnel...
that is 3 meters high
and 2 meters wide?
What?
Is that question
related to this case?
No, not directly.
It's thinner than I thought.
I'm paying you a lot of money!
I'll fire you if you don't find
the thief by tomorrow morning!
Perhaps by tonight.
I'll do it as many times as I like.
But this is wrong.
Does that really matter?
It was originally their money anyway.
Even so, do you think
they would be happy...
if they knew you were
getting the money like this?
But now they can buy
medicine and food!
Please stop this.
There is a detective here.
I'm not scared of a detective!
You can't stop me!
If you feel that way
then tell my father!
Michael.
I just can't sleep!
Even at this moment, somebody must
be trying to steal my gold coins!
Michael.
Maria...
You can't stop me.
I'm going with you.
I was the one who showed you
downtown and my mother's orphanage.
That is why you started doing this.
I didn't think you
would suffer this much.
I can at least help by
being a lookout for you.
Maria.
Please wait here. I'll be quick.
Don't say a word!
You burglar!
I finally caught you by the tail.
Go inside quietly.
Come out! Lousy thief!
Hello there.
Holmes!
With the help of Ms. Maria,
I have found the answer.
What?
Maria, please turn on the light.
Yes.
I'll now show you how
the thief stole the gold coins.
Put birdlime on the gold coin.
Here take this.
A big catch!
W... What is this?!
Thank you.
Anyone can make this
bird carry gold coins.
You traitor bird!
So, who's the thief?!
Is it somebody in this house?!
Maria, would you clean up here?
Yes.
You don't have to rush.
Please work quietly.
Yes.
Don't keep me waiting!
Just tell me now!
The thief is Moriarty.
Moriarty?!
Yes.
The famous Professor Moriarty.
People call him the Napoleon
of the crime world.
Don't be ridiculous!
Why would a notorious
thief only steal twenty coins?!
What is it?
Be quiet!
Professor.
All right, begin now.
It's... it's... it's!
What is it?!
Get out of the way!
Hello, Professor.
He's here!
Bring it down! Bring it down!
My coin bank!
Thief!
Papa!
Michael, come here!
What was that?
Help me!
Professor, there's something
strange attached to us!
Never mind!
Just leave him like that!
Papa!
Michael! Help me!
Hurry up! Holmes is coming!
Papa!
Oh, my son!
Oh, stop it!
Don't cut that rope!
Got it!
Ah, I'm scared!
Holmes! What the?!
You can't win!
You! You!
Michael!
Papa, let's jump!
Go!
Good bye Holmes.
Take the helm!
The helm!
Scary!
Michael!
Papa!
Michael, you did a good job.
Of course he did. He's my son.
Michael is my treasure!
Treasure?
My treasure!
My coin bank!
He's hopeless.
Don't touch my gold coins!
Shut up!
How can you dirty
up the river like this?!
There is sludge everywhere!
It's mine!
The important thing is
that you do it on your own.
And never be impatient.
Do it on my own
and never be impatient.
Although, I think the fishing
pole idea was ingenious.
All right.
Be well.
Thank you very much!
Goodbye!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Professor Moriarty has discovered
the route used to transport cash...
by horse and carriage.
He's set up traps all over the road.
Can Holmes stop him in time?
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Professor's Big
Failure in the Storm!!