FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Blundered Operation
at Loch Ness!
Beautiful tone!
Your violin attracts even the fog.
It's begun to roll in.
Fog? Tonight's a quiet and
peaceful London evening.
Even with the fog
laying over the city.
Nothing is happening in London.
What is wrong with this city?
Well, do you mean the investigation
came to a dead end?
Anyhow, it's not even a real painting.
It's just a replica.
Moriarty would never deal with
this kind of cheap stuff.
You mean the Professor
would never steal a replica?
Then at least we can eliminate
one of our suspects.
Yes.
As you said,
this is really a boring case...
so why don't you solve it for once?!
Y... yes sir!
Inspector!
What is it?
A short while ago,
someone came here to see you.
He said three French
students are missing.
Not just a cheap robbery case,
but missing students as well?
Humph! I'm busy now.
Send him to somebody
who is suitable for such a case.
Yes.
The fog has gotten much heavier.
I guess you made London
into a peaceful city.
As long as
Sherlock Holmes is here...
no criminal can commit
any crime in this big city.
Even...
Even Professor Moriarty?
That's right.
I don't think so, Watson.
Why?
The Professor is being quiet now,
because he is thinking about...
another nasty plan.
See! We've got a visitor.
When did you take this picture?
We took the picture in Paris
before we went on vacation.
Three students of the Paris Art School
vanished while travelling in London.
Do they have any acquaintances
in London, or in England?
No, and they couldn't have
been able to go far.
They haven't much money.
Did you receive anything
like a threatening letter?
No. I didn't hear from
them for two weeks.
What?
Why didn't you start
looking for them earlier?
Because, I have a cousin in Redding,
so I was travelling by myself for a while.
I see. So, when you went back
to your hotel three days ago...
all your friends were gone?
Yes. Even their luggage
was unopened.
I understand clearly.
Let's investigate!
Shh! Be quiet!
Go back to work!
How is everything?
Is the painting that
I ordered coming along?
How long are you planning
to have us do this?
I guess it will be finished soon.
Well, this is beautiful.
The touch of the paint brush,
the colour, and the way it's layered...
even the way the light reflects...
it's exactly like the
painting of Volgetti.
You can sell this for a
very expensive price.
You don't have to say that!
Ouch!
I'm very satisfied with
all of your talent.
This would definitely add
some class to my collection.
You are not thinking about...
That's not for you to worry about.
Let's go!
After you finish that,
start working on the next project.
Wait a minute!
That's not what you promised.
You said this was the only one we had
to work on and that would be the end.
Promise?
Do you want to go home quickly?
Then don't complain
and do your work!
Damn!
I wish someone would find our message.
Then they might find this place
and come rescue us.
It has been a long time since
I last visited the National Gallery.
Hey Watson, we are not here
to appreciate the art.
Watson, let's go!
So those three students came here.
Somebody remembered them
carefully sketching famous paintings.
Well, the next place we have to go to
is the Piccadilly auction centre.
Yes.
Thank you.
Oh?
What?
Inspector!
Inspector Lestrade!
Holmes!?
Hello, Inspector! Is there anything
interesting you found at Sotheby's?
Or, are you investigating something?
W... well, it's just a boring case.
People call me the finest
Inspector of Scotland Yard...
but now I'm being forced
to look for a replica painting.
By the way, Holmes,
why are you here?
I'm looking for some lost children.
Lost children?
But, if you're having some trouble,
I'll be happy to assist you any time.
Any time!
Brother!
Stupid! We are gentlemen now.
Gentlemen have to
behave like gentlemen.
I told you to call me Colonel Moron.
And, what is it anyway?
Colonel Moron,
I saw Mr. Holmes over there.
What would you like me to do?
H... Holmes! Damn it! Hide!
Well, aren't we supposed
to be gentlemen?
Smiley, what do I look like?
A veteran...
I know that!
We are gentlemen.
Holmes will never
discover who we are.
Yes! We are gentlemen.
Oh, hey! You must be
Mr. Sherlock Holmes!
And you are Doctor Watson. I'm always
reading your case report books.
Well, excuse us. See you later.
Who are they?
Excuse me!
The clues are coming together.
Let's follow them.
Oh!
525! 525!
550!
The customer on my
left side said 550!
575!
600!
625!
Yes, 625!
650!
Yes, 650!
The lady on my left said 650!
670!
Oh!
Yes, a bid of 670!
700!
A bid of 700! 700! Will anybody
bid more than that? 700!
720!
Wow, 720!
725!
750!
There is a bid of 750!
Is there anybody who
wants to offer more?
750! 750!
800!
The lady on my left side said 800!
Do I hear any more offers?
Oh, no!
All right. It has been sold for 800.
Congratulations dear Lady!
Oh, thank you.
I'm so glad. Thank you.
That's great!
You knocked that vase down for 800.
800? Oh, no!
As usual, this place is
really bustling with energy.
That means there are plenty
of rich people around here.
No wonder crime
will never disappear.
What is next?
Well, it will be the artwork of Volgetti.
It says many of the paintings
and sculptures were found...
in an old Scottish castle.
Oh, I think I can expect to see
something nice.
Ahem! The next painting up for bid
now is a very rare and valuable one.
It was made during a bleak period
in art history. It survived through...
the Medieval wars, before it
finally arrived, here, in England.
Just take a look at this!
Oh my!
Wonderful! Fantastic!
I've heard about this, but this is
the first time I've ever seen it.
I can't believe that this kind of
painting is being auctioned.
What do you think?
Such a marvellous piece of art,
it could be considered priceless! Yes!
Now, the bidding for this wonderful
painting will start at 500!
Please bid!
550!
A bid of 550! Is there anybody
who wishes to bid more?
600!
650!
700!
750!
We have a bid of 750!
Are there any more bids?
800!
820!
850!
900!
900! The bid for this painting
is now 900!
Watson, I still think they're strange.
Who?
The two gentlemen who keep bidding.
950! Anybody else?
This is a valuable painting!
The value of this can't be
compared to anything else.
Please bid more!
M... Moriarty!
Shh! Be quiet!
They're here!
And that painting is!
Don't you think it's strange?
A bid of 1550!
1600!
1650!
1660!
1665!
I'll go up to 1700!
Uhm! A bid of 1700!
Rats! He's gone too far!
Well, does anybody wish
to bid more?
Anybody else?
Do I hear any more bids?
The value of this painting
is much higher!
A... anybody else?
A bid from anybody is fine!
Even if it's just a little higher...
Maybe they should take
the painting with them.
1710!
Yes! It has been sold for
1710 pounds!
Congratulations!
I knew I wanted to buy that painting
from the moment I saw it.
Excuse me.
What?
Unfortunately, it's true.
That painting I just bought is a fake?
My 1710 pounds is...
Oops.
Well, a landscape of Scotland
inside of an Italian painting.
Did you find out something?
Uh.
A robbery of replicas...
Kidnapped art students...
Scotland...
I got it!
What?
Is my money coming back?
Inspector!
There is a telegraph for you!
What? Come to Kings Cross Station
as soon as possible. Holmes.
I'm going out now!
Yes sir!
Telegraph for you.
That's too bad.
I made Mr. Watson's favourite
curry dinner tonight.
And Mr. Holmes can't make it either...
Inspector! This way!
Where is he? Where is Moriarty?
In Scotland.
Scotland?
Well, I'll explain it to you
on the train.
So, Moriarty stole the replica
and used it to make fake paintings?
Yes, he kidnapped three art students
who were visiting from France.
He must have imprisoned them
and forced them to forge paintings.
Hmm.
So far, your explanation is logical, but...
What a beautiful brightness!
What a lovely tone!
This is a crime that can only be done
by one who understands art, as I do!
My active energy has no limits!
People often get jealous
and try to destroy my plans.
But I will never rest!
By the way,
are they still painting?
Yes. They are very submissive.
All right. I will make
them paint Rembrandt.
I will express my dream to the world,
in light and darkness.
Oh, where is the Inspector?
He'll catch up with us soon
along with the local police.
I'm sure he'll bring too
many officers again.
Here they come!
All right!
Here we go!
Stand by!
Now!
Here!
Take this!
No! They're attacking us!
Damn! We've been too nice to them,
so they got puffed up!
There!
Here!
Let's get out of here!
Wait!
Professor!
What?
What a mess!
They escaped.
You dummies!
Wash your face and
go after them right now!
It doesn't work!
None of the keys match!
It's rusted.
Let's ram into the door together!
All right!
There!
This way!
Watson, look at that!
That's very high!
Over there!
I see. Why don't you guys
chase them this way.
I will take the faster
way to reach them.
There they are! Over there!
Everybody! Charge and break in!
It's Lestrade!
Smiley why don't you keep climbing?
I'll go back and tell the Professor!
Professor, there's so many police here!
What? Rats!
We have no choice but to load the
gold coins onto the Pteranodon!
Follow me!
Yes sir!
Here!
Oops.
Oops!
Let's go!
You are really slow!
You know that!
But...
We're too late.
Let's hurry and go upstairs.
Yes.
This is a dead end.
Darn it!
Holmes!
Watson!
This door!
All right!
Let's go up!
Hurry! Hurry up!
You guys seem like you're
carrying very heavy luggage.
Oh, it's Holmes!
Hey! Don't leave me here!
I found them!
Don't let them get away!
Calm down! We have so
many other escape routes!
Here we go!
There!
Ouch!
Look, it's him over there!
I'll get you!
Ouch!
Be patient!
Just a little more!
Ah! Ouch! Ouch!
It hurts! Help!
Do you want more?
Over there!
Wait! You're not getting away!
Just hang on for a little more.
Over the bridge!
Chase them!
This is strange, Holmes.
They aren't here.
Where did they go?
Holmes, I'll give you credit
because you chased me this far.
But can you actually catch me?
They tricked us!
Keep chasing them!
Goodbye!
Wait for me!
Wait!
Smiley!
Brother!
Wait!
Smiley!
Don't leave me alone!
I won't leave you alone!
Smiley, jump!
There they are!
We can still make it!
Everybody, jump! Jump!
Brother!
Good! Never let your hands go!
Pull them close!
Smiley, hang on!
Brother!
What are you doing?
No, my gold coins!
Even my replicas!
Stupid! What are you doing?
Just hold on tight!
No way!
We did it! We did it!
Heave ho! Heave ho! Heave ho!
The Inspector's
"never give up" attitude...
and enthusiasm for his work
is so impressive, it exhausts me.
I agree.
I just love a peaceful London,
just like you do, Mr. Holmes.
Is anything underneath?
"Ness-ing" is there!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
During a strong wind that
was blowing one night...
the famous Rosetta Stone was stolen
from the Museum of Great Britain.
How could such a heavy stone
been carried out?
When Holmes was on the case...
he visited a Japanese student
named Kinnosuke Natsume.
If you ever find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Soseki Kite Battle
Over London!