FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Soseki Kite Battle Over London!
Is this the famous Rosetta Stone?
Yes it is, Madam.
Oh!
This description is written
in ancient Egyptian.
This description is
written in Greek.
The contents of both
descriptions are the same.
The French scholar, Champollion,
was the one who deciphered...
the ancient Egyptian language.
This stone is a treasure of England.
Now we can read the Mummy's language.
May I say something?
The people who discovered this
stone in Rosetta, Egypt...
were soldiers in the army of
Napoleon The First.
The person who found
the Rosetta Stone was also French.
And the person who deciphered the
ancient Egyptian language was French!
In spite of this, why is
this stone in England?
I don't know why?
This stone should
belong to us in France!
May I say something?
The land of Rosetta is in Egypt.
So Egypt has the right
to keep the Rosetta Stone!
One third of the language they
wrote on the stone is in Greek.
I, as a Greek, insist on having
one third ownership of the stone!
May I say something?
Huh?
Who are you?
Where are you from?
Don't say you're Egyptian!
Ahem!
Who are you? Get lost!
What are you doing here?
I am who I am!
Shut up!
I can't sleep!
I heard the mummy talk.
I feel something bad might happen.
I'm hoping that a group of
distinguished professors, like you...
could give this a thorough
scientific analysis.
- I wonder if he's speaking the truth or not.
- It must be some mistake.
No, it's true.
This room has been kept
closed since the incident.
What is it?
What happened?
I don't know.
It's over there!
Oh, wait! Please wait!
What is this?
Hey! What's going on?
Here!!
There!!
Here we go!
On your right!
Your right!
No!
Oh, please don't go!
This must be a dream.
A dream?
How could a stone
fly off into the sky?
It's against the great laws
of Sir Isaac Newton!
I must be dreaming now.
I see! This is just a dream.
Yes! This is a dream.
So long Mr. Rosetta Stone!
Good bye! My honey, Rosettina!
Good bye! Good bye!
Why are you guys sticking
your noses in my dream?
Wait a minute!
Is this really a dream?
Ouch! This is not a dream.
Oh, my god!
What am I supposed to do?
We did a great job.
Hurry up and get to Dover!
I'm sure the mummy's ghost did it.
The mummy got angry because
people discovered the secret...
of their language after
the Rosetta Stone was found.
He was unhappy because they woke
him up from his eternal sleep.
Well Chief,
don't rush to conclusions.
Somebody who really wanted the
Rosetta Stone must have done this.
Anyhow, the Rosetta Stone
is a treasure of England.
There are always people who
are trying to steal treasures.
If nobody was interested in stealing
it, then it's not even a treasure.
However, about the
mummy doing this...
Then, who stole the stone?
I don't know.
French, Egyptian, Greek...
anybody who has some connection
to the stone, wants to have it.
That stone is a treasure that
has brought ancient Egypt...
into the modern world.
But they stole it from the sky.
It's a cunning strategy.
Do you think they used a blimp?
No, yesterday's wind velocity
was more than 60 meters.
Then they used an air plane?
But I don't think they
could have used an air plane.
Nobody seems to have heard
the sound of an air plane.
By the way, Watson, why don't we
go out and eat French food tonight...
since we haven't done
that for a long time?
What? French food?
Yes, Mrs. Hudson,
would you like to join us?
Oh, yes.
- Allons enfants de la patrie...
- Arise children of the fatherland...
- Lejour de gloire est arrivé!
- The day of glory has arrived!
- Contre nous, de la tyrannie...
- Against us tyranny's...
- I'étendard sanglant est levé.
- Bloody standard is raised.
- Entendez vous dans les campagnes...
- Listen to the sound in the fields...
Mr. Napoleon...
you look like you're
having a fun time.
I can't stop laughing after I heard
that the Rosetta Stone disappeared...
from the British Museum.
Well, Napoleon found that stone and
Champollion deciphered the letters...
sculpted on the stone first.
Therefore, France should
keep that stone.
Does that mean someone
French stole that stone?
What? Not at all!
The French people are
never thieves!
I don't need change!
I thought so!
Holmes, why did he rush
to leave so quickly?
That man must have hired
somebody to steal the stone.
But if he didn't use a blimp or an
air plane, he must be very smart.
I already have some idea
how they did it.
Well, let's enjoy our dinner.
Yes.
Here we go.
Japanese?
Yes, his name is
Kinnosuke Natsume.
He's a young professor who came here
to study the culture of England...
from the far eastern
country of Japan.
So, how is he related
to this incident?
There are big typhoons that strike
Japan over and over...
from summer to autumn.
I see.
European people try to control nature,
but Japanese people know how to use it...
and adapt to it.
K. Natsume...
I'm very interested about
the incident of the Rosetta Stone.
Really?
Has something happened?
Yes, about one month ago...
When I was returning home...
Wait!
Who are you?
There!!
Here!!
Here we go!
I thought the other students were
making joke, at first.
But, the attitude of those two
people was very suspicious.
They stole an illustration book that
I brought from Japan...
that was translated into English.
And the book had a story
about a thief...
who used the big wind
to steal things.
Used the big wind?
Yes, there's a big castle
in Nagoya, Japan.
A monster fish with the head of
a tiger and the body of a fish...
called Shachihoko is on the top of
the castle, to protect it from fire.
The scales of the monster fish
are made of gold.
A hundred years ago,
on the night of a storm...
there was a thief who stole
the scales of the fish.
I understand!
What do you understand, Holmes?
You are a smart detective,
Mr. Holmes.
This is the picture book.
While I was wondering about
the book they had stolen...
the Rosetta Stone
incident happened.
Well, thank you very much
Mr. Kinnosuke.
I think there's a person
who ordered those men...
to steal your picture book.
He got the idea from the book
and committed the crime.
But, you don't have to
worry any more.
We will take care of this incident.
Well then, goodbye.
Goodbye!
Bye!
If they stole the Rosetta Stone,
where did they hide it?
I have some idea where.
There is no Rosetta Stone?!
I wanted to see it.
This is just like a party
with no cake.
What is Scotland Yard doing?
The Rosetta Stone might be hidden
somewhere between London and Dover.
So, Mr. Holmes, do you already
know the place where they hid it?
I guess so.
Then let's go over there and
take it back with us!
No, I'm already tired today. I'll make
sure I bring the stone back tomorrow.
B... but...
Hey, Holmes!
Don't worry. I'll never
let the stone get to Dover.
Curse you Holmes!
I'll never let you do that!
If you are trying to stop
me tomorrow...
I, Professor Moriarty, will
take action tonight!
Your tea will get cold.
By the way, Holmes, do you really
know where they hid the Rosetta Stone?
No, to tell the truth,
I don't have any idea.
What did you say?
The only person who knows
is Moriarty.
What is going on? Really?
Tonight, I hope a strong wind
will blow again.
What's mine is mine
and what's yours is also mine
Long live France!
We have a problem.
Holmes found out about this!
What? Is that true? He might have
found out at the restaurant!
Don't worry about anything.
He is bragging that he will
find it tomorrow...
but I'm sure he doesn't know
the Rosetta Stone is here.
Oh, why didn't you tell me that first?
Then let's cross the ocean,
and move this to France, tonight.
Oh, don't play with it!
Oh, excuse me! Wait! Ouch!
Wait!
Watch out!
Here we go! Here we go!
Todd! Smiley!
Yes sir!
Prepare the kite!
Oh, yes yes!
Here we go!
Great! Run fast as soon as
the wind starts to blow!
Yes! Here we go!
Heave ho! Heave ho!
Isn't it amazing that you can cross
over the Straits of Dover so quickly.
Oh, I can already see the ship.
Well, Mr. Rich descendent of Napoleon!
Can you pay me the amount
you promised me now?
Well, congratulations for the
good job. Let's shake hands!
No! No! I don't want to shake hands!
Why don't you give me 10,000 pounds?
Non! Non! I don't want
to pay even 1 pound...
until we arrive safely in France.
Stingy!
I'm not stingy. We French make a
distinction between right and wrong.
Make the rope longer!
Oh, what is that?
Moriarty, good evening
from the ocean!
Rats!
How could this happen?
Todd, Smiley!
Use battle plan #302!
Start the battle!
Roger! Battle plan #302...
start!
Kinnosuke, how are we doing?
We're doing all right!
Leave this up to me!
In Japan, we have a game called
"kite battle".
We cut our opponent's rope.
Now go!
All right!
Oh, Professor!
Operation number 105!
All right!
What?
Well, I'll make it this time!
No!
The engine is...
not working.
Here we go!
All right!
Wait!
L... let me go!
Protect your own life by yourself!
Oh!
Help me!
Protect your own life by yourself!
Please, don't say such mean things!
Kinnosuke! Are you all right?
I'm all right!
Vanished!
Holmes might have given up.
Oh! It's coming over here!
Holmes!
It will crush us!
You fool!
Todd! Smiley!
Bring down the kite quickly!
Yes sir!
I thought something was fishy
so I came here to check.
Then I found you guys here!
Damn it!
Don't get so close!
The kite will fall!
Well then...
Charge!
Here we go!
Now, bring it down!
Yes!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
Heave-ho!
Oh, this is it!
I'm going to swim.
Spinning! Spinning! Spinning!
You can't do that!
We have a ship down there.
Wait!
We did it!
We won!
It's good to have things
back in their proper place.
That's right.
The Rosetta Stone is a symbol of
the British Museum.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
A blueprint of the airship,
White Silver, was stolen.
There are only a few days until
the maiden voyage.
Who did it and what
are their intentions?
The shining silver airship, White Silver,
took off with Holmes in it...
and so begins the
mystery in the sky.
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Chase the airship, White Silver!