FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Listen! The Tribute to Moriarty
It's time to test the machine.
Todd, Smiley, are you ready?
Yes, sir!
Go!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
That's good!
Keep it up!
Why do we have to do this?!
Why?
So we can test the machine, right?
All right! Stop!
Now, bring it back down.
The test was successful!
Ah, lovely.
The tolling of Big Ben
is always music to my ears...
especially when it's
chiming in a huge treasure.
That's very odd.
It's the correct time, though.
Is there a problem?
Well, it may just be me,
but did you hear Big Ben chime?
No...
Oh!
It's high time for the
bell to have chimed.
Odd indeed.
Yes, isn't it?
My watch is correct, why?
What's going on?
Big Ben's gone quiet.
That's strange.
Here comes Inspector Lestrade.
I wonder if there's any trouble.
So it appears.
Big Ben's bell has...
disappeared!
It was stolen sometime last night!
Stolen?! By whom?! And how?!
That's why I called you in, to answer
those very questions, Inspector!
I know that!
Start searching for clues!
Overlook nothing,
not even a single hair!
What's happened?
It would seem that Big Ben's
bell has been stolen.
Are you serious?!
That's not possible, is it?!
Whoever did this
must be unconscionable.
What are those
milk bottles doing there?
They probably fell off
of a milk delivery truck.
Have you found any other clues?
Not a one.
Inspector General!
Inspector Lestrade,
have you found any clues?
I'm afraid to say there are none so far...
What?!
Are you aware of what this means?
What?
Big Ben is not only London's...
but it is the very symbol
of the British Empire!
If this incident gets out
to the public...
not only will you get fired,
but so will I!
Fired?!
So we must quietly apprehend the thief
and return the bell immediately!
Holmes!
Inspector General, your staff
explained the situation to me.
We're in deep trouble.
I figured that I
would need your help.
This is far beyond
my area of expertise.
What are those milk
bottles doing there?
They probably fell off
of a milk delivery truck.
What a waste.
In any event, let's have a look
at the scene of the crime.
It appears to be the work of
someone who owns an air plane.
You mean someone
like Professor Moriarty?
Lestrade and his men are so confused,
they're completely helpless.
Naturally.
What about Holmes?
He's also completely puzzled,
and could give up any time.
Right, right...
Excellent! Excellent!
An overwhelming victory!
It's mine!
No mine! I'm starving!
Professor!
How cruel!
Pull yourselves together!
It's only for a little while longer.
But...
The vast reward for the return
of Big Ben's bell will go to us!
Once that happens,
we can feast ourselves sick!
Really, Professor?!
Now, shall we go?
So, you're saying an air plane
wasn't involved?
Big Ben's bell weighs
thirteen and a half tons.
Far too heavy...
This is machine oil...
You figured something out?
I've got a pretty good idea.
Let us through!
Impossible! We have our orders!
Let us talk to whoever's in charge!
You can talk at the
press conference later!
Things are getting interesting.
Even Holmes is helpless this time.
This is really not good.
If the press releases
this news to the public...
our country will be the
laughingstock of the entire world.
I have an idea.
Watson, please bring me
that item I asked for.
Yes Holmes.
Holmes...
What's going on, gentlemen?
Is it true that Big Ben's bell
has been stolen?
Who's spreading such
unfounded rumours?
Then how do you explain
the bell not ringing this morning?
That's because someone
sabotaged the bell.
Sabotaged?
That's right.
The bell is under repair now,
but should be back in service soon.
Then who's the saboteur?
We only know the saboteur is someone
possessing great energy and wisdom.
Would that be Professor Moriarty?
You must be joking.
He doesn't have the brains
to commit this type of crime.
Don't overestimate that man.
This is the work of a genius,
not some petty thief.
Holmes, why you!
Professor, please calm down!
Let me go!
I've had my fill of this humiliating!
Think about that vast reward!
Gentlemen, repairs of the bell
have just been completed.
It is now five minutes to ten o'clock.
As proof, you will soon
hear the tolling of Big Ben.
President of the Ames corporation,
the bell of Big Ben... as you ordered.
Let me see.
Oh!
Indeed...
Now, if you would please,
give us the fee you promised.
Impossible!
I'll be taking this back, then.
Now see here!
You promised me those!
Don't speak of promises when
you break them, Professor Moriarty!
You promised me Big Ben's bell,
not this fake!
This is not a fake,
it's the real bell from Big Ben!
Then what's that
we're hearing right now?!
There must be some mistake!
Wait, President Ames!
It looks like I'll just have to prove
that this is the genuine article!
All right.
If you can really prove it, then the
reward I promised will be yours.
Curses!
I'll prove it, or my name
isn't Moriarty the genius!
I wonder if the Professor
will take the bait.
His pride won't keep him quiet.
He most certainly will.
First and second squads
are in position, sir.
Good.
Squad 6 and the reserves
are in position, sir!
Very good.
Not even a mouse could
escape my notice, now.
Moriarty, you're challenging me to
expose the trick of Big Ben's bell?
I'll take that dare!
Holmes, do you think it's wise to
leave Big Ben in Lestrade's hands?
It's more important for us to discover
the whereabouts of Big Ben's bell.
That's the key to solving this case.
But, this milk bottle
is our only clue.
I don't see anything
like that in the book.
Are you sure?
I'm absolutely certain.
Any milk that comes through
here would be in our records.
So, you're saying that no store
has ever purchased through...
you for just one day?
That's correct.
Then where did this
milk bottle come from?
Are there any other
warehouses for milk?
No, this is the only one.
Permit me...
This is unblended.
What do you mean?
In order to maintain our milk's
taste and consistency...
we always blend ours.
This must be a farm-direct purchase.
Which means, this milk
came directly from a farm.
Can you tell us which one?
Let's see...
from the flavour and aroma, I'd say this
comes from a farm in the Northwest.
Holmes, it's about
time you explained...
how the milk bottle
relates to the theft of the bell.
A milk delivery truck
is the only vehicle...
that could move unnoticed during
the hours when streets are empty.
That's what they used
to transport the bell.
But I'm not yet certain
how they did it.
I'll get them no matter
where they come from!
There you are, Moriarty!
You fiend!
Follow that balloon!
Go!
Don't lose them!
That way! Go!
Go! Go! Go!
Professor Moriarty!
Give it up, or I'll shoot you down!
I am a genius, not some petty thief!
Catch me if you can!
I have had enough of you!
Arrest that man!
Moriarty, you're under arrest!
I finally got you!
It came off!
It's a dummy!
What!?
But, I definitely heard his voice...
Catch me if you can!
Curses!
I knew it!
Holmes must have come up with
this pathetic attempt at deception.
I'd love to see his face
when he hears this.
That guy not only bought cases
of milk, but a truck, too.
A truck as well.
Do you know who the man was?
From the household of the
president of the Ames Corporation...
The Ames Corporation!?
Thank you!
Everything seems normal here.
Humph, let's double
check for safety's sake.
Is everything OK?!
What a troublemaker.
Then why did he play
such a cheap trick on us?
Attacking and taking, I'm Moriarty
Cracking safe and busting lock
I'll strip you down to the very bone
The lord of crime, oh yes, that's me
Super cool and smart, I'm Moriarty
I'll continue on my criminal way...
They did it to us.
Inspector Lestrade has failed.
Let's hurry, for his sake.
Let me go!
Not yet!
I cannot bear to live
with this humiliation!
There's still hope!
Don't give up, Inspector!
Ames is a huge corporation,
conducting extensive trade with India.
Why would the president of such a
big company want Big Ben's bell?
This is no different than
being thieves ourselves.
Look at that.
That's Moriarty's Pteranodon.
This is it!
He must have thought
this through carefully.
That's a reinforced
manual steering lift.
Using this machine,
Moriarty took the bell...
Just like that!
I see.
Please inform Inspector Lestrade.
I'll be watching here.
All right.
What are they planning
to do with the bell?
So, this is the secret of the fake bell.
Do you accept now that the
one I brought is the real one?
Of course!
I never doubted you
in the first place...
but I needed absolute confirmation for
the man who actually paid this reward.
Sir, the bearer for
Prince Hassan has arrived.
Very well.
Oh, wonderful!
This will fit perfectly in
Prince Hassan's new palace!
I'm honoured you like it.
So about that reward you promised...
Yes. Yes. Yes.
Yes, that's right.
It is from the Prince Hassan.
Please accept this, Professor.
Sir...
Inspector Lestrade and his
police force have arrived.
Ah yes, very good...
What's that?!
I know nothing about this!
I had nothing to do with it!
Stop right there!
Professor Moriarty!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
Catch me if you can!
Keep away!
Drat!
Stop!
I told you to stop!
No, now wait!
You want to catch me?!
Then fly!
At last, things feel right again.
Indeed.
The sound of Big Ben tolling is
the pride of the British Empire.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Imagine someone who is bold enough to
steal a jewellery shop's diamond...
in broad daylight.
In fact, Professor Moriarty has done
exactly that... or so he thought.
There was an unexpected hitch
to his seemingly perfect crime.
If you ever find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Chaos!
The Doll Swap Case