FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Missing Freight Car!?
The Professor's Big Magic Trick
Here.
Heave-ho!
What are you doing?!
Everybody!
Put that gold back in the boxes quickly!
Beautiful!
I'll become an instant millionaire,
if I steal all of them.
I'll be able to eat a trainload of candies
and ice cream, as much as I want.
I have to make those two dolts work
in order to make my plan successful.
Wake up!
- Yes!
All passengers taking
the train to London...
the train is arriving.
The freight car is sandwiched
between two passenger trains.
I'm sure they must be carrying
gold, silver or some treasure.
We will never know what might happen
until we arrive in London.
Please protect the gold bullion,
even at the risk of your own life.
Yes, we will.
It's time for me to shock people all
over London and all over the world.
I will complete the perfect crime.
Is anything wrong?
Well, I guess I'm tired.
I just saw something strange.
The people I hate
are on this train.
No, I'm scared.
No!
Chicken!
Idiot! Get down! Get down!
Tunnel!
Pull me up!
Pull!
Hurry!
Huh?
We'll be arriving soon.
We just passed Newton station,
didn't we?
We're close to the
Kenyon junction point.
I think we'll be in time
for a late night dinner.
You mean, Mrs. Hudson will be
making a late night dinner for us?!
I sent her a telegraph at the station.
Hmm, that's not a bad idea.
What?
We must have a bad train engineer.
He suddenly hit the
brake going downhill.
A warm meat pie and milk tea!
That doesn't sound bad.
I like it.
It's not there!
The freight car is gone!
It can't be!
I don't believe this!
Is this the train that departed
from Liverpool at 5:25 PM...
and arrived at London
at 10:37 PM?
This is it!
But...
What's going on?
Don't ask me! I have no idea!
You! This train carried one
freight car. Is that right?
Yes, to transport gold bullion
it's connected as the fourth car.
What?
The freight car is gone!
We should call the police!
The freight car is more important
than calling the police!
Where is the freight car?!
You're asking the wrong person!
Excuse me,
is there a problem?
The freight car is missing!
It vanished like a ghost,
with a huge amount of gold bullion!
Gold bullion?
It's true.
I'm sure I saw one freight car before.
A missing freight car.
Excuse me, but you might be?
Yes, I'm Holmes.
Oh, I thought so!
You're the famous
private detective, Holmes!
Please help me!
Please find the freight car!
I think that it must be fate that
I happened to be on this train.
I'll investigate.
A rope mark.
Everybody!
All passengers!
Please wait for a while.
I would like to ask
everybody some questions.
Well, the famous detective
is already here.
No, I just happened
to be on this train, too.
Oh, then can I ask some questions?
The freight car was connected between
the front and rear passenger cars.
And it disappeared.
There were passenger cars
in front and back.
Where has it gone?
The train was running on the rail.
If one successfully detached the cars,
there are still passenger cars...
on both front and backside.
There is nowhere for
the freight car to go.
Mr. Holmes!
Did you find out anything?
I learned that when we passed
Newton station and Kenyon junction...
the freight car was still there.
And they said the freight car
was gone at Burton Moss station.
That means the freight car disappeared
between the junction & Burton Moss.
But how?
Who did it?
There's only one person who could
think up this type of bold crime...
and actually commit it.
Professor Moriarty!
Ah what?!
Gently...
Open the box.
Gold!
Open the other boxes!
Yes sir.
Here we go.
Everything is gold!
It's a pile of gold!
Yes, it's gold!
Gold! Gold!
It's a pile of gold!
I finally became a millionaire!
Gold! Gold!
Professor! We did it!
We're finally victorious after having
been patient in this poor life!
Yes! And this victory is because of
my artistic talent for crime.
I'm sure Holmes won't
figure out this trick...
and he'll run away from the case.
And do you think you can figure
out where the freight car is?
I'm planning to check between the
two stations tomorrow morning.
Whoops!
Oh, that's an interesting idea.
Yes, I recycled my old gloves.
They're very unique kitchen gloves.
Why are you playing with them?
Oh, sorry. This is really unique.
Do you think so?
Thank you.
Why don't you eat it
while it's still warm?
Well, we will be very busy tomorrow.
It's just like I thought. The rail road
tracks split off in several directions.
It's true. There are so many.
I see. Those are for the coal mines
and iron factories around here.
I think the freight car was separated
and sent on one of the sidetracks.
That's right.
But how could they separate the
one car from the rest of the train?
Hey!
I thought so.
It's still working.
But Holmes, if you change tracks, all
the cars would go onto the sidetrack.
Do you remember the rope marks
I found between the passenger cars?
First, they tied with rope between
the two passenger cars...
in front and behind the freight car.
Oh, just like Mrs. Hudson's
kitchen gloves.
That's right. It means that...
Liverpool station had tight security,
so they did it after the train departed.
Somebody tied the front and
back passenger cars with rope.
After the train passed Kenyon Junction
and came on the top of the hill...
they disconnected the front
and backside of the freight car.
After Kenyon Junction,
it was all downhill.
While the train passed,
they separated the freight car.
And the person who was waiting there
switched tracks and the freight car...
went onto the sidetrack.
The rear passenger cars were pulled
by the rope and accelerated.
When the engineer applied the brake,
the cars automatically joined together.
I remember feeling a jolt
around that area.
When you said the driver was
not very skilful using the brake.
We should have checked
when that happened.
Now all we just have to do
is follow the sidetrack...
to find the missing freight car.
Somebody must be
using a blast furnace.
Heave ho! Heave ho!
Don't be so slow!
We have to get the gold out
before people find us here!
What?!
What are you doing?!
Do it quickly!
I'm too hungry to move!
I feel dizzy!
What?!
Steak! Or at least some sausage!
All right!
I'll go and get something.
But you should continue working.
I won't give you any gold
unless you finish on time.
Nuts!
Ah, I only have this much.
If I exchanged the gold into money,
I'd be a millionaire. How shameful!
And now, I don't even have any gas.
I don't like this!
I didn't expect that we could use
Mrs. Hudson's dinner here.
Although, I feel it will be a waste.
Yes.
If we don't finish before the
Professor comes back...
he won't let us eat anything.
Thank you for waiting!
Yes.
Who is it?
Mr. Moriarty asked
us to deliver this.
The Professor?
Yes, he did.
Here we go!
Oh, that's gorgeous!
There's also some wine here.
He's acting like a millionaire.
He's very generous.
By the way,
where's the Professor?
Uh, well...
The Professor had something to
take care of in London, suddenly.
I thought the Professor was
very cheap and annoying.
A man shouldn't be
judged by his looks.
The sleeping pills work best
when people are hungry.
All right.
This is perfect.
Rats! I could only buy a little.
I know they're going to complain.
My gold bullion!
Wait!
This is no good.
What are you waiting for?!
Get up!
Come on!
Go! Go!
Don't let them get away!
Here!
Hey, wake up!
I'm telling you to get up!
You!
Hey!
That's it!
Go! Go!
Holmes! Holmes!
Where are you?
Mrs. Hudson told me he
went in this direction.
Stop!
Lestrade of Scotland Yard
will take the gold bullion!
Go!
Arrest them!
Here!
You villains!
A little more!
Todd! Smiley!
We have to rescue the Professor!
Let's not do that!
We never know what he'll do
to us when he's very angry!
You!
Stop! Stop!
Chase them!
Do you want to do that now?
I guess so!
All right!
Here we go!
That line just goes around the old
station and comes back here.
Let's relax and wait here.
All right! Go!
Go! Go!
Don't let them escape!
Stop!
Where are they?
Where is Moriarty?
Where is the gold?
Well now.
Not again!
Bye!
I can't stand it any more!
Fool! You're in my way!
Get off!
It's too slow!
Slow!
Get off! Get off!
Yes, yes.
Then!
Wait!
Here!
Go!
Heave ho! Heave ho!
Stop it!
Go!
This is not the gold bullion.
It doesn't look like it.
It's not gold?
They replaced it.
What is this?!
Delicious popcorn!
Danger! Danger!
Everybody take cover!
Switching the freight cars
was a successful plan!
Whoops.
But nobody will be able to
finish eating this much popcorn.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Professor Moriarty,
who loves lobster...
stole the most expensive lobster in
the world form Brydon mansion.
This lobster is made of
jewels and coral.
It was put into a barrel and
shipped from the harbour.
What kind of taste does
this lobster have?
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Gourmet! Coral Lobsters.