FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Magic Castle!
Holmes, Dead or Alive?
The Holy Cross Sword...
...after thirty years,
it's open to the public.
The noble Wizard family...
they even sat at the same dinner table
with King Arthur in the old days.
They handed down this mysterious
treasured sword to their descendants.
Mr. Holmes, are you listening?
The Holy Cross Sword is
a symbol of aristocracy.
And it has a very important
secret sealed inside of it.
Oh...
There's a rumour about the secret.
It could lead to an enormous treasure.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Since such an important treasure will
be open to the public, tomorrow...
I don't think it's time
for you to relax.
Well, until tomorrow, they're
planning to have security guards...
and the sword will be
kept in a large safe.
What?
How do you know so much?
Well, a messenger from
the Wizard family came by earlier.
That's our invitation.
Oh, really?
I didn't know that.
You!
What is this?!
Hey, are you okay?
Oh, this really is a marvellous sword.
The jewels and ornaments
are so beautiful.
This workmanship...
It must have been crafted almost five
hundred years ago or even earlier.
But why have they sealed this
inside of a triangle crystal?
That's a mystery.
I see. It's very interesting.
Hello, Mr. Holmes!
Sir Wizard, It's been a long time.
Little Sir William, how are you doing?
This is my friend, Watson.
How do you do?
Welcome.
Willy, can you greet our guests, too?
Mr. Watson, it's nice to see you.
How come you have such sharp ears?
Does this mean there's
a case going on?
Oh, you didn't know about it?
Actually, a mysterious incident
recently occurred.
Mysterious incident?
The Holy Cross Sword
was kept in this safe.
However, yesterday, some thief
broke in and opened the safe.
As you can see,
he didn't steal the sword.
I see. Is there any other
jewellery inside the safe?
No, only the Holy Cross Sword.
The thief's target was the sword,
but the sword was not taken.
I've never heard of such
a ridiculous story.
Did they replace the sword
with a forgery?
I thought so at first...
but this is the real sword.
Well, I'm going to
investigate elsewhere.
I'll let you investigate here,
Mr. Holmes.
Nyah!
What is it, Holmes?
I see. It's magnesium.
Magnesium? What is that?
Don't you know?
The stuff that creates a flash
when you take a picture.
Why did they only take a picture
and leave the sword?
May I see it?
Oh, I can see some
small hieroglyphs.
Excuse me.
This is...
The first one is a snake.
The next symbol is three lumps
and two shiny eyes.
And a castle.
There are seven symbols all together.
If you figure out what they mean,
you will know the secret of the sword.
Then the legend of a treasure
hidden by our ancestors is true.
The Professor wanted to take
a picture of these symbols.
The legend was written in the ancient
code of the Wizard family.
What is wrong with this?!
There's nothing on the photograph.
That's shouldn't be!
What's going on?
We took out the sword and
projected the symbols on the wall.
Then we took a picture of it.
Yes.
You fools!
Because you burned magnesium,
the symbols didn't show up!
But we can't take a picture unless
we use a magnesium flash.
We just followed your instructions.
Yes. How could I make the mistake of
giving this mission to these two fools?!
Oh, then it wasn't our mistake.
Well, that's good.
Yes, that's great!
Shut up!
You two! Just remember what
kind of symbols they were!
Now! Hurry!
Well.
It was a snake!
And its tail was split in two.
First, the snake,
is of course... a river.
Then, the two tails are...
the joining point of two
of the river's branches.
So, the three lumps
are mountains?
Yes and the two shiny eyes
are either lakes or swamps.
Now let's put all of these
on the map.
It's Dayburg Castle.
It's the ancestral home
of the Wizard family.
Now we just have
to visit this area.
We're going to Dayburg Castle
immediately.
They saved us the time
of figuring this out.
Let's follow them and steal the treasure.
The clouds are very close.
It might rain soon.
What?
You found me?
Why are you here?
They've stopped.
You can't just come
along with us like this.
I left a letter for my grandfather.
So, don't worry.
But...
it's all right.
I'm already old enough.
Do you promise that you won't
do anything dangerous?
Yes.
Then, let's go.
Yeah! All right!
Don't do anything dangerous!
Oh, they started to move.
They're trying to get ahead.
It will soon be daybreak.
Dayburg Castle.
I see.
Three mountains and two lakes.
Hey! Get to the basement quickly.
Why the basement?
Fool!
It's an old custom to hide
treasure inside a basement!
Stone circle.
It's shaped like a necklace.
Let's hurry!
It's almost sunrise.
Professor, let's go home.
I'm sure some scary
ghost will come out.
Humph! Ridiculous! I won't share
any treasure with you two!
This is bad.
Professor, look at that!
Hurry! It's not here.
I thought so.
As usual.
The one piece of rock that
the sunrise points to.
This must be the entrance.
Wait! "Two people who have good
souls should help each other."
"Go backward one step
and then go forward."
It's impossible to move this rock
with just two people.
Wait!
Hurry up and open this!
Hold this rock!
We have no choice but to use force.
Ready?
Let's go!
What are these holes for?
We should be careful.
Oops.
Watson!
What was that?
What is that sound?
What is that voice?
Who knows?
It seems like there is a
tunnel over there.
Watch your step.
I feel like I'm at
the bottom of a well.
This is not good!
Let's go back!
Oh, no!
Now there's water!
Water from the lake is pouring in.
Hey, Holmes! Do something!
We will all drown if we stay here!
Just hang on until the
water reaches the ceiling.
This is it.
Goodbye my friend.
Watson!
My rival, Holmes.
It's strange meeting each other
in such an unusual place.
Oh, you look awful!
So this is the end of
the famous detective.
I humbly pray that your soul
rests in peace.
We're saved.
Professor Moriarty's
new weapon saved us.
It's dangerous!
This stone bridge looks very fragile.
It can handle my weight.
Secure the end of the rope.
All right!
Here!
Oh, no!
Watson!
Willy, the hole!
I finally found it!
Is the treasure inside of this?
Yes.
What is this?
It looks like an old bible.
I know that!
I see! The place where they hid the
treasure, must be written in this bible.
Professor.
Nothing's there!
It's just a bible!
Drat!
I know! Somebody
must've already stolen it!
Ouch!
Somebody's coming.
We have no choice but to leave.
Oh, no!
They got here first.
The treasure is gone.
No, there wasn't any
treasure to begin with.
See, only the mark left by the bible.
One bible.
Professor Moriarty got
angry and threw it.
Look at this!
Holmes.
Just watch.
Oh, this is!
What a beautiful bible!
This is the treasure that the
ancestors of the Wizard family...
left for their next generation,
700 years ago.
Oh, grandpa!
Grandpa! I...
I found your treasure!
Oh, is it true?
Curse you, Holmes!
I was waiting for you!
Moriarty, this is your last day!
Run!
Hurry!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
In the Thames River,
covered by heavy fog...
There is a monster that pulls cargo
ships down deep beneath the river.
Such rumours are
spreading around London.
One evening, a young man
disappears in the river.
A girl believes he's still alive,
and Holmes starts to investigate.
If you ever find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Monster of the Thames River