FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Blue Ruby
This is really bad traffic.
Was there an accident?
It's always like this
during this time of day.
What is that?!
What?! What?! What is that?!
What's going on?!
It's a monster from
the previous century!
No! That's an air plane!
There it goes!
Oops! I'm sorry!
Stupid!
None of these young
brats have any manners!
Hey, that's enough!
Let's get out of here!
Holmes, what do
you think they were doing?!
This is terrible!
Robbery! Robbery!
Somebody broke open the safe!
Please call the police!
I see. That's why.
I never cease to amaze
myself with my own genius.
What?!
It's gone! It's gone! It's gone!
That brat did it! Curses!
Scoundrel!
Don't even think you
can get away with this!
Miss, may I have two apples?
All right Polly.
You look very happy.
Did something
good happen today?
Sort of.
Here we go.
Winnie, I'm back.
Were you being good
staying here at home?
I'll show you something special.
See.
Great!
This is really beautiful.
Winnie, let's make
this jewel our treasure.
This case is elementary.
I don't understand what's going on.
The owner of the jewelry shop made
a big scene, screaming "robbery", but...
I'm sorry everybody.
I made a mistake.
Could you please leave?
Please just leave!
How could he cause such
a burden for everyone?
No.
It actually did happen.
Such things always happen.
Either the jewelry was stolen
and they were keeping it for someone...
or they already negotiated with
the thief and bought it back.
I see.
He doesn't want this
to turn into a big case.
The people who flew that air plane
were the ones who stole it.
Oh, what an unusually awful smell!
Uh, who is visiting us so late?
I understand.
I'll give this to Mr. Holmes.
Oh, thank you.
What a very pleasant smell!
Well, I was just trying to make
perfume out of ammonia.
I do feel sorry for Mr. Watson.
The jewelry shop is
requesting us to investigate?
Are you going?
I have nothing better
to do at the moment.
I will lose everything
if I can't find it!
I was asked to keep the jewel
by a member of the royal family.
It's the Blue Ruby,
supposedly the only one in the world.
Is the jewel more important
to you than arresting the criminal?
That's right!
Please get it back no matter what.
You can even buy
it back from the thief.
Are you saying we may have
to negotiate with the criminal?
Why do you think I'm
hiring a private detective?!
I don't care how you get it back.
I will pay you five hundred guineas.
Five hundred guineas?
That's a lot of money.
I will do my best anyway.
Hey, hey! Holmes!
Aren't you going to
check inside the shop?
There may be some evidence.
It's not worth doing.
The thief didn't touch anything
other than the blue ruby.
I want to look
for the air plane's hangar.
Here, please get in.
I'm sorry.
Oh! Sorry.
What an energetic lad.
Here.
My wallet, when did you get that?
That boy did it. He has great skill.
What?! It's gone.
It's him! Get him!
This is bad!
Don't let him go!
Wait!
Holmes, that's the boy!
Hello!
Did he do something?
Yes, the Professor finally
stole the jewel and he...
Idiot! Don't say those things!
Stole the jewel?
Hold on tight, Watson!
See! Now they know!
There he is, Professor Moriarty.
Little brats!
I will crush all of you together!
Let me go!
Drat!
- Damn it! Don't try and fool me!
- Just come and get me!
Power up! Give it more!
Yes, Sir!
Nice!
You're a girl?
I'll crush you!
I did it!
I won't let you go!
Idiot!
Bye bye!
Don't think you
can get away like that.
This is a nice room.
Polly, are you living here alone?
No, I live with Winnie.
Winnie... I see.
Who taught you to pickpocket?
My father was a
professional pickpocket.
You're skills are good as well.
So are yours.
Polly, where is the jewel that
you pickpocketed from Moriarty?
Sorry fellas, I couldn't tell you that,
seeing as we just met.
How feminine.
Oh, thank you.
Come over here, Winnie.
Here, please help yourself.
I would be happy to.
Very well.
Oops.
Just do like this.
Like this?
Oh, I see. Like this.
This way.
Say Polly, can I invite you to dinner
in return for this wonderful tea?
Sure, but I won't give
you the jewel.
Polly, you shouldn't
underestimate Moriarty.
He is not a man who gives up easily.
This place may not be safe any more.
Come to my place.
Yes, but...
If you have anything important,
you may take it with you.
Can I take Winnie with me?
Yes, of course.
Stupid brats.
They finally came back.
They brought him into the office.
Damn Holmes.
He must be trying to swindle the kid
and keep the jewel for himself.
Why don't we get a good night's
sleep and attack them tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
There is no tomorrow for criminals!
You two!
Go back and watch Holmes' office!
What? Right now?
What about dinner?
Shut up!
Just stuff yourselves with anything
around here and leave!
Yes, yes, yes!
These were my clothes
when I was a child.
I can barely move in these things.
You shouldn't say that.
I will give your clothes
back after I do the laundry.
Well, it looks quite good on you.
You look nice Polly.
Humph!
All the men get excited
when I wear this type of clothes.
I liked the outfit you
were wearing today.
But, it's you who looks nice.
Well, let's eat dinner now.
Here.
Cheers!
This smells like tobacco.
Because it's my bed.
Do you mind it?
No, not at all.
My dad's bed smelled just like this.
I see.
Mr. Holmes.
Yes.
Do you dislike young pickpockets?
I knew immediately
after I saw your room...
that you were a good child.
Do you want me
to give you the jewel?
Only if you feel you should, Polly.
Good night.
Yes, good night.
Now...
While Holmes is looking for their
hideout, I have to protect Polly.
I can't sleep tonight.
Hot!
Who is it?
Ms. Hudson.
A messenger brought
this letter just now.
This is a letter from Holmes.
"Watson, danger is looming ahead".
"I am under observation and
I can not come out".
"I'll be waiting in the coach
at the crossroads."
"Please send Polly there by herself
and in secret."
Wake Polly up.
Yes.
Mr. Holmes?
I don't know the details,
but I assume he has some plan.
Wait a second.
That's the carriage. Can you see it?
Yes.
Holmes!
Damn it!
Go!
Holmes!
The car!
You won't get away this time
you brat!
Do you think you can fool me
by wearing a girl's outfit?
Where did you hide the jewel?
Tell me!
If you don't tell me...
What are you doing?!
Professor! Holmes is chasing us!
What?!
Humph.
He's panicking and chasing us.
Just go to the park quickly!
Over there!
Polly!
Mr!
Don't give up, Smiley!
Don't give in! Kick! Kick!
Kick?! Kick?!
Smiley, don't worry
about what happens next.
For everyone's sake, just let go.
Yes sir.
You take care of
yourself too, Professor.
Good bye, Holmes!
They're too high.
Give it up brat.
Todd!
Fly straight to hideout number two.
Yes!
Oh, wait!
Don't go on top of the wing!
It's just paper!
Mr. Holmes!
Polly! Don't let go!
Todd! Control the plane!
Damn it! What are you doing?!
Raise altitude!
The engine is malfunctioning!
What?!
Did you check the
plug before you left?!
I think so!
Watson, hold the wing!
I quit being a white collar criminal!
Damn you little brat!
I'm a girl!
What?!
It's heading for the Thames River.
Holmes, the engine!
A bridge! It's a bridge!
Bridge! Get out of my way!
How can a bridge
get out of the way?!
Everybody evacuate!
Yes, yes!
Polly!
Mr. Holmes!
Got you!
Ouch!
Sliding!
Safe!
Mr. Holmes! Thank you very much!
I'm glad!
Winnie.
Did you know about Winnie?
Yes.
Do I have to return this?
I thought I could
make this my treasure.
But it's all right.
Well, that's the Blue Ruby,
the only one in the world.
Yes.
Well, you're the person who
protected the jewelry from Moriarty.
We will go with you.
Why don't you give this
to the shop owner yourself.
Don't you agree Watson?
Yes. I think it's a great idea.
Then I'll do it.
Then it's a deal.
Now let's go back and eat breakfast.
Yeah.
Mrs. Hudson may
be worrying about us.
Hurry up!
Yes!
The prize of five hundred guineas
would be of most use to Polly.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
A green balloon has fallen
into Mrs. Hudson's garden.
Tied to it is a
letter asking for help.
Holmes discovered that the balloon
came from the ocean.
Is this a shipwreck or a kidnapping?
Whenever you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Solve the Mystery
of the Green Balloon!