FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Grand Flight Championship of Chaos!?
I did it! It's finally complete!
Helen! Helen!
Come and see, Helen.
Quickly.
Oh, my! Is this it?!
Compared with the
earlier prototypes...
this engine is several
times more powerful.
I'm so glad!
I was beginning to worry that it
wouldn't be ready on time.
Don't worry. With this...
I'll win this year's World Aircraft
Championship for sure.
I will preserve the honour of England!
Shall we celebrate?
Yes, we'll eat out tonight.
Now!
Let's grab it.
Oops!
Watch it!
Oh no! Put out that fire!
It's no use.
It's not going out.
My precious cloak!
Go out! Go out!
Oh, my! Fire! Fire!
Rats! Hide!
And there goes another one.
I wonder if it's close by?
Those flames appear to be quite high...
But a fire usually appears to be
closer than it really is.
That smoke isn't the type you would
expect to see if a house was on fire.
It must be from a factory...
or some place where the fire
is burning quantities of oil.
That direction...
that would be the factory
owned by Mac Bain!
Mac Bain? Do you mean the famous
aeronautical engineer?
If I remember right, he's the favourite
to win the world aircraft championship.
A race that will be held in Holland
sometime soon.
My late husband really
admired him.
Oh, I do hope everything's all right.
Well then.
Why don't we have a look?
How terrible! Where is Mac?
Is Helen safe?
Ma'am, it's too dangerous!
Stay back! Stay back!
We are acquaintances of Mac.
I am Sherlock Holmes.
Pardon me, sir.
Please stay here, Mrs. Hudson.
Mac! Helen!
Let me see...
How could this have happened
in an empty factory?
This is it. Someone must have
knocked this over.
No! It's not here!
My engine! I've just completed it!
It's gone!
Please stay back, Mr. Mac Bain.
It's too dangerous.
The engine was just completed?
No... It can't be.
The efforts of a lifetime have been...
We understand how you feel.
Mac, please get a hold of yourself.
Chief, one of our fire trucks
has disappeared!
That's impossible! Keep looking!
I made some hot soup.
Please have some,
it'll make you feel better.
You're welcome to
stay here if you'd like.
Thank you very much for your kindness.
Oh, dear, I don't think you should give
up just because the engine...
No!
There's no hope whatsoever.
It's all over!
Your wife is correct.
I think it's too early to give up, Mac.
Spare me your empty
words of comfort.
I am giving you no such thing, sir.
I am saying that I can help you.
Have you found a clue?
Is that? It can't be.
This was left at the scene of the fire.
I believe that this scrap of cloth is
from the cloak of Professor Moriarty.
Moriarty?
An odd little man who fancies
himself a criminal genius.
So, he stole the engine...
Dear!
Please help them, Mr. Holmes.
Ouch! Ouch!
What the devil is this?
An engine?!
Who would dare drop such
a filthy old thing out of the sky?!
That's Moriarty's aircraft Pteranodon!
Did he intentionally drop it on me?
After him! Give chase!
Go!
What a wonderful engine!
With this, there's no doubt that
I will win the world championship.
I knew that we couldn't win
with the engine that the Professor built.
Did you say something?
Uh... well.
Nothing.
Out to sea?
Where are they heading?
"The judging committee has approved
the entry of a mysterious aviator..."
"Mr. Black Eagle, who had been
petitioning for some time..."
"to be allowed to participate
in the race."
A mysterious aviator?
Look at this face!
Who else could this be
other than Moriarty?
He is going after the prize of
100,000 crowns, Moriarty, that fiend!
Trying to win the championship
with a stolen engine...
that's thoroughly unforgivable!
Mr. Mac Bain was always
so kind to my late husband.
I would like to do something
to help him in return.
You look very nice.
I promise, I won't get in your way.
In any event, I've already decided.
Well...
Well... uh...
Right...
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Hurry up and get us to Holland!
I will capture Moriarty with
my own hands!
Well, well.
Mr. Holmes,
your reputation precedes you.
Welcome to Holland.
In terms of this Mr. Black Eagle,
we've discussed whether we should...
accept his entry or not. However...
However?
Have you heard the old story
from medieval times?
Where a mysterious cavalier
came out of nowhere to participate...
in a joust and won the title?
So you're saying that you accepted
the mysterious pilot's entry...
in honour of that cavalier.
Yes.
But, Moriarty used foul means to...
Do you have proof that
Mr. Black Eagle is Moriarty?
No, but...
Never mind the issue of proof...
I will never allow
his wrongdoing to succeed!
- How do you see the outcome of this race?
- How confident do you feel?
Thanks to the absence of Mac...
I now have great
hopes of winning the title.
What about Black Eagle?
I've never even heard of him.
So it may safely be said that I will
be the one to win the championship.
What's that?
Mac!
So you are going to participate
in the race after all?
Yes, this is the prototype of
my missing engine.
I had kept it at a friend's place,
so it wasn't destroyed in the fire.
It may be not as powerful as
the other one, but I'll race with it.
Good luck to you, Mac.
I'll do what little I can.
You're right.
Let's do our best.
Am I in time?
It's really a fine day for flying,
isn't it?
Has Moriarty appeared?
No, not yet.
Please take care of Mrs. Hudson.
I'll fly with Mac.
Right.
Finally, the moment has come
for me to show the world...
that my "Crow" is Number One!
Here! Here!
I can't wait to see who's going
to win the championship.
Are you ready, Mrs. Hudson?
Yes.
How strange!
He still hasn't appeared.
Oh! It fell apart!
Oh, my god!
This is Moriarty's doing.
There he is!
Hey!
Here we go!
You won't get away from me!
Wait!
Here they come!
What a fantastic engine
I have stolen!
It works perfectly with
my beloved 'Crow'!
Dirty rats!
Here we go!
You, get out of my way.
How paltry!
Here we come!
Stop that, stop that!
You won't get away from me.
You coward.
Oh, I'm coming apart!
It seems that we're
the last two planes left.
What?!
Here I come!
When it comes to technique,
I can hold my own against anyone!
Get down!
How swift he is!
If that's how you're going to be,
I'll just come to you.
All right then, commence
Mrs. Hudson's basket operations.
Would you like some tea?
And, here's some dessert as well.
Good job!
Here I go!
Look out! Right, right!
You...
Go! Go get him!
No.
What's your problem?!
Now, go!
Hey, let go.
What?! No!
Holmes!
Where are they?
Where did he go?!
Professor Moriarty.
So Holmes, we finally make
the time for our final confrontation.
I will settle my accounts
with you right now.
Sure thing!
Just look!
You have no escape.
Holmes!
That's the spirit, Mac Bain!
It can't be!
I'm sorry that your engine is...
No, it's all right.
I can always make a new one.
I'd rather lose my engine than
seeing it misused by a villain.
This is it.
Here I go.
I do this and this, and then...
Professor, here we come!
Oh, no!
Ouch! Ouch! Ouch!
Wait!
He has the devil's luck, indeed.
Did you see that?
Two planes are leading.
Mac's and Hudson's.
Everybody's here.
Dear!
Helen!
Here. Congratulations
on your victory.
Congratulations, Mac.
Thank you very much.
I owe my victory entirely
to your kindness.
No, it's due to your
excellent engine.
Or perhaps to
Mrs. Hudson's lunch basket.
Oh, that may be right.
I wished I could have asked Professor
Moriarty how he liked the dessert.
I bet it was the bitterest
cake he had ever tasted.
Ouch...
Shall we raise our glasses?
Cheers!
Professor...
we completely blew it, didn't we?
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Moriarty's mechanical dragon attacks
a speeding locomotive...
and they steal a parrot that
belongs to one of the passengers.
Meanwhile, Holmes finds out
that there's a relationship...
between the parrot and Indian
merchant who's gone missing.
What will the parrot tell us?
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Game of Wits! Parrot vs Professor