FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Professor's Big
Failure in the Storm!!
Keep it up!
Faster!
That's it!
Is this wise, Inspector?
Don't worry! Go faster!
Whoops!
Hey, get me!
Got you!
Very good.
This new car
is a great model.
It's safe and performs great.
Quite right.
We can catch any
kind of criminal with this.
What's wrong?
What?!
Inspector, we've ran out of gas.
This is the third time the police
department has had to buy new cars.
Considering Inspector Lestrade
was test driving this time...
he must be really angry.
Eh, Holmes?
Automobile companies are
putting a great deal of effort...
into the development of new cars
and the number of cars is increasing.
But people may begin to lose faith
in the automotive industry.
Do you smell something frightful?
What?
It's not as bad as usual...
Oh, on second thought it does
smell rather dangerous.
It's the smell of crime.
What?
I guess we can't make juice
from hydrogen after all.
I heard a loud noise,
but I guess everything's all right.
Mrs. Hudson, I guess
you weren't hurt...
but you must have been startled.
Oh I'm fine, but there's
a client waiting.
You do have a good nose.
I'll be right there.
After I've cleaned myself up.
Mr. Focus is a banker
and the richest man in town.
He's also a famous antique collector...
but this is far more than I expected.
It's very quiet.
There's no sign of criminals here.
I was referring to
the police car before.
What?
Then you don't think
it was an accident.
You're planning to transport money
from the bank to Manchester tomorrow?
As you know, my father
hates modern things.
He insists on going
by horse and carriage.
That won't be easy.
It's a two day round trip,
without resting the horses.
I've asked him over and over, but he
says he doesn't need a police escort...
So I...
I see.
You want us to
escort him in secret.
Yes, if you would.
Of course!
For a sweet girl who cares
so much for her father...
we'll do it no matter
who tries to stop us!
Right, Holmes?
We'll make sure he's protected.
You certainly live up to your
reputation as a great detective.
I'm glad I asked you.
As long as we're here, we won't allow
a beautiful woman like you to feel sad.
Will we, Holmes?
He's totally smitten.
What are you doing up there?
These things get dirty, constantly.
Be careful.
Keep up the good work.
Oh, I'm so hungry.
I haven't eaten real food for days.
Isn't there any food in the kitchen?
Maybe, let's look.
Hey Smiley, let's go
back to being pirates.
At least we won't
go hungry there.
Rats! Not even one cookie.
Nothing at all.
Damn!
Strawberry!
What?!
It's true.
Cunning professor!
Hiding this in the dirty laundry.
He's so greedy.
Trying to eat this all by himself.
Let's eat them all.
Eat them all.
Something's wrong
with these strawberries.
I suddenly feel sleepy.
Yeah, me too.
You dolts!
Those strawberries were
for the police horse!
I put sleeping pills in them!
But they were really awful.
Yeah, they were very old.
No horse would've eaten them.
You should appreciate the fact that
you can eat when we have no money!
Nothing!
Not even one!!
Now I have to think of another
way to stall the police.
That's all right.
Our long period of poverty
is at an end, today.
We can eat all the finest food,
as much as we want, after tomorrow.
You got the money?!
Where? Where?
You idiots!
There's work to be done!
Start training!
Yes!
Heave ho!
Work hard! Work hard!
Work hard!
I'm starting to feel sleepy.
I'm sleepy.
Sleepy. Sleepy. Sleepy.
I can't take any more.
I'm falling asleep, too.
Good night.
Our company makes
great performance cars.
They're totally different from our rival,
NG motors.
There always is a possibility
of a breakdown...
but nothing like these
strange accidents.
I'll arrest you if you're lying.
Inspector.
May I examine the wrecked car?
What?
What are you going
to do with that junk?
Where is it?
The trash dump
at the police station.
I don't even know
if it's still there.
Mr. Holmes.
Why would he want to see the car?
He must be investigating something!
Follow him!
Oops!
There's a crack in the fuel line.
And they filed the pipe with...
Just as I suspected.
What's the point of escorting
someone who doesn't like the police...
and says he doesn't need an escort?!
Why are you wearing riding clothes?
Even though you asked,
I won't take you with me today.
I wish I could make you
change your mind...
but I'll just practice my
riding on the way back.
Don't get carried away.
Be careful, Papa.
Take care of things
while I'm gone.
Be careful.
It's the time that
the Professor told us.
That awful training
makes my whole body ache.
And yesterday's strawberry sleeping
pills still make me feel dizzy.
Here we go.
No!
I think it's about time.
Giddy up!
So, you're saying Moriarty's the one
who caused the police car accident.
There's an uneasy storm brewing.
Why would he do it?
So he could successfully
complete his plan.
His plan?
Are you saying he's planning
to commit some big crime?
Don't you think he's a typical
target for the Professor?
Yes.
The Bank President
is becoming impatient.
I hope the horses don't wear out.
Are you all right, Watson?!
Goodness sakes, I...
I'm all right.
Watson, it's gunpowder!
Get down quickly!
What are you talking about?!
How can I get down quickly?!
Go!
What?
It's them.
Moriarty's henchmen?!
Just as I suspected,
they're trying to stall the police.
So they blew up one
police car after another...
awaiting the chance
to rob that horse carriage.
I see.
That's his strategy.
Now that we know the enemy is
Moriarty, we have to inform Mr. Focus.
Watson, hang on tight.
Alright!
With that 400,000 pounds...
and the successful disposal
of our worthy opponent Holmes...
This genius thief will thoroughly
enjoy his next meal.
Stupid Smiley! You blundered!
All right, now for my next attack!
Now!
Oh, rats!
You fool!
I can't hold on!
Curse you Holmes,
will you never give up?!
Ouch!
I'll show you what I can do to you!
Time for the next operation!
Mr. Focus!
I'm not a suspicious person!
But I have something to tell you!
Come any closer and I'll shoot!
A criminal genius named Moriarty
is trying to steal your money!
Please be careful!
I'm more suspicious about both of you
knowing about these things.
Hurry up!
Yes.
Stop it! It's dangerous!
Be careful, or else it will fall.
We have to rescue the horse.
Now is my chance to
get ahead of them.
Take that!
What?
What's this?
Rats!
Here.
Alright.
OK.
Careful Holmes!
That's it.
Slowly, slowly.
It's a very important horse.
Please be careful.
Almost there.
Don't be so rough.
Get off.
You're totally different
from your daughter.
That was really close.
You can't do it.
You have to let him go.
Don't tell me what to do!
I know that!
You should move your
luggage to my car.
Don't be silly! I will take care
of my job in my own way.
My family has gone everywhere and done
everything with this horse carriage.
If it's necessary, I'd even pull
the carriage by myself.
You!
Why don't you try to understand your
daughter's feelings of concern.
Papa!
Emily!
Giddy up!
Why did you come here?
I expected this might've happened.
Here, your replacement horse.
Then you were already
planning to follow us?
I'm sorry, it's not that
I doubted both of you.
I love horses more than my Papa does,
and the carriage as well
I'd feel bad if the horse
was forced to continue.
Yes, of course.
I'm glad you weren't seriously hurt.
Papa, this is Mr. Holmes and Mr. Watson.
They are private detectives.
I hired them.
Nice to meet you.
Humph!
I'm not the one who hired you.
Don't you understand
your daughter's...
I'm sorry. He's very stubborn.
Well, I mean...
Don't worry about it.
You asked me to work for you,
not that blockhead...
Well, I'm sorry...
I'll take this horse home,
so don't worry.
What have they been
doing all this time?
They should've finished
digging a long time ago.
Why should I be doing this?
I'm the Professor.
Professor!
Oh, how is the work progressing?
Idiots! You're late!
Take my place! Take my place!
What is he trying to do with this?
He is planning to lure
the carriage in here.
Old carrots won't work.
How is it?
Here they come!
We need to make up for lost time.
Hurry!
There was only one before.
When did it become like this?
Go!
Run! Run! Run!
Take the left tunnel!
Huh?! Why?! Why?!
Rats!
The smell of the carrot didn't reach
because of the storm.
Why did you choose left tunnel?
I saw the tracks of
the carriage go through.
Professor.
I've stop being a clever criminal!
From now on, we will use force!
Holmes, it's Moriarty!
Now I'll crush you!
Power up!
- Yes sir!
- Heave ho! Heave ho!
I won't let him go!
I'll crush him!
Holmes, watch out!
Watson, hang on tight!
Whoops!
How can he be so clever?
I'll make sure to settle this later.
What is that?!
Mr. Focus, that is Professor Moriarty.
Moriarty?!
He's acting reckless!
How can your primitive carriage
win against my steam car?
Take this!
Curses!
Blow them up with dynamite!
Sure!
Dynamite... Dynamite...
Here.
What?
Hurry up! Hurry!
Good!
Here we go.
Oh, no!
No!
Holmes.
Mr. Focus...
Moriarty and his henchmen
won't chase you anymore...
so you don't have to worry.
Thank you Mr. Holmes.
Holmes!
Stop right there!
Where is Moriarty and his henchmen?
Oh, I just saw them
floating in the sky.
Weren't they, Watson?
Yes, yes. Floating.
This way! Hurry!
Curses! What was the point
of crushing the police car?
You made us do ridiculous training.
Right?
Yes, my body is totally worn out and I'm
very hungry, too. How can I be strong?
Don't think you can get
away like this, Holmes!
Mark my words, Holmes!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
On a train departing
Liverpool at 5:25 PM...
and bound for London...
the freight car carrying gold bullion
suddenly disappears.
What kind of magic
did the Professor use?!
Holmes starts the investigation of
the disappearing freight car.
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Missing Freight Car!?
The Professor's Big Magic Trick