FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Mrs. Hudson Is Taken Hostage
You took so many photographs.
They're all of Holmes.
I will see this thing
through to the end.
That's the criminal's way.
Now, I will explain
the entire operation.
We've had to endure so many things
because of our hated enemy, Holmes.
He's thoroughly beaten us.
Our urgent task is to defeat Holmes
and recover our honour.
Urgent task?
I don't know.
I have been thinking of ways
to beat that cunning young man.
There are so many flies in here.
Shut up! Just listen to me!
Yes.
I've been observing Holmes
closely to find his weakness.
And I've finally found it.
Look at this photo.
Look!
Look at his eyes!!
The way he's acting.
Uh?
He is giving those
eyes to only one person.
This person!
I know her! I know this person!
Mrs. Mary Hudson. She's a widow.
Nineteen years old.
She is the owner of the boarding
house where Holmes staying.
I... I want to have this picture.
Then, what are you
going to do professor?
We'll kidnap her.
Kidnap?! This woman?!
We have no choice
if we are to defeat Holmes.
I understand!
You are planning to marry
her after you kidnap her.
No!
Oh, you are so dirty!
Shut up!
You turned red!
You rat!
Oh, another chemistry experiment?
I wouldn't suggest going
in there for a little while.
I'll be sure not to.
Here is a letter, it just arrived.
Oh, I hope this is a request
for an investigation.
Hey, Holmes!
It must be a letter.
I just made a simple deduction.
I heard a doorbell just before.
Anyhow, why don't you stop
this useless experimentation.
My brain would begin
to rot without work.
Car loan, a bill from the
liquor shop and the drug store.
Nothing looks good.
Watson! It's trouble!
All right.
Are you going some place?
Well, it's not such a big case.
I'll see you.
I'll be back for dinner.
Does Mr. Holmes live here?
Yes.
Hey, carry it in.
Oh, excuse me?
This is our finest coffin
that you ordered.
A coffin?
Excuse me, but this must be
some kind of mistake.
No...
It matches the height perfectly.
Whose height?
Oh, you don't know?
It's yours.
Oh! Perfect!
Careful...
Oh, beautiful.
Just like Snow White.
Is the air hole open?
Of course.
Now!
What a poor joke.
Sending us a fake letter.
Indeed.
Uh?!
This is the plant Mrs. Hudson
was holding when we left here.
I can still smell
some tranquillizer here.
Holmes! Look at this!
Moriarty.
Holmes, I took Mrs. Hudson.
If you care for her safety,
wait quietly for further instructions.
Professor Moriarty.
I see.
He wrote that fake letter.
What can we do Holmes?
We'll just have to wait
for him to contact us.
She isn't waking up.
Is she dead?
Don't worry!
The drug will wear off soon.
But she still hasn't woken up!
She's dead!
What a pest you are!
I said she's just sleeping!
Liar! You killed her!
What?
Don't accuse me like that!
My murders have never
been successful before!
Murder!
What are you doing?!
I'll kill you!
Stop it! Just stop it!
It's dangerous!
I'll die after I kill you!
Don't be so hasty!
I'll kill you!
She came back to life. I'm glad.
I... what happened to me?
See! I told you!
Hurry up!
Just bring coffee or brandy.
No, bring both of them!
We better not talk back to him.
Hurry up!
Yes!
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
You're really slow!
How are you Madam?
It seems like there's a
fatal oversight to this plan.
Shut up!
Hey, this brandy is empty.
I had it the other day.
This was a very expensive brandy!
Hurry up!
I know there's another
one inside your bookshelf.
How'd he know that?
Oh, kidnapped?
Am I being kidnapped?
That's right. You are my prisoner.
If you behave,
I won't take your life.
Which would you prefer?
Coffee or brandy?
Well, I'd like to have brandy.
Here, please help yourself,
but it's not an expensive one.
You seem like a good person.
What's you name?
She said I'm a good person!
What am I gonna do?
I... I'm Smiley.
Enough of this!
This is my secret hideout.
No matter how loud you scream,
nobody will come to help.
Don't you have a wife, Professor?
A wife?
Who would want such a thing?!
But...
Is this place so dirty?
I'm so used to it.
Well, if I have to stay here a while,
can I clean up?
Clean up? I'm a busy person.
I don't have time
to do housework.
I won't make any trouble for you.
Both of you, could you help me?
Yes, we'll be happy to!
Have a nice day!
Is this going to be all right?
Moriarty.
It's already past the time
we were supposed to meet.
I've been here for a long time.
Pick up the phone Mr. Holmes.
A thread phone.
Don't pull so hard.
What are your terms, Moriarty?
Good! You are so submissive, Holmes.
Well, it's no big deal.
You just have to do one task for me.
By tomorrow, I want you to steal
famous portrait, La Giconda...
now on exhibit
at the National Gallery.
And you want to
exchange it for Mrs. Hudson?
That's right.
She's a very attractive woman.
I assume that losing her
would be a great loss.
Busy! Busy!
Inspector.
I received this letter just now.
What?
I'm sure it's just some complaint...
like the neighbour's cat
is making too much noise.
"I am going to steal the
masterpiece La Giconda's..."
"from the National Gallery, tomorrow."
"It's no use trying to guard it.
S.H."
Uh?! This smell's like...
pipe tobacco and chemicals.
It can't be...
No, it can't be!
It can't be!!
Well, I'll have a drink
and go to sleep.
Did I come back to the wrong house?
Oh, are you already home?
Oh! E... Excuse me but what is this?
It's gotten a little cleaner,
hasn't it?
I'll serve dinner right away.
Please put your hat
and coat on the rack.
Y... yes.
Oh!
Welcome home Professor.
What is this?
Here, please sit.
Y... yes.
I hope you will like this.
Oh!
Great! Great! Great!
This is the smell of kidney pie.
Mr. Smiley told me
that you love kidney pie.
T... Then did you make this for me?
What's wrong Professor?
I know.
You have a stomach-ache.
No! I'm touched!
This is... the first time anyone...
I'm deeply moved.
I understand that feeling.
But a game is a game.
I can't loosen up my plan.
Sure. I know my situation.
Work is work.
Here, please eat this.
I've made many more dishes.
Let's eat!
Delicious! Tasty!
Win, lose, win, lose, win.
Lose, win, lose...
Ah... win!!
Damn!
I want to win.
I must beat Holmes this time.
If I can beat him...
Oh, are you going out?
Well, just launching a surprise
attack on the National Bank.
Do a good job!
Please come back for dinner.
All right!
How wonderful!
I'm going to win!
I will absolutely win this time!
How is everything?
Good.
There is no sign of movement, yet.
They've been like that
for the last three hours.
I think it's just a phony letter,
but just to make sure, keep watching.
Yes sir.
Has anyone else
left the house?
An old couple came
out a little while ago.
What?!
Could it be...
Come on!
What's going on?!
Didn't you read the original work?!
Just as I thought.
Place guards all around the museum!
Yes!
They're really going to do it.
Was that detective watching us?
Yes, he's working for Lestrade.
Moriarty must have tipped them off.
But he wants to get the portrait.
No, what he really wants
is to get me arrested.
I see.
Has anything happened?
No, not so far.
There are so many police.
Holmes might have a difficult time.
Rats! Help me!
You're so heavy!
Let me through.
What's going on?!
There are rats!
Coming out all over!
What?!
It's gone!
Damn!
Oh, no!
He left a letter.
"I'll hide this for a little while."
"Please don't worry.
I will return it by tomorrow."
How can I not worry?!
Be quiet!
Nobody move!
If you move even an inch,
I will arrest you!
The thief must be hiding here.
I will check them all one by one.
The portrait isn't small,
so it's not so easy to hide.
He is the last man.
We've already checked all the women,
but we couldn't find anything.
I see.
Wait, I think I've
seen you somewhere.
Ouch!
I'm sorry.
How rude!
Please excuse me.
Do I have to get
into that coffin again?
Yes, after that, I will take you home.
This must be another trap.
Yes, probably.
We'll be arriving shortly at the
location they designated.
Excellent!
This time I'll catch the thief!
I brought the portrait as I promised.
Where is Mrs. Hudson?
Mrs. Hudson, are you all right?!
Yes!
Well, let me see the beauty
that you brought.
That is the greatest treasure
in all history... the Mona Lisa!
What kind of outrageous
thing did you do?!
You acted just like a thief!
Oh my god!
The Detective stole the portrait!
Police!
Yes!
There is the thief who
stole the famous portrait!
You tricked me Moriarty!
You are under arrest
for art theft!
Don't say I tricked you.
People might think it's true.
You villain! Moriarty, you
have the mind of an eggplant!
Don't think you can
get away with this!
That's the line I wanted to hear!
Oh no, it's broken.
What did you do to that
treasure of all mankind?!
Please explain to him, Inspector.
All right.
I just stood in front of the empty
frame with amazement.
But the painting was merely
covered by a piece of paper.
And on the back of
the paper was a note...
with the entire account
of this incident.
This portrait is a copy.
What?!
I guess we lost again.
Yeah.
Excellent Holmes,
but you haven't won just yet.
The hostage is in my hands.
Or are you going to jump
the river to get her back?
I guess he still doesn't understand.
Elementary.
This river is so shallow,
even a child can cross it!
What?
You're right, I can
see fish swimming...
No good! Retreat!
Be careful.
Get them!
Heave-ho!
This is it!
Hang on tight!
Let's go!
Go around! Go around!
Mrs. Hudson, are you all right?
Good, you didn't get hurt.
We lost again.
I really should take you home,
but I have to say goodbye here.
If I ever have the chance,
we can see each other again.
If I had met you earlier, my life
would have changed for the better.
But I promise one thing.
I will never let you become
involved in my work again.
See you.
This is my treasure,
but I'll give it to you.
Oh.
I'll give you my marble.
Thank you.
Good bye!
Hurry up!
Please take care!
Good bye!
Mrs. Hudson.
Are you all right?
You finally arrived.
I'm sorry.
You must have had an awful time.
Look at this.
Uh?
It's the first time I've had
something so worth cleaning.
What?
Wait! Wait!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
In the sky over London, a monster
bird "Steramadon" appeared.
The public square was in a panic.
Professor Moriarty took
advantage of the chaos...
and stole the blue ruby,
the only one of it's kind in the world.
If you ever find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Blue Ruby