FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Great Chase
of the Little Detectives
Oh, that's...
the golden Angel Statue!
Whoops!
Pardon me.
That's better.
That's the country's
finest treasure.
There is nothing else like it.
There they are again.
Ah... rats!
They're in the way! Get rid of them!
You! Go away!
Get out of here!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Brats!
Hard to solve crimes
really excite me.
Moriarty! Tonight?!
Wait!!
As you all know, there's enough
gold in that Angel Statue...
to provide the weapons needed
to destroy an entire country!
Do whatever's necessary
to keep it from Moriarty!
Yes, Sir!
Has Moriarty been delayed?
Get on with it!
It's him!
Ridiculous!
Why didn't you mention in your warning
that you would come from the sky!
Now you know the true genius of
crime that Professor Moriarty is!
Here goes.
Whoops!
Listen up!
I'll give a reward
to whoever catches him!
Yes, Sir!
Okay, piece of cake.
Well, we can't let him get
away with the Angel Statue.
It's the symbol of our nation's peace.
Where is Inspector Lestrade?
He's leading a suicide squad.
So he is...
Let's see, the wind is...
Okay.
He won't get away.
Your suicide squad efforts
are down the drain.
Good luck on your way back down.
So long.
I won't let you go!
I will not allow you to escape.
Let's follow him.
Hey!
Why you! Wait a sec! Hey!
Hey, pull me up will ya!
You annoy me.
Now...
What! Hey, wait!
You don't have to!
All gone!
This is bad.
We'll have to go around
and take the bridge.
Professor, don't linger!
Please land quickly!
What?
What's wrong?
What's with this?
Not like this!
Professor!
Are you OK?
Are you dead?
I am immortal!
Hurry up and hide the Angel Statue
at the prepared site.
Yes, Sir.
We did it.
Not yet.
The wind is from the
south-east with a 3.2 velocity.
The wind has died down
but maintains the same direction.
Let's hurry.
Hey, can you see?
It's him, isn't it?
Come on.
We're hurrying.
Listen!
Check the contents of
every carriage thoroughly.
My life is depending
on this police cordon...
to cover the entire city of London.
Don't let even a
single ant sneak out!
Wait!
Do it.
All right, you can go.
That rat.
What a fool.
All I have to do is to
wait until the heat is off.
We'll hide in the warehouse and stake
out quietly until Moriarty arrives.
What?
There's no trace of the carriage,
even after a thorough search.
So the Angel Statue must be hidden
around here somewhere.
Does that mean they'll
come back to get it?
They'll be back.
Be careful.
Huh?
Hey, wait a minute!
Hurry!
I said wait!
Hey, over here!
Wait!
Oops, Watson!
Sorry I landed on you!
We did it!
Don't underestimate us!
We haven't done anything.
Why don't you tell me what's wrong?
You can't fool us!
We know you're one of them!
One of them?
To whom are you referring?
Humph!
Humph?
Cool, isn't it?
We can go on our dream adventure...
once we've installed
this engine on our boat.
We're in trouble.
Indeed.
What are we going to do, Holmes?
They're not upstairs!
Have they gone up in the sky?
Or down underground?
If we don't get back the Angel Statue,
my life as an inspector...
Stop! Stop!
Stop searching where
there's nothing to be found!
Move on to the next location!
Yes, Sir!
The cops withdrew so quickly.
Lestrade's head is empty.
I can't believe he's an inspector.
Yeah, empty, empty,
completely empty.
I hope they didn't find our
hiding place for the Angel Statue.
Don't be stupid.
My brain is the best in the world.
No one can match...
Well, maybe one person can.
Are you talking about Holmes?
Yeah, yeah.
You must be scared of him.
Shut up!!
Holmes, why are you
going along with these kids?
There's no harm.
Tell me.
When you said "them", you meant
Professor Moriarty, right?
You saw Moriarty come down
in that balloon, didn't you?
Be quiet!
You're still trying to act innocent
after messing up our playground!
Humph!
Moriarty's come
here that many times?
Perhaps in preparation of something...
Preparation?
Yes.
It's them again!
Get in close and grab him.
It's them!
Let's rescue him!!
Okay!
Take the other side.
It appears Moriarty has arrived.
Oh, over here, too.
Sure.
Not yet? Hurry it up!
Yes, Sir.
Here we come!
You rascals!
Don't assume I'll go easy on you
just 'cause you're little kids!
Whoa!
Look out!
Take that!
You!
What?!
Watch out, stop it!
You little!
Take this!
Oops!
I'll take the hostage
as a last resort!
Ouch!
He got away?!
While the Professor was dancing,
I saved the kid.
Dancing!
Drat!
Smarty pants Holmes!
Eat this!
Watch out! Get out of here!
Here we go.
Huh?
Mister, it's true you're one of them.
I'm sorry.
I'm glad you see that.
You were brave.
Boys should have courage.
Oh no!
Two members are missing!
They're still on that boat.
After them! Quickly!
After them? We've no boat!
Sure, you do.
You have your boat.
Everyone, will you help us?
Yeah.
What a disaster, eh Professor?
It doesn't matter so long as
we get what we want.
They have no boat to come after us.
Then the treasure is all ours.
Okay.
Good.
Careful.
Good?
There, it's done!
Our boat!
Let's go save your friends.
We'll have to hurry.
Here goes!
Good!
We did it!
Here goes!
Can we catch up with them?
What?
Idiots! Check it out, quickly!
It's Holmes!
What?! It can't be!
It's very fast!
Right, this engine is special.
I keep it well tuned.
Whoops.
What nonsense is this?!
Take them...
hostage!
Here.
Want some more?
I'll drive you straight into that.
Watson, full speed!
All right.
What do those fools
think they're doing?!
Hey, don't panic!
After them!
Watson, you take over!
Certainly.
You overly persistent pests!
More power from the engine!
Easy for you to say.
With this wrecked engine.
Shut up and do what I told you!
Yeah, yeah...
Whatever.
Whoops!
Thanks.
Abandon ship!
We did it!!
I know they've hidden the Angel Statue
somewhere on this boat.
It's not here.
Not here.
No, not here, either.
We can't find it.
It's not on deck or in the hold.
Then, it must be here.
We found it!
Mister!
Yes?
Sorry, we busted your car!
We'll give you the engine back!
We'll give it back!
Well, just consider it a present
to help fulfil your dream.
Really?!
Yes, really.
In return, you can take both of us
on your next adventure.
All right?
Oh, sure thing!
You'll definitely come with us?!
You got it.
See you later.
Goodbye!
Bye, thanks Mister!
Thanks Mister!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
After solving a crime...
Holmes and I wandered into an old
mansion where a dark plot was brewing.
What impending danger waits
for the beautiful lady of the mansion?
And what is the frightening
secret of a dotted rope?
If you ever find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Speckled Band