FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Speckled Band
Professor, Professor!
Professor!
Professor!!
Ouch.
What is it?
How can you be so calm?
Miss Ellen, the lady of the house is
coming back from America any minute.
There's no point in panicking.
We are fully prepared.
Take a look.
I didn't know that you knew
her for so long a time.
Idiot.
This is just a composite picture!
I can buy her trust with this.
It's so like you!
She has an eye-popping
amount of fortune.
Remember, you are the
servant of this house.
I wish I had a better role.
I've missed this old house
where I grew up.
Welcome home, Miss Ellen.
Thank you for taking
care of the house.
I'm glad to be back.
Oh, I'd forgotten
that I had this picture.
Even back then, you were
already very pretty.
You used to toddle to me
calling out, "Roylee, Roylee."
All of you haven't changed a bit,
you still look young.
What a sweet thing to say
to an old woman like me.
Thank you for that delicious meal.
You mean this?
You must be tired
after your long trip.
Thank you.
This is my childhood room.
Yes. I'll take my leave.
Good night.
Miss Ellen, please keep
your voice down at night.
You surprised me by visiting
my lab this late at night.
You idiots!
Are you trying to ruin my plan?!
Mr. Holmes, I have a letter for you.
Thank you.
Lately, you've been receiving
investigation requests...
from as far away as America.
Yes...
Roylott?
Who's he?
Is that another request
for an investigation?
Mr. Holmes, good luck!
Mr. Roylott, I have
a letter for Miss Ellen.
It's from her fiancé, isn't it?
I'm so envious of him, being able to
marry a girl of such wealth...
and such beauty.
Anything else?
Are you sure this is all?
An unnecessary inconvenience.
Giddy up!
As usual, you displayed
your prowess, Holmes.
Not at all.
I took more time than
expected on that case.
Oops!!
The road's getting more desolate.
It looks that way.
Even the car appears to be sulking.
No, not appears to be,
it's completely depressed.
Not here.
We can't cheer up a car.
Great, it is raining.
Can you hand me a screwdriver?
Certainly.
How is it? Can you repair it?
I'm not sure.
It's really starting to rain.
We have no choice but to push the car.
Holmes, stay on top of it!
Yes, yes, yes.
Sorry, just a little further.
Keep going.
Oh, we made it.
Oh, no?!
Holmes!
Please hurry up and grab it!
I don't want to be run
over by my own car!
Hold on, Holmes!
I'm coming quickly!
But I don't think!
Holmes, look out!
Now!
Are you all right, Holmes?!
Are you injured, Holmes?
And I thought I was good at this.
We're saved.
Drat, it's them again!
Hey!
Please stop!
Please stop.
Our car broke down.
Watch out, Watson!
This is...
a seriously bad day today.
From the looks of this place,
monsters are going to pop out.
Apparently, someone lives here.
Maybe they can't hear us.
Holmes!
Our car broke down...
in this rain.
May we see your master?
Who is it?
It's nothing.
Don't talk like that.
Invite them in.
Yes.
I'm Holmes, just a traveller.
Our car broke down in this rain.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Please stay with us until
the car gets repaired.
Thank you for your kindness.
We don't mean to be brash.
Well, I'm called Watson.
There is a garage in the back.
You can put your car in there.
Thank you. We will.
We're saved, Holmes.
Miss Ellen sure is beautiful and we can
hardly complain about the house.
Though the old woman is
rather unsettling.
She's the housekeeper
of my cousin, Roylott.
She doesn't talk much.
Mr. Roylott's?
Pay him no mind.
He studies the ecology of animals.
He's a little odd.
He really is odd.
I'm not good with oddballs.
Where is he now?
I asked him to do some errands.
He should be back shortly.
You must be tired.
It's early, but please go on to bed.
Oh, already...
I should repair my car tonight.
All right.
Don't overwork yourself.
As I expected, he came
back some time ago.
In a house this big...
it's no surprise that one wouldn't
notice someone coming in or out.
But why?
Ellen's fiancé will arrive
the day after tomorrow.
We must finish the work before then.
What are we gonna do about, Holmes?
Leave that to me.
They haven't seen me yet.
And hide this letter.
It's really quiet here.
Maybe Holmes is finished
with the car.
But those footsteps...
maybe Miss Ellen has come
by for some conversation?
Well, then...
That's strange.
I'm sure something
was in front of the door.
No strangers allowed in this house!!
Get out!!
It's the oddball!!
Get out!
I don't understand!
This house is cursed!
Don't do that!
Get out of this house
for your own sake!!
Holmes!
I can't take it!
Ouch!
Gone! Gone!
The stairs are gone!!
There, it's done.
That was a close call!
That's a dangerous
trap they've set here.
They must be getting desperate.
It's Roylott.
What are these?!
Is this Roylott's lab?
What kind of place is this?!
Hey, what are you doing?
Help me!
Holmes!
I scared Watson away
when he came into the lab.
Well done.
Don't allow anyone to enter the lab.
What a house! It's full of monsters!
How long does it take
to repair a car?
No matter what happens, I won't move
from here until Holmes gets back!
What?
What is this?!
What is this spotted rope?!
What's wrong?
Why are you so panicky?
Holmes!
As soon as you're done with the car,
we should get out of here.
I see, for an old man,
he's quite strong.
What are you mumbling about?!
Forget that.
Let's get out of this creepy house!
You're right.
We should get out of
this creepy house quickly.
It's late, but we'll say goodbye
to Miss Ellen before we go.
That's a good idea.
Why do you have to go
at this time of night?
We're sorry to have bothered you.
If you ever have any trouble
please contact us.
Okay.
Good bye.
You haven't forgotten anything
have you, Watson?
Everything's okay.
See you again sometime.
Oh?!
Great, they left without noticing us.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry but would
you remain here?
Is it the car again?
I'll explain to you why later.
I must hurry.
Hey, Holmes!
Wait, Holmes!
I'll be right back.
Stay awake tonight.
Scream if something happens.
I wonder what's supposed to happen?
I thought we were leaving, Holmes.
Who?! Who's there?!
I'm glad that you're all right.
I have no idea what's going on.
You happen to be in danger.
Remain here for now.
A venomous snake.
Be careful, Holmes!
No! I hate snakes!
Watson, put out the fire!
There.
Holmes must have called for them!
Drat! Go back!
Holmes, what's going on?!
What happened to the crooks?
Thank you for coming,
Inspector Lestrade.
They're probably in the back garden.
Go around to the back garden!
They're using a balloon again!
After them!!
Catch us if you can.
I won't give up so easily!
Open fire!
We've been hit!
Stop making stupid faces
and pedal faster!!
Your luck's run out.
I'll have you in my hands soon!
Professor!!
We're still going down!!
Go as far as you can!
Keep pedalling!!
Hey, wait!
Tickle, tickle, tickle.
Well done.
Look out!
See you later!
You cowards!
This stinks!
Thank you for saving my life.
But how did you know
that I was in danger?
Ellen!
Oh, Johnny!
I've just arrived from New York.
I was worried when
your letters didn't come.
I've been sending you
a letter every day.
Thank you for your help.
Johnny, do you know Mr. Holmes?
Since he didn't receive your letters,
he asked me to investigate.
Your cousin, Roylott,
was destroying the letters.
Oh?
Dr. Roylott died of an illness
10 years ago.
Then, who was that man?
He's a villain named Moriarty.
He was after the
valuables in your house.
A villain?
He was planning to
sell the dinosaurs...
that your cousin,
the archaeologist, unearthed...
and sell to a museum
for profit.
Holmes, why didn't you
explain that to me?
I'm sorry, but it was the
only way to fool them.
So everyone knew but me!
I feel like a clown!
Don't be upset.
We didn't catch the Roylott imposter.
But they'll live happily ever after.
Isn't that enough?
Oh, well.
Snake!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
While servicing the beloved
prototype Mercedes Benz...
Holmes and I were abducted
and taken to the Naval Commander.
The case begins with the
disappearance of a submarine...
and involves an undersea treasure
discovered by adventurer, Raythunder.
If ever you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Treasure Under the Sea