FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Solve the Mystery
of the Green Balloon!
Push. Push.
Excellent.
Hurry up!
What?!
There they are! Get them!
Get 'em!
Fools, how dare they!
Oops!
Curse you! Wait! Wait!
Now!
Here we go!
You!!
Pull! Pull!
Get on board, quickly!
Nyah-nyah nyaah-nyaah!
What's going on?
You idiots! Chase them, get them!
Well... Goodbye!
Au revoir!
Ciao!
Hurry! Chase them!
Make sure to capture them!
Worthless.
Next, go!
Bonehead.
W... Wait, I've got you!
Don't touch me.
Wait, you darn smugglers.
Do you hear me? I'll get you!
I'm going to catch you someday!
Inspector Lestrade makes
a bombshell announcement.
Arrest of the culprits
will be forthcoming...
D... Don't mention it, Mrs. Hudson...
What is going on?
Mr. Watson.
I feel guilty that someone of your
importance would offer to help.
Don't mention it.
I have lots of time on my hands.
There you go again, Watson!
Under the blue sky,
surrounded by beautiful flowers...
Mrs. Hudson,
you look lovely... quite lovely.
Don't get carried away
and ruin her flower garden.
Anything wrong?
Oh, nothing. Shall we?
Look! A balloon.
Some kids must find it amusing to drop
green balloons into your green garden.
Shall we continue?
Budworm!
Help.
Capture the evil gang.
Dolphin Island.
Dolphin Island...
Oh my, what a cute letter.
Mrs. Hudson, have you
ever heard of "Dolphin Island"?
Dolphin Island? No, I haven't.
Maybe, it's a very small island,
not even visible on a map.
"Dolphin Island" sounds like a
name any kid could come up with.
It could be the work
of some mischievous child.
I hope that proves to be so...
if not, we may have
a big problem on our hands.
Thanks for your patience.
It's finally dry.
Oh, thank you, thank you.
I am so privileged.
I wonder where
Mr. Holmes has gone off to?
Oh my!
- Give me one!
- Can I have one?!
I need them for my work.
I'll give some to you next time.
Sorry.
Is he still working?
It has been almost 5 hours...
He's been ignoring all my questions.
Let's start dinner, shall we?
Holmes, dinner is ready.
Is there something
wrong with your head?
Hey, Holmes!
Sorry, but go ahead without me.
That won't do.
There is nothing I can do.
5 hours 12 minutes!
Watson! Take a memo! Now!
12 minutes 30 seconds.
31 seconds.32 seconds.
33 seconds.34 seconds.
I got it. Thank you.
It took an average of 5 hours,
15 minutes for the balloons to fall.
In other words, the balloon that fell
in Mrs. Hudson's garden...
flew that much time from somewhere.
Considering today's
pressure distribution...
referencing wind direction and velocity
against meteorological observation...
I deduced that the balloon
came from around here.
A seaplane?!
Right now?
Mr. Hudson must've had many contacts
with air plane companies.
It would be the quickest way.
Yes, I understand.
I'll make some calls.
Air plane?
Listen, wrongdoers are nocturnal.
Apprehend all suspicious
cargo and check it!
I am determined to
capture these smugglers!
Stop!
Stop that vehicle.
Thank you for your hard work.
Excuse us, we are in a hurry.
Holmes?
Wait! Hey!
A new case?
Turn the coach around!
Be careful.
I'll pray for your success.
Well then, we're off.
The engine is in excellent condition.
It... It's high!
Are you okay, Watson?
If my calculation is correct,
our destination should be nearby.
That must be Waymer Island,
just like the map indicates.
W... Waymer Island
s... should have a lighthouse.
Let's find out.
Let's check with the
person running the lighthouse.
Do you work in the lighthouse?
Yes, my wife and I live
here alone, there's no one else.
Did anyone visit the island,
or have you seen anything unusual?
Nothing. It's been quiet
and no one's visited recently.
A balloon!
What brings you gentlemen here?
Well... actually...
We must be mistaken.
We'll look somewhere else.
What's wrong, Holmes?
Look over there.
A balloon!
Watson, hold on tightly!
That man's awkward
manner bothered me...
but then I saw the
balloon behind the lighthouse.
That's why I turned back.
So there must be
something going on there.
"My wife and I are alone"...
That man was lying.
Holmes, look up over there.
Is that your balloon?
Don't move!
If you had just gone back,
you might have saved yourselves.
Hey Mister! Run!
Shall we?
Quickly Watson!
This won't do, will it?
That's as far as you go.
Thanks for the...
Hurry up and walk!
It seems that
balloon letter was no trick.
Are they pirates? Or maybe...
In any case,
we have to get untied.
But what are they up to?
Listen carefully!
In regards to our plan...
our target, the cargo ship,
will proceed this way.
Then our decoy boat
will move this way.
When the lighthouse goes out...
the cargo boat
runs into the reef! Ka-boom!
And the cargo belongs to us.
By the way Professor, I'm not sure
we should keep those two alive.
Once the job is done we'll get rid
of them and the lighthouse family.
More importantly...
the decoy boat is ready, right?
It passed the tests perfectly.
All right then,
let's celebrate in advance!
Go for it!
Ya-ho!
Oh my...
We must not be caught
until we rescue the boy.
We'll have to go
through the window...
Great, we'll use that tree.
Where are you going?
The brat must have fallen off his bed.
Go and check on him.
Yes, sir.
Where is my dinner?!
Someone go check on it!
Yes, sir.
You're the famous "Sherlock Holmes"?
That hurt a bit.
We located you by deducing
where your green balloon came from.
Yeah, I knew you would come!
What's taking so long?!
The Professor is waiting!
Don't act stupid!
Remember, your brat
and husband are captives!
Smugglers?
Yeah, they do whatever,
smuggling or pirating.
Smugglers...
Jack, we'll do all we
can to rescue your parents.
You said you like chemistry, right?
Yeah, I filled the balloons with
hydrogen I generated in an experiment.
What kind of tools do you have?
Over here.
I asked my dad to buy them for me.
Impressive. I like chemistry, too.
But he always makes a big mess
conducting his weird experiments.
No chloroform or ether... hmm?
We can generate a sort of
knock-out gas by mixing these.
Will you help me?
Professor!
Here she comes,
like a moth to a flame.
Everyone, no slip ups!
Hey, lighthouse keeper.
Obey our orders, or you'll never
see your wife or kid again, got it?
We did it!
Jack, fill the balloons with gas.
Jack, now!
What do you think you're doing, brat?
Yeah! Complete success!
Holmes, look.
Hurry up!
Moriarty!
I see. He's the mastermind
of this smuggling gang.
They're leaving.
What's with that tugboat?
Please, hurry and save my husband!
My dad is locked up in the lighthouse!
They are planning to
loot cargo from that ship!
Hurry or my husband
will be an accomplice!
Watson, take care of them.
I'm coming with you!
Hurry up and turn off that light!
What are they doing?!
If they don't hurry and turn it off!
Did you forget your
wife and brat are at stake?!
What are you doing to my dad?!
Jack!
Don't move!
Hurry and turn off the light.
If not, we throw
your brat into the ocean.
You, coward!
J... Jack...
Dad, don't listen to him!
Hurry up or I'll!
Oh, the light went out.
The light went out!
What? What the?!
Captain! We've lost
sight of the lighthouse!
That's ridiculous! Look sharp!
Turn on the decoy!
Yes, sir!
Come on! Hurry up!
Oh! It's all the way over there!
This is bad! At this rate we'll crash!
There are lots of reefs around here!
Hard right rudder!
As expected, they're
changing their course.
Look out! You're
headed for the reefs!
Keep quiet!
What are you doing
to my dad, you!
The brat!
Captain! Another
lighthouse has appeared!!
What is going on?! Hard left rudder!
What happened?!
Yeah, they made it!
You won't get away.
Release the decoy lighthouse!
You there, get on board!
You won't get away this time!
Drat! Run for it!
They came back for us!
Get out of the way!
You can't run any more!
We're gonna crash!
Retreat, Todd, Smiley!
I knew someone would find
my balloon and come to rescue us.
Really, it's all thanks to you.
I didn't know that Waymer
Island was also Dolphin Island.
I called it that in case those
bad guys picked up the balloon.
Pretty cool, huh?
Indeed. Very cool.
Well then, Jack, so long.
Goodbye.
Goodbye!
Mr. Holmes, please
visit us again sometime!
Not yet. You still
can't catch me Lestrade.
Moriarty, I'm going to catch you.
Inspector Lestrade, I'll send
you a rescue ship right away!
Forward! Keep going Todd, Smiley!
What are you doing?!
Hurry! Stroke! Stroke! Stroke!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
A golden statue of an angel was
stolen by Professor Moriarty.
Holmes begins his investigation as
seven tiny faces appear before him.
Holmes and the boys
start an adventure...
to recover the statue
from an abandoned boat.
If you ever find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Great Chase
of the Little Detectives