FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Air Battle Over Dover
What a beautiful day!
She's the most beautiful
flower in the garden.
Good morning, Mrs. Hudson!
Good morning!
I'll get breakfast ready right away.
Please take your time.
I'd like it soon, Watson.
I'm really starving.
You're already up, Holmes.
I'm up...
Oh?
It crashed!
Let's go.
W... What?!
Help!
Mrs. Hudson!
Catch him!
The gasoline is about to explode!
Oh, yes!
Oops!
Mary, get the mail bag!
Mary?!
Catch this!
Sure.
Get out of here!
Wow, that was close.
I knew it was you, Mary.
I've been looking for you.
Mary!
Mrs. Hudson.
Burn, burn it all up.
You're awake?
Mary.
How about some water?
Brandy?
- Mary, something cold?
- Something warm?
Could you please leave me alone?
Oh?
Yes.
- Very well.
- Bye then.
Please call us if you need anything.
Yes.
Ah, Mary...
Ouch!
Be patient!
How dare you be so casual,
calling her "Mary"!
Explain yourself!
Well, Mr. And Mrs. Hudson
and I were flying mates.
Flying mates?!
Her husband, Jim was a nice young
man studying air plane design.
Everyone was in love with her.
When Jim won her heart...
we were all heartbroken.
I don't blame you.
But within a month
of their marriage...
It was a horrible accident...
After the accident,
she disappeared from us.
So, the accident this morning
brought back the bad memories.
But thanks to her efforts,
the mail didn't get burned.
It's the airmail flight, just opened
between London and Paris.
But we've yet to make
a single delivery.
Even though the commemorative
stamps were issued.
I heard that there's been
a series of accidents.
We always keep the planes
in good working condition.
But on the day of the flight,
the planes break down.
At this rate, the postal business
itself may be discontinued.
I'll return to the airport
and try again tomorrow.
Thanks for everything.
Bye now!
I wonder if someone's
interfering with those flights?
Perhaps.
Look at this, Watson.
The fuel pipe has a crack.
A metal rasp was used.
Then someone's
definitely interfering.
Mrs. Hudson.
Well...
I know.
I'll take you to the airport.
Thank you.
Hey, hey, do you want to race?!
Oh, Honourable Count,
it's been a long time.
Oh, it's you, Mary!
I've missed you.
You haven't changed a bit.
This highway looks sad without you.
That shabby looking machine
doesn't suit you, Mary.
Just let me know,
I'll lend you my car any time!
What's shabby?!
You old speed freak!
It's Mary!
Hey, Mary's back!
Mary, how have you been?!
You all look great.
Step down, step down.
Make room for Mary!
Hey, don't push!
She's really popular.
But I can't blame them.
Indeed.
Oh, thanks for this morning.
You're going to fly this tomorrow?
Yeah, it's the only one left.
This old plane's really beat-up.
It's been well cared for.
Oh Mary! You're here, too!
Mary!
Mary, Mary...
He's so excited, will he
be able to fly tomorrow?
For the time being,
let's finish the inspection.
Professor!
What are you fussing about?
Holmes! Holmes!
What?
Holmes already caught wind of us?
Another fish from
that river back there?
What will you do, Professor?
Who cares where
the fish comes from?!
Back river or not, it's all protein!
No, I mean about Holmes.
I wanna eat meat...
Be patient.
I'll feed you meat, eggs or whatever
you want soon enough.
You spent all your money
on those commemorative stamps.
Are you sure they'll
become valuable soon?
If we stop tomorrow's flight,
the airmail business will cease.
When that happens, the airmail stamps
will stop being issued.
In no time, stamp collectors
will come for my stamps.
I can name any price I want!
So today, I will say goodbye
to these fish.
I hope it works.
Lately the odds...
Shut up!
My plan is perfect!
Stop yapping!
Go to the river
and fish for my supper!
Yes, Sir! Yes, Sir!
I won't lose to someone like Holmes!
Ah, where did it go?
Well.
Mrs. Hudson will be back tomorrow.
Tonight, we'll keep eye on the plane.
Help!
W... What's that?!
Help! Stay away!
Come here! Come here!
Mrs. Hudson's in danger!
Shall we begin?
Yes, Sir.
Mary, good morning!
Tommy, did you see Mr. Holmes
and Mr. Watson?
They told me they would keep
an eye on the plane all night.
But I haven't seen
them this morning.
Maybe they're having breakfast.
Did you sleep well, Holmes?
Thanks to you.
That's good.
We had tons of work to do.
We've worked throughout the night.
You did something with the plane?!
We did a little more this time.
Exciting!
What a cliché, using nitroglycerine.
Call it being artistic and reliable.
The postal plane is in danger.
Right.
Please postpone your flight!
I can't!
The future of airmail
depends on this flight!
But Mr. Holmes and
Mr. Watson are not here!
That means something's wrong!
Don't worry!
The engine's running great!
It's on its way!
They're not even aware.
That's the last airmail flight.
Hot! Hot! Hot!
I'll be cooked before
that rope comes off.
Hot! Hot! Hot!
Just hold on.
I can't...
Did you hear something?
Wait!
Oh, whatever!
It's too late!
Give me back my bike!
Mr. Holmes!
Stop! Stop right there!
Come back down!
He can't hear me over the engine.
Here goes!
What?!
What are you doing?!
Let go!
There's a bomb on your plane!
Holmes!
Mr. Watson!
The postal plane's in danger.
Oh no!
Let's witness the end of Holmes!
Professor!
He's the culprit!
Hello, Mrs. Hudson!
See you later!
Mary!
It's terrible!
There's nitroglycerine on the plane.
What?!
Catch that plane!
Right!
Start the engine.
Moriarty did this.
Stop, stop, wait!
Let's go!
Mrs. Hudson.
Let me borrow your car.
Sure.
Hold on tight.
Wow, here comes Mary!
Just like old times!
Let's help her!
Mrs. Hudson.
Don't talk!
You'll bite your tongue!
Cool!
Follow her.
We're not so cool.
Nitroglycerine?!
I can't even make
an emergency landing?!
Keep the plane steady.
I'll look for the nitroglycerine.
They must've done a lot
of sabotage to this plane.
Do you have something like wire?!
I have this for emergency repair!
But I can't take my hands off!
Throw it to me.
Here.
He showed up.
This is great entertainment.
He's desperately trying to repair it.
It's the last desperate struggle
of Detective Holmes.
Keep struggling in despair!
Oh no, here, too!
Come on!
The game's over!
It's going to explode!
See...
Boom?!
They're still flying.
What's the hold up?
Well it seems he's repaired
it for the most part.
Hey, stop struggling
and start crashing, Holmes!
Yes, we will after I find
the nitroglycerine.
Hey, I know where it's hidden!
Hey you!
But he'll get mad if I tell you!
I see them!
Thank Goodness!
They're still flying.
Hey, w... what's wrong?
We're out of gas!
What?!
Mary!
The old speed freak again.
Honourable Count, could you please
let me borrow your car.
Wow, what an irresistible line!
Be my guest!
I don't even care if you wreck it!
Wait!
Go!
Yeah, dynamic!
Yahoo!
Haven't you found it yet?!
Since it's not in the body,
it must be somewhere in the wings.
Oh no, he's checking the wings!
I'm positive he can't find it.
Oh, he's close! He's close!
Found it!
It's in the wing!
Bingo!
Smarty Holmes!
I'm giving up on this perfect crime!
Now I'm moving onto brute force!
Start!
What's he up to?!
He's trying to rip us
apart with the anchor.
He's coming!
Where is the nitroglycerine?!
Almost there!
Oh, my!
Okay, once more!
You're not so bad yourself.
It's coming again!
Oops!
What's this?
Here, once more!
What is this?!
I don't think you
can kick it with bare feet.
Here it comes.
Keep on pulling!
No good!
It's going to come
apart in mid-air!
Give me the pistol!
What?!
Hurry, give me the pistol!
Oh, yes, certainly.
Take the wheel.
All right!
What?! What's happened?
Mrs. Hudson, stop!
Stop it!
That's dangerous!
It can't be!
It can be.
It's nitroglycerine!
Drop it! Quickly!
See you again, Mr. Holmes!
Jump onto the bag, quickly!
I'll do as you say.
Look out!
It's the Dover!
This is the end of airmail flight.
I don't think so.
We found out who the culprit was.
It hasn't undervalued the planes.
What a thrill that was, Mary!
Are you all right?!
Mary!
No! Don't!
Hip hip hooray!
Now, we're having
fish from the park.
Don't be sarcastic.
I'll feed you tons of meat someday.
Hey!
Commemorative stamps for the
subway opening will be issued!
Brother...
We'll be eating fish from
the park for a while.
Today, they had the first airmail
flight after the grand reopening.
I see.
It's flying up there.
You're right, it's flying.
Indeed it is.
I'm glad.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Upon the request for an investigation
by the wealthy Mr. Gilmore...
Holmes and I visit a valley
filled with his factories.
We challenge the mystery of his
disappearing sovereign gold coins.
All the while being disgusted by
Mr. Gilmore's vulgar opulence.
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Targeted Giant Coin Bank