My name is Watson.
I'm a medical doctor.
I met a person who claims
to be a detective.
On board a ferry crossing
the Straits of Dover...
His name is Sherlock Holmes.
Soon after I met him,
we were involved in a mystery...
about 4 signatures approaching
from the fog.
The famous detective, Holmes.
He's the Famous Detective
Please look forward to seeing him.
FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
He's the Famous Detective
Well, well.
20 more miles to Currie.
What was that about?!
So they want to get in my way.
That was close.
What?
Oops!
This is really heavy.
Be careful!!
Come on! Bring it down!!
A little bit more!
Ah, this sea breeze feels good.
That family is...
That man...
with the heavy looking trunk
and the little medical bag...
he must be a doctor.
Oh, thank you.
No problem.
Let's play more!
Wait for me!
Hey, I'm hungry!
There you go.
I'm a doctor.
If he gets hurt,
just bring him over.
Thank you!
Oh, well.
What a thick fog.
Hey, wait!
Hi! Sorry I surprised you.
I'm Dr. Watson, and you?
Holmes... Sherlock Holmes.
I'm a private detective.
Oh, are you really?
You must have had quite a few dangerous
experiences in your line of work.
I was working as an
army surgeon in Afghanistan.
A hard time there, really.
I suppose it requires a wide range of
knowledge to work as a detective.
Of course.
I'm an expert in botany,
chemistry and physics.
And I like to play violin very much.
Oh...
What is it?
I remember seeing a symbol
just like that when I was in India.
I got it! It's Bengal's...
Yes, it's a symbol
of the Bengal Pirates.
Don't you find this a little odd?
Odd?
This is the Straits of Dover,
4000 miles from the Indian Ocean.
What do you suppose the Bengal Pirates
are doing all the way over here?
It's them! It's them!
They followed me here!
Papa!
There is nothing to fear.
Please open the door.
Who are you?
I'm Sherlock Holmes.
I'm pretty sure that I can help you.
Well... what are you?!
I'm a private detective.
A private detective?
The people chasing after
you are Bengal Pirates.
And what they're looking for
is hidden inside your pocket.
That black box...
And perhaps, your life?
Father!
Excuse me!
Doctor!
It's an emergency!
His heart has been weakened,
but I don't think it's serious.
Thank goodness.
We really wanted to have some help.
Barbara!
Since my father got that letter,
he's been very nervous and frightened.
It has been six months
since we left on this trip.
Do you know any of these four names?
Just one.
It was the name my father
used when he was young.
He was a Bengal Pirate,
a long time ago.
I thought so.
The other three people
were his associates.
And...
now they're chasing him.
Yes.
This is a shark's tooth.
The Bengal Pirates have a custom
of sending a shark's tooth...
to announce the
death mark of a traitor.
So, the pirate ship is here to take
revenge on Lord George?
Full speed ahead!
Engineer! Stoke more coals!!
Aye! Aye!
There!
Good!
In you go.
There!
God!
They'll show no mercy!
Now that they've targeted this ship...
There are many
passengers on this ship.
We can't get them involved
just because of you.
At the same time,
we'd like to help you both.
Therefore, please fully explain
the little box in your pocket.
Very well.
I guess you already know everything.
I took this box when I betrayed and
escaped from my three compatriots.
This is what they are trying to get,
in addition to my life.
Full speed ahead!
They can't catch up with us
if we run this ship at full speed.
It's done.
What's wrong with the engine room?!
Stoke more coal!
T... This?!
Did they do this?!
Smiley! Are you rowing?
I'm rowing brother!
I assume those two people
stopped the engine.
Then are they pirates, too?
I'll give this back to you now.
Well, Mr. Watson, I need your help.
Yes, but what do
you want me to do?
I want you to collect
small and shiny objects.
All right.
Will it take long to repair?
Yes. They completely destroyed it.
I can stall for a little while,
but please hurry!
Uh, sure.
Here mister.
Here.
Ah, thank you.
How is it going? Did you get enough?
Yes, quite a lot.
Thank you everyone.
We did it.
Stop!
If you move any closer, I will throw
these jewels into the ocean!
Can you hear me? I'm not lying!
Do you want me to throw any more?
Will it take much longer?
I'm helping, but
it will take more time.
W... wait!
I understand!
If you hand over Lord George and the
treasure, we won't harm anyone!
Still not finished?
I'll take it!
What are you going to do?!
Are you giving us
the treasure or not?!
Understood! I'll give it to you now!
Watson, what's taking you so long?
It's done! It's done!
Let's go!
That was close!
It's still too early to celebrate.
We have yet to find a way of escape.
I assume you can lend
me a hand, Mr. Watson.
Of course.
My, this is a great motorcar!
I brought Lord George.
Hang a rope ladder!
Show us the treasure!
Great, do it now!
Here goes!
They tricked us!
Don't let them go!
Here they come!
Mr. Watson, please take care
of the accelerator!
Now comes the real fight.
I believe it was around here.
Good.
Good! We can escape.
We did it!
What?!
Damn! It's a dead end!
Here!
Shift your weight slowly,
all the way to the front.
Well, if I must...
I got it.
Looks like this is the end.
So it seems.
Watson.
Holmes.
That's it!
The British Navy!
I guess they finally
got through to them.
Oh, it's Inspector Lestrade
of Scotland Yard.
That's it! That's it!
Go! Go!
Capture everybody for
the honour of Scotland Yard!
Smiley, row harder!
Brother, I can't!
I guess they're here to pick us up.
Mr. Holmes! Mr. Watson!
Let's shake hands again.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
English subtitled version produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
I moved into Holmes' boarding
house on Baker street.
Before I had time to meet the beautiful
boarding house owner, Mrs. Hudson...
I got involved with a case.
The famous Crown of Mazalin
was stolen.
The shadow behind this crime is
that evil genius, Professor Moriarty.
Whenever you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Evil Genius, Professor Moriarty