FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Did You See the Big Shining Thief?
Get out of the way!
Out of the way!
One million?!
One million pounds worth
of English gold bullion!
This should never have happened.
No matter what...
No matter what,
I want you to arrest the thief!
Please! Inspector Lestrade.
All right!
Leave this matter to me!
You can see for yourself.
This is the work of a professional.
They didn't even touch the cash,
only the heavy gold bullion.
I checked before I left last
night, the gold bullion was here!
How could they move one million pounds
worth of gold bullion, so quickly?
Inspector! Inspector, please!
Inspector!
My job will be in jeopardy
if you don't arrest the thief!
Please take care of this!
All right. All right.
Just relax and wait for the solution.
Yes.
Everybody, let's begin
a thorough investigation!
Yes.
I really appreciate this.
Can't find anything unusual.
Not even one piece of broken glass.
No evidence that it was
carried out through the windows.
Inspector, can you find the thief?
Leave everything to me!
Why don't you eat while it's still hot,
otherwise it won't be tasty.
Yes.
I'm sorry I have a bad habit.
Mr. Holmes, it seems like something
has been bothering you recently.
It's already been a week...
but the London Police's investigation
hasn't been progressing well at all.
Since then?
You know that the bank's
safe was recently broken into.
In the newspaper, Inspector Lestrade
declared that the case was simple...
but he still hasn't found any clues.
The only thing they're doing
is making me frustrated.
Unless we get involved, this
case will never be solved, Holmes.
If they're really having a hard time,
the Inspector will come to us.
Why are you so easy going?
It's one million pounds
worth of gold bullion!
Wait a second.
Mr. Perison is still missing.
Perison?
He's a popular sculptor.
He has won a lot of awards because
of his unique creative style.
I'm talking about
the stolen gold bullion!
The day Mr. Perison disappeared was the
day after the gold bullion was stolen.
Don't you think it's related to this?
A thief steals a large amount
of gold bullion...
and a skilled sculptor goes missing.
I see! The thief is planning
to coin fake money!
I've never heard of anyone making
fake money from real gold.
Then how are they connected?
This has become an interesting case!
Do you want to come with me?
Of course!
That's the spirit, Holmes!
Excuse me, but what about dinner?
We'll eat that later!
Hey, that's not nice!
So your husband, Mr. Perison...
after leaving with his
painting materials...
has failed to return for three days?
Yes, he said he was supposed to paint
a portrait of the American millionaire...
Mr. Sallinger.
Holmes, look at this.
Those are the sketches
he was drawing.
It looks like he was
trying to sculpt a bird.
He said he didn't like those sketches,
so he left with our son to redo them.
Your son went with him?
Yes, he said he'd be back shortly
and left with our son, Copit.
But, they haven't returned.
If his son is with him...
this might be trouble.
But if this is the only clue...
Watson, did you notice that the person
in the sketchbook looks familiar?
Huh? Looks familiar?
It can't be!
Mr. Holmes, I was actually thinking
about visiting you today.
Can you show me the fastest way to the
underground safe from the back door?
Uh? Yes, I can.
I can see a lot of scratches on the wall.
Yes, Inspector Lestrade
ordered us to leave them.
What's this hook for?
Inspector Lestrade experimented with
ways to carry out the gold bullion.
It took the same amount of time from
the back door as it did from the front.
If you wanted to carry one million
pounds worth of gold bullion...
you couldn't do it in one night.
This is the way to the safe.
The lock on this
door was broken, too.
Yes, it's already been fixed.
It was like this at the front entrance.
Look at this!
Only the gold bullion is gone!
Did Inspector Lestrade
investigate this room?
No, Inspector Lestrade's investigation
was for the most part outside.
Did you find something?
There are marks indicating
that somebody moved the shelf.
Then there is an entrance
behind this shelf?
That can't be!
This room is surrounded
by a thick brick wall.
May I move this?
Yes, you may.
Don't just stand there watching us.
Give us a hand.
Sure.
It's a wall.
What's wrong, Holmes?
The wall is!
What about the gold bullion?
They dug this entrance.
If they used this entrance, they
shouldn't have had to break the lock.
They might have done
this to trick the police.
Excuse me, but can you get
the gold bullion back?
Otherwise, my job will be...
I don't think they could've carried
the gold through this shabby tunnel.
It looks like it's about to collapse.
I can't see anything.
Ouch!
There's light.
What?
What kind place is this?
I think it connects to the river.
Wait!
I don't like this place!
This is a caterpillar tread.
It continues all the way.
Let's follow this.
This case is getting smelly,
isn't it Holmes?
We're getting close to the exit.
I can hear the sound of water
going into the river.
Are we going to travel
along with sewage?
Well, it hardly matters,
I'm already dirty.
This is not good!
Here, let's hurry!
Well. Well.
If they carried it off by boat from
here, there's no way to trace them.
But what if it could run on the ground,
and then become a ship on the water?
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about an amphibious vehicle.
An amphibious vehicle?
It seems we're going to have
a lot of heavy work on this case.
All right. Let's go.
Watson, I found it!
Over here!
Over here.
What does it mean?
All that remains are the tread marks
of a caterpillar.
I think the thief probably...
I see. This is a complicated caper.
It must be the work of Moriarty.
If we follow along the river,
we can trace him.
What?
We're going to walk along
the river under water?
Did you find something, Holmes?
They must have gotten out here.
This is?
There's no mistaking it.
This is the mansion of the famous
antique art dealer, Mr. Richard Molly.
What does it all mean?
If caterpillar treads were the
way the gold bullion was carried off...
strange, isn't it?
I remember that Mr. Molly died
suddenly in India ten years ago.
Ten years ago?
I heard that his son was with him
at the time and is still missing.
Then who lives in this mansion?
Oh, were you both customers
of my late husband?
I thought it might be rude to just
drop in on you like this...
but we were in the neighbourhood.
Oh, not at all.
It brings back memories
of my husband.
Let's discuss and remember
my husband after such a long time.
Here, please come in.
Thank you.
I can certainly see he was an antique
art dealer who travelled the world.
These are all very rare.
Please don't trouble yourself.
Help yourself.
Excuse me, but do you
have poor eyesight?
Yes, but it's good to live a long life.
He came back.
I'd almost given up on him.
It was all of the sudden.
Came back?
Who?
My only son, who was missing.
Your son?
He's really grown up.
He even said he would
stay here forever.
That sounds great.
Is he here now?
Yes, he is trying to finish his
respected father's statue.
He is hard at work in the shop.
Statue?
Yes, it's a statue made of fine gold.
What? A gold statue?
I'll bring him here.
Why don't you talk to him?
Oh, you don't have to rush.
We will visit the shop later.
I'd like to talk more
about your husband.
Yes indeed.
Excuse me, but I'd like
to call my friend.
Yes, of course.
Rats!
I'm running around everyday,
even checking out rat nests!
But, it turned out to be
just a waste of effort!
Where did they go?!
Inspector!
What?
This had better be good.
You've got a message from Holmes.
The message said it's good news.
What?! A message from Holmes?!
Yes.
Fool!
Why didn't you say
so in the first place?!
Well, I was...
You were what?!
It's the building over there.
Here, come this way.
Perhaps you could wait here?
Oh, why?
Please just wait here.
That's strange.
Why can't I go into my son's shop?
If it's all right with you,
I'll explain later.
How is it?
It looks a little complicated.
Hey! Don't stop working!
The gold is going to harden!
Hurry!
If you love your son,
finish it as soon as possible.
The genius thief Moriarty's
once-in-a-lifetime achievement.
A golden statue to show my glory
to all of my descendants.
Papa, don't listen to those guys!
Scream! Say whatever!
The genius sculptor will
make my golden statue!
We can't do anything
unless we get Copit out first.
Can I take care of that?
I'm excited, I haven't
done this for a while.
Can you take the roof?
All right.
Here we go.
Almost completed.
You guys! Don't cut corners!
Work harder!
Yes!
Copit!
I'll help you. Just be quiet.
Yes.
Listen, you have to hide
somewhere quietly.
Don't be mean to my Papa!
I won't allow it!
This is bad.
Damn it! They found us!
Todd, Smiley! Get him!
Yes!
Yes, yes!
Moriarty, just give it up?!
You finally showed up, Holmes.
Beat him up first!
Yes!
Drat!
He always uses us so harshly.
Do you think that will
help you get away?
Come on then!
Oh, so you've got some guts.
Let's fight!
Oh, he is strong!
You!
All right!
At least, I can carry the gold bullion
out while they're fighting.
I'll take care of him.
Drat! My precious gold bullion!
Brat! Did you do that?!
I have to pick up the gold first.
Papa, aren't I strong?
Copit, you are great!
All right!
Now, it's my turn.
Hey!
Mr. Perison!
Papa!
All right!
Take this!
And this!
Oops.
Out of the way!
Open... sesame!
- Wait!
- Professor!
Wait!
Copit!
Copit, watch out! Get off!
Copit, get off!
He is just an annoying brat!
Hey, your papa's calling you!
That's it! After them!
After them!
Turn about!
That's it! That's the gold bullion!
Grab it!
Here we go!
They're riding on my gold statue.
Let it go! Don't touch my gold!
You think I'd let it go!
You bums!
Don't touch my gold statue!
Dolts! Take your hands off!
The gold!
Down! Down!
All of it down!
Drat!
All that's left is my gold statue.
Can't breathe!
Curse you Lestrade!
You took my gold statue!
If you want it, come down here!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
A two tailed snake...
three lumps, and...
two shiny eyes...
The seven hieroglyphs.
What do they represent?
Holmes pursues the mystery of
the Wizard Sword of Saint Cross...
in a dead heat
with Professor Moriarty.
But where is the treasure?
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Magic Castle!
Holmes, Dead or Alive?