FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Chase the Airship, White Silver!
Inspector, this is the last one.
Please make sure this is protected.
I'm the one who will be guarding this.
Leave this matter to me.
Uh?! What's that smell?!
Let's go!
Oh, the horse wagon is...
Wait!
Damn!
Giddy-up!
Idiots! Follow them!
Hurry up and follow them!
Let's go!
Wait a minute!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
You fool! Don't follow me!
Follow the horse!
Drat! Curse you Moriarty!
I'll be sure to get you!
Extra! Extra!
If you don't buy this now,
it will sell out quickly!
Hey! Can I have one?
Thank you.
Oops!
How's the White Silver doing?
She's nearly ready
for her maiden voyage.
It's the biggest airship in England
made by the Gingham Company.
Everybody in England is very
excited about this.
Of course I'm looking
forward to it, myself.
Moriarty and his gang stole a bag
containing £7000 from the Royal Bank.
But the police haven't
been able to trace them.
Drat! Moriarty did it again.
I can imagine Inspector Lestrade
must be very eager to find them now.
Hey, it looks bad.
It seems like it will be very
difficult to get out of here.
How do you plan to get all of
this treasure out of here?
Professor?
Professor?!
Drat!
Stupid newspaper!
Why don't they write about
my tremendous achievement!
Isn't my achievement far greater!?
They have wasted my effort.
I had even prepared
specially ordered fireworks.
You're right!
We succeeded this time,
and that's very rare.
Yes, yes!
Shut up!
So now we will follow my original plan.
We have to break through
the police's dragnet...
so let's surprise them.
Listen!
Moriarty and his henchmen
must still be in London!
We have closed off all of the
routes heading out of London.
Don't even let baby ants go through!
Yes, sir!
Moriarty, I'll be sure to arrest you!
Here, one more!
All right!
This is the last one!
OK!
Professor! We're finished!
All right!
Do you know where
we're supposed to meet?
Yes, but is this going to be
as successful as we have planned?
You fool! My plan will not fail!
Just go quickly!
All right!
Drat!
They never shut their mouths!
Well, the day of the voyage
has come at last.
Everyone in the country
is looking forward to this.
We are also very excited about it.
Thank you very much.
By the way, there's
something troubling me.
That's why I invited you both here today.
I needed to talk to the famous detective.
What's troubling you?
I hope this is just a coincidence,
but a few days ago...
some sketches for
the Airship White Silver...
and a copy of the flight plan
for her maiden voyage...
went missing from this office.
What?
Was it stolen?
Well, there's no proof of that.
Because, the designs and other
important documents are still here.
I didn't call the police, because
I don't want to cause a scene.
Has anything strange
happened to the airship?
Everything is all right so far.
I really want to make tomorrow's
maiden voyage safe and successful!
Of course.
Everybody in the country
is hoping for that.
I would be happy to help you.
Oh, thank you very much.
Well, president, as long as
Mr. Holmes is involved...
you don't have to worry.
Some sketches and the flight plan...
...a rival company's spy
might have stolen it.
Then why are the designs and the
important documents still there?
They would've wanted
those more, wouldn't they?
Here is the storage room.
Oh, this is great.
It's much bigger
than the photograph.
The total length is 120 meters.
It's really big.
What are those bags
they are loading?
Oh, that's ballast.
There is sand and water inside them...
and they adjust the
balance for the ship to float.
Really.
I see.
Excuse me.
We have to load this.
Oh, you guys are working hard here.
He's an easygoing man.
Here we go!
Oh, thank you.
Excuse me.
Mr. Holmes!
How was everything?
Did you find anything strange?
I investigated thoroughly last night,
but there were no bombs or anything.
B... bombs?!
No way! It can be!
I'm just pointing out the
worst case scenario.
But you don't have to worry.
Watson and I will also board this
airship and assure its safety.
Welcome.
Welcome. Welcome.
Please.
Oh, Minister of State, thank you for
coming during your busy schedule.
For the glory of our country, I've
been looking forward to this trip.
Famous businessmen and politicians...
there are so many important faces.
If something bad should happen,
it would be quite serious.
Yes.
Oh, it looks like they
are starting to take off.
Let's hurry, Watson.
Oh, yes.
I guess they made it.
Everything went just as I planned.
Now...
Ouch!
This is gorgeous.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for waiting!
We prepared a party to celebrate
today's maiden flight.
Please come this way.
Oh, that sounds nice.
Well, let's go over there.
Oh, this is a really great view.
Thank you very much.
I like this airship,
because it's so quiet.
Thank you very much.
I'm honoured to hear that.
Excuse me, have you seen Mr. Holmes?
No, I haven't seen him at all.
I see.
Over the wall!
Here we go!
It's Moriarty! Don't let him go!
The train for Liverpool
is now departing!
There he is!
Get him!
Yes sir!
Hey you!
Wait Moriarty!
Where did you stash the money?!
I always admire your
enthusiasm for your job...
but this is the end of it.
Here!
Damn you!
Stop it!
Here you are! Oops!
Damn! I can't stand it!
What is that?
This is really gorgeous!
Hey, Holmes!
Are you sure you checked
everywhere inside this airship?
Well, briefly.
Briefly?
Isn't that a bit irresponsible?
You promised Mr. Gingham
this airship would be safe!
Oh, a bomb might not be the
only thing I'm looking for.
It's about time.
Yes, let's get ready.
Holmes... what are you looking for?
Watson, hurry up!
Those postures...
I think I've seen them before.
We found what we were looking for.
Come with me Watson.
H... hey! Holmes!
I'll never give up!
Let's go!
Get out of the way!
Help me!
Keep going!
What did you really find Holmes?
Don't say there's a bomb inside!
This is...
Those two you just saw
were Moriarty's henchmen.
Then these gold coins are the ones
they stole from the bank.
As for Moriarty's job, he did it well.
He was trying to use
the Airship White Silver...
to get through the police cordons.
Brother, can we really reach the
ballast through here?
If we don't hurry we're
going to run out of time.
Shut up!
Since you lost the floor plan,
We now have to end up doing this!
Stupid!
But!
Uh, what is this?
Hey, you're really heavy!
Wh... what is it?!
Gas must be leaking!
Throw the ballast away quickly!
Brother!
This is bad!
Hurry!
I'm sorry to have thrown the ballast
away without your permission.
Well, Mr. Holmes
you really are clever!
What?
By the way, I found some bags
with strange marks on them.
Let's throw them away too.
Oh, I didn't know you guys were here.
B... brother!
All right.
Excuse me.
Oh, no!
Stop! That train should stop now!
Moriarty! I won't let you escape!
They never give up!
A little more!
Inspector! Look ahead!
Swim!
It didn't work!
Nice going.
Now!
A genius scientist!
Behold, Moriarty's new invention!
Here. Here. Here. Here
Well, let's go!
10 points! Perfect score!
Just in time.
They will arrive soon.
Where are you planning
to meet Moriarty?
Tell us!
Captain.
What's the airship's present heading?
Well, we passed the Severn River
about 50 miles back.
I see.
This is London...
here's the Severn River...
and right now, we are around here.
We'll cross the railway here...
I see.
Oh, there they are.
Professor! I'm sorry!
Help us!
Stupid! Drop the money quickly!
I said drop it quickly!
Fools!
But we can't do that.
Holmes threw away the bags
that had the money inside of them.
What?!
Oops!
He threw them out?!
You are both idiots!
What were you doing?!
Moriarty!
Unfortunately, your plan
didn't work as usual.
Why don't you give up
and prepare to be arrested.
Curse you Holmes!
Don't expect me to
give up so quickly!
What are you doing?!
Go back there and get the money!
But professor...
If we jump from here, we will die!
All right! I'll take care of this.
I already prepared for this!
Pull up the gondola!
Hold on a minute Captain.
I don't think that will be necessary.
Listen, cut the rope when I say so!
Yes, yes!
Here we go!
One, two, three!
Cut!
Oops!
There they are! Get them!
Yes!
They came down! Hurry!
What?!
What is going on?!
They are inside the cabin!
Arrest them!
There we go!!
So long! Mr. Lestrade!
Here we go!
Curse you Moriarty!
He's doing it again!
I'll never let you go!
Follow me!
Yes!
Return my pigs!
Move out of my way!
They're back again!
Thank you for everything.
It brings honour
to the Airship White Silver...
because it helped to
expose the criminals.
But I wonder...
how could you tell the difference
between the ballast and gold coins.
Oh, as soon as I picked those up,
I could tell because of the weight.
And there was also those strange
markings on the bags.
It's... because of both of you...
that the maiden flight
finished safely.
I would like to thank you both.
We are about to arrive at the airport.
Wait!
Who wants to wait!?
Stop!
Who wants to stop!?
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Red roses and a crime letter
were left in a jewellery store.
Could this be
Professor Moriarty again?
As it turns out he
was completely innocent.
The professor stakes his pride on
stealing the famous Royal Horse...
and begins to organize his plan.
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street
Buzz Buzz!
The Fly Fly Mecha Operation!