FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Game of Wits,
Parrot vs. Professor!
How wonderful it feels when
a case is settled so quickly.
I did say it would be a
piece of cake for you.
Smoky!
What's this?
Well...
Smoky!
Oh, excuse us Mr. Parrot.
That's quite a unique
parrot you've got there.
We didn't mean any...
What was that?
I guess he felt we might
try to take his parrot.
It must be very important to him.
But still...
What is that?!
It's going to run into us!
Don't!
Somebody help!
Look!
What's that!?
You're doing great! Keep it up!
You may not want to cut loose with
one of the Professor's machines.
See, I told you.
What is that thing?!
What's going on?!
Dragon?
Yah-hoo!
Yee-ha!
It's coming right at us!
What's going on?!
Excellent.
It appears to be
the work of Moriarty.
What's he up to this time?
All right.
He's just fainted
Don't worry.
They were after the birdcage.
A man suddenly jumped
on board the train...
struck a blow then disappeared!
I wonder how valuable that parrot is.
I am Sherlock Holmes.
I promise to keep this quiet.
I say!
Please contact me when
you're ready for my help.
I am Holmes.
Oh, I see you two were on board.
I flew over as soon
as I received the news.
So, where's the monster?
It flew away with the stolen parrot.
Parrot? What parrot?
Gone, with the flying machine.
And the primary suspect is...
Moriarty!
Right, I'll get him this time,
no matter the cost.
Everyone, follow!
Well, well.
Still sleeping?
You must have been very tired.
I suppose I should
make a fresh pot later.
Yes, yes. I'm coming...
Ah, something...
This is comfortable.
Ah, here's the whole story.
I knew that parrot was valuable.
Would you read it to me.
It says the parrot was from India...
and whoever finds it will
receive a £1,000 reward.
The person who placed
the ad is named Harras.
And, the address is...
What? This address...
the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs?
I am Sherlock Holmes.
I've been expecting you.
So, his name is Mr. Khiviji.
Yes.
He is a wealthy merchant from India...
and he's been an important
patron of ours for some time.
Are you certain that
he's disappeared?
He left his room yesterday
and has not returned since.
This is the room.
Have you received a ransom note?
No, not yet.
But, it's not likely...
We can't say anything for certain, yet.
He loves to draw.
Those animals are all his work.
These are quite good.
He could easily go professional.
Is this the...
Then these two cases could be...
It's elementary, Watson.
They most certainly
relate to each other.
Thank you for waiting.
I am Harras, I placed the ad
in the newspaper.
You're the man from the train...
Please forgive my
rudeness the other day.
Although I knew who you were,
there were special circumstances...
This case involves our
country's greatest secret.
Greatest secret?
He just won't talk.
I don't know what
kind of secret he's got...
but I think it'd be
smarter to return the parrot...
and collect the
£1,000 reward.
Stupid!
Hey, you're mocking me!
You!
Ouch!
Stop that!
I am very sorry, birdie.
What are you doing
to this precious parrot!
Have you gotten anything
out of Khiviji yet?
Well, he's been pretty difficult...
You idiot!
Unless this man
tells us the password...
the parrot won't say anything
about the secret treasure.
A password...
I wonder what kind of treasure it is.
What?!
The case involves the
country's greatest secret?!
According to Mr. Harras' story,
the Maharajah of India...
who has maintained friendly
relations with England...
has entrusted a sensitive
governmental message to the parrot.
The Maharajah?
He was the king of India,
but I heard he was killed by rebels.
That's why Moriarty stole the parrot.
Moriarty, that thief...
So, what is the secret?
We don't know yet.
What's wrong?
These must be the parrot's feathers.
Feathers?
Why are they here?
The hoof prints
become disarrayed here.
They continue further on.
No, look at them more closely.
Each hoof print becomes
shallower from this point on.
Despite the fact that the character
of the ground remains constant...
the depth of the hoof prints changes.
We can deduce that the overall
weight of the horse changed here.
The horse became lighter
That means Moriarty got down
off the horse here, then?
Not down, up... he flew away.
Flew?
The flying machine,
operated by Todd...
picked up Moriarty at this point.
I see.
You're right.
I don't see Moriarty's footprints.
The parrot went wild in its cage...
panicked by the sight
of the flying dragon.
And that's when
his feathers fell out.
It also means the trail ends here.
It seems we've only
one means to capture them...
we will set an elaborate trap.
An elaborate trap?
Right.
Shut up!
We're busy right now!
All right!
Tickle, tickle, tickle...
How do you like that?
Ticklish, are you?
It's at maximum tickling!
I can't take it any more!
Brother, your being ticklish
doesn't do us any good.
Oh, that's true.
This guy's got nerves of steel.
Even at maximum tickling,
he hasn't even cracked a smile.
Ridiculous!
This is ridiculous!
Who the devil are you?!
What's wrong, Professor?
Read this!
What's it say?
Mr. Harras, of the Ministry
of Foreign Affairs...
is holding a grand reception in honour
of Mr. Khiviji's arrival in London...
Mr. Khiviji?
That's you!
Does that mean this man is a fake?
They invited celebrities, dignitaries,
made a huge production of this...
and they didn't think to invite me?
That means the Professor
isn't so important after all.
What did you say!
Security looks awfully tight,
doesn't it?
With this many guards,
the genuine one must be inside.
Let's go.
Pardon me, Sir.
Your invitation, please.
I must have left it home.
I'm afraid nobody
gets in without one.
Hold on a moment.
I suppose I'll have to go all
the way back home to get it.
I'm sorry to trouble you...
but would you mind
holding this for me?
And we'll hold you, too,
Professor Moriarty!
Curses! It's a trap!
Get those flowers out of here!
Blackout!
It's sleeping gas! Be careful!
Stop right there!
Come on, Holmes!
Hurry!
Yes.
Wait, I've seen him somewhere.
Something's wrong.
Todd, fix the engine!
But, we're still moving...
Get on with it!
They're catching up!
OK... OK...
Well...
Here we go.
Is it this one?
It's about time for
the Inspector to wake up.
Where am I?
Had a nice little nap, Mr. Khiviji?
Khiviji? What are you talking about?
Oh, you don't have
to play dumb any longer.
You're now under the thumb
of Professor Moriarty.
Moriarty?!
You've just kidnapped, of all people,
Inspector Lestrade of Scotland Yard!
This is unforgivable!
What's going on?!
What is Lestrade doing in my car?!
Prepare yourself!
Look out!
Thank you for rescuing me.
No trouble at all...
What am I doing?!
That's right.
You're under arrest!
Wait!
Hey!
No!
I said wait!
I'll arrest you today!
Got you!
Be careful.
Let go of me!
Not on your life!
Wait...
Don't let go, or I'll arrest you!
Wait a minute, I've already got him?
Let go!
I'll never let go!
Don't know anything...
W... w... w... w... wait!
Quickly! Let's get away!
Inspector!
Are you all right?!
Let's go!
He won't budge!
Humph.
As long as I've got this parrot,
the secret treasure is mine anyway.
Inspector...
Moriarty! This is unforgivable!
Charge!
What about Moriarty?!
The car!
Pull the car around!
Let's go!
Why you! Why you!
By hook or by crook!
Oops!
Inspector!
Moriarty escaped again
with the secret and the parrot!
No, he hasn't.
What?
We've got them right here.
As long as I've got this,
the secret is mine.
Ouch!
The message the Maharajah left was...
Ahar-hara-jita shari-guta.
"The Red Queen Carries Arms"
The Red Queen?
That's the name of a ship.
The Red Queen is the ship
loaded with armaments.
The rebels in India bought them
from English scoundrels.
Good heavens!
To arms, gentlemen!
I wonder what
that parrot's secret was.
It must have been for a mountain
of splendid Indian jewels...
or, perhaps a mountain of gold...
We'll get it for sure, next time!
Whatever.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
The city of London wakes up one
morning to a stunning crime.
The bell from the famous clock tower,
"Big Ben", has disappeared.
Holmes sets a trap for Professor Moriarty
by pretending the bell hasn't been stolen.
If you ever find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Listen! The Tribute to Moriarty