FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Treasure Under the Sea
An adventurer, Captain Raythunder,
discovered Napoleon's war chest...
sunken deep in the sea.
At present, he is returning to England
by ship, loaded with treasure.
Holmes, don't you agree
with me...
that Moriarty would go after
something like this?
No way that he would
miss something like this.
I have to replace this part...
What?
You're not listening.
Well, it's slow today.
What a surprise!
Inspector Lestrade is here.
Inspector, what's going on?
Holmes!
I can't work with you standing there.
It blocks my light.
Holmes, I don't want to be rough
on you. Just come along with us.
Huh?
Lieutenant, explain what we have here.
Yes, Sir.
Before that, do something
with those feet! It's impolite!
Holmes, he is the
Naval Fleet Commander.
Are you saying it is not impolite
to bring us over here...
against our will,
without even telling us why?
We will explain "why" to you now!
It was necessary to keep this
important matter confidential.
At least we could've told Mrs. Hudson
where you were taking us.
Mrs. Hudson? Who is that?
It's their landlady. She is a beauty.
Beauty? It's nothing!
We're talking about an
important national matter here!
You called Mrs. Hudson nothing!
Of course I did! It is nothing
compared to my problem!
My submarine was stolen!
Submarine?!
That's right. Submarine!
It's become the greatest
shame of the Navy.
Lieutenant, explain it.
Yes, Sir!
This is it.
This is our first naval submarine,
which we've been developing in secret.
It was almost completed. We were
just waiting for the launching ceremony.
One day, we had stew for lunch.
It was made with old meat.
The entire crew got food poisoning!
One week later,
when we resumed work...
Oh, it is empty inside!
At the time of this incident,
three of our cooks disappeared.
They seemed suspicious.
End of report!
Moriarty!
But why would he
steal something like that?
You call it "something like that?"!
It's our newest weapon!
Who called Mrs. Hudson "nothing"?!
You said it again!
Never repeat her name!
Will you shoot me then?
I'll show you!
You can't beat me!
So, Inspector, when did it happen?
A month ago. We need your help.
Our investigation reached a dead-end.
Look at the Commander. He's been
stressed out by the anxiety.
Please bring me newspapers
for the last month.
Are you going to undertake
the investigation, Holmes?
Look at this. Those spots with pins have
been robbed during the last month.
Lately, there's been a series of
robberies of ship materials...
engine parts, pipes and screws.
Is the robber trying
to build a submarine?
That's right.
They stole materials for the interior
and now they're building the exterior.
- Damn it!
- Where are they building it?
There are many factories
on the other side...
but only this area was targeted.
Why is that? Because they can't
cross the bridge.
They can't cross the Thames River
through the sewer.
Then, they are in the sewer!
They must be either inside
or around the exit.
- I'll catch them!
- Lieutenant! Prepare to cast off!
Yes, Sir!
- Cast off! - Ready the weapons!
- Stand by for orders! - Raise anchor!
Is that Commander going to start
a war on the Thames?
I don't know.
Let's get out of here.
What is it?
In order to keep this top-secret...
the Commander has ordered that you
stay here until everything is resolved!
Full speed ahead!
Get the contents of our submarine back!
They're hiding in there.
Report to the Commander!
Yes, Sir.
A signal from Lestrade.
"Found them."
"The enemy's ship is right below."
That's the face of a robber.
Stop the ship! Prepare to fire!
Yes, Sir.
Professor. Professor!
What?!
Look at that.
What a huge naval ship.
Take accurate aim at it!
They spotted us!
Charge!
Oops!
Hurry up!
The fake ceiling is falling on us!
Moriarty, don't even try to escape!
Hurry up! Prepare to submerge!
- You, thief! You're under arrest.
- Fill up the main tank!
Don't underestimate me.
You don't know how to give up.
Oh, no!
Tickle, tickle.
It's Lestrade!
He's sending hand signals.
Decode them.
They're on the run from us,
down below!!
We lost them!
Prepare to open fire!
I've got a treat for you.
Prepare for torpedo launch!
Aim at the periscope!
Fire!
They must be out of their minds!
Fire! Fire!
Keep on firing!
Let's get out of here!
It's getting really messy.
Launch torpedo!
Huh? What is that?
Commander, incoming torpedo!
What?!
That'll hit us.
Help!
We're sinking!
It's our newest weapon, all right.
Oh?! What's that?
Decode it.
Yes, Sir. B, L, E, A, H,
It's bleah!
They're on the run!
Watson, see, I told you to diet.
Hey, driver,
rush to Baker Street.
Are we going home?
Yes. What do you think
he stole that submarine for?
Oh, I got it! It's for the
treasure under the sea.
Right. He's planning to loot the ship
out there that's loaded with treasure.
Ready, pull!
Fools! A submarine doesn't
necessarily stay underwater.
Here we come.
The treasure is waiting for us!
Mrs. Hudson, please call
Inspector Lestrade.
Okay, be careful.
We'll be back by dinner.
I sure hope so.
That's the tread marks
of Moriarty's steam car.
It's going onto the street.
They headed south.
Thank you.
Sorry to bother you from up here.
The sea!
Watson, can you see that?
Yes.
They must've pulled the submarine
into the sea with that.
We should fly straight. Watson, keep
your eyes on the marine chart.
Roger, leave it to me.
Professor, are you sure there is a
treasure ship somewhere out here?
Cookie!
All right, all right.
Don't worry.
My calculations are perfect.
I hope so.
Don't you trust me, Goofball?
It's an airship. Yoo-hoo!
Yoo-hoo!
It's Holmes! Impossible!
Submerge quickly!
They've submerged.
But, we can see them very well.
How smart they are!
Captain Raythunder should be
somewhere in the area they're heading.
Raise periscope!
They're upon us!
Don't get excited, Watson.
Be serious!
They're trying to head us off!
Submerge quickly!
Yeah, okay!
Hurry up! No time for submerging!
Captain! Captain!
It's urgent, Captain!
What is it?
A suspicious airship
is approaching us.
An airship?
It must be those people
after my treasure.
Hey, is this
Captain Raythunder's ship?!
You've been targeted
by a submarine!
Change your course!
Fire on the count of three!
What?!
One!
- What did you say?!
- Two!
Three!
Fire!
Oh, boy!
Do you believe me now, hogs?!
Commander?!
Aren't you the Commander?!
I'm Raythunder.
The Fleet Commander
is my twin brother.
Twins!?
You've been running after
my treasure, haven't you?
We're speechless.
So, your brother's submarine
was stolen by Moriarty...
Don't lie through your teeth.
Admit that you're after my treasure.
Are you calling us thieves?
Then, you must be
private investigators.
There seems to be a pattern here.
Indubitably.
I knew it.
It's Holmes. This is perfect.
Prepare to launch torpedoes!
Ready.
Fire!
It's coming,
I knew it would come!
Captain, torpedo approaching!
What?!
Looks as though we'll be hit again.
We did it! Bullseye!
Let me see it!
Me, too!
I did it!
It'll sink! Get out of here!
This is tighter than before!
It's not good!
Shut the window quickly!
Oh no! The ship has broken off!
Our treasure!
Which one should we follow?
The aft, of course!
The Captain's room must be in there.
Moriarty's coming!
I'm getting it.
Oh, no!
It's open.
Oh, well.
It's you!
Did you think I'd let you
steal my treasure so easily?!
I won't allow it!
Listen you!
Enough already, we've got to hurry!
Watson, don't waste your time.
Look at his eyes.
This is my treasure! Nobody will
take it away from me!
Stop that! Watch out!
Enough!
- It's all mine!
- Let us help you see this clearly!
Stop that!
Put your hands up!
You're the guys who sunk my ship!
That's right!
Put your hands up.
Simpletons, I'll kill you all!
You!
Fools, don't let that weirdo in here!
Prepare to launch torpedo! Launch!
Oh my!
Watson, this is...
as I suspected.
What?!
The shock of the torpedo is
causing the ship to sink!
It's bottomless sea below us!
We'll be crushed by water pressure!
Hurry up! Take as much as you can!
Water's gushing out
of the launch tube!
- Mama!
- Close the hatch!
We'll pull away!
Even if they escape successfully...
they cannot hold their
breath to reach the surface.
Good bye, Holmes.
Ready? Let's go.
We give flowers to the soul of our
worthy opponent, Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
Since there's no florist around here,
I made flowers of toilet paper.
Rest in peace.
We did it! We did it! We did it!
Ooh!
Holmes!
What?!
Get out of here!
Don't follow us!
I can't breath.
Don't come closer! Look out!
It's gonna hit!
You! You! You!
My treasure!
Look you, give up on it already.
Men overboard, directly ahead!
Oh, that's...
my brother!
I'll never leave here! My treasure is
waiting for me down below!
You can come back for that!
Shut up! The whole thing started
with you making a submarine!
You caused the whole thing
by picking up that treasure!
Quiet! I'll wash your mouth with soap!
Are you asking for a fight?!
Sure, I am!
I'll teach you a lesson today!
Go ahead. I can't wait. Come on down!
- You come up here!
- Professor,
It seems like we're not going to move.
- You ugly hog!
- You old bacon!
Yes, it looks like they
have family issues...
- Shut up!
- Chicken!
You have a face like a lizard!
We missed Mrs. Hudson's
supper after all.
Do you want a fight?!
Fine! Don't talk about my face!
Likewise!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
There was a series of
postal air plane accidents...
between London and Paris.
One morning, one of the planes
crashed on Baker Street.
Mrs. Hudson was shaken up
when she saw the crash.
What is her untold past?
If you ever find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
The Air Battle Over Dover