FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Evil Genius, Professor Moriarty
Newspaper!
What?!
The crown of Mazalin?!
This is going to be a very rare catch!
The Banker Sampton's mansion...
Well then!
Well, his mansion is...
right here.
Darling, this is very enjoyable.
Right?
Yes, I'm having a lot of fun.
Mr. Sampton, I'm sorry to call on
you in the middle of your party.
Well, this is a very
important business meeting.
It was nice to meet you.
The pleasure was mine.
What's wrong?
This is very strange.
Mr. Sampton?
Uh?!
Zeal?!
Father, the crown of Mazalin is!
What?!
What about the crown of Mazalin?
It's gone!
The crown of Mazalin
has disappeared!
This could be a
big scandal, Mr. Sampton.
The crown of Mazalin
is a national treasure!
I... Indeed...
If it has been stolen...
Mr. Sampton,
who has access to this room?
Only me.
Oh! My son also knows
where I keep the spare key.
The spare key?
Your son?
It's not me!
It was gone when I came here!
But if only two people
could access this room...
It can't be. My son wouldn't...
I would like to think so... but...
I've heard so many rumours about him.
But that's...
Anyway, we should
call the police now.
Wait!
Zeal!
Let go of me!
Zeal...
Hurry up and call the police!
Eh, yes...
They're all a bunch of imbeciles.
They would never be
able to figure out my plan.
I'm Inspector Lestrade
of Scotland Yard.
Thank you for coming.
You are the inspector?
I was waiting for you.
As I asked you before...
you didn't allow anyone
to leave the house, did you?
Please help find the culprit.
Don't worry! I can take care of this.
I can solve even the most
difficult cases instantly.
Please help.
Are we already on Baker Street?
This is the street where
Sherlock Holmes lives, isn't it?
He has his own detective office.
You really never heard of him?
Oh?
It's very unusual,
you not knowing Holmes.
He's my best friend.
He can solve even the most
difficult cases quite easily!
I haven't happened on
any difficult cases, yet.
That's too bad.
I'm going to live with him.
Whoa!
Baker Street. 221 B. This is it.
We've finally arrived.
Oops.
Well, sorry about that.
Who is it?
Sorry I arrived so late.
Oh, I'm Watson. I'm sorry.
I was planning to
come here tomorrow morning.
But I arrived late tonight.
Holmes told me about you.
Please come in!
Uh... yes.
What's wrong?
Here, come inside.
Well, this is a very nice place.
Then, please come in.
What a beautiful...
Is something wrong?
Oh, no! Not at all.
Oh. Oops!
Do you need a hand?
No, of course not!
I'll show you the room.
Please follow me.
Yes.
She's so beautiful.
Mind your step.
Thank you. You are very kind.
This is it.
Well, this is a lovely room.
Do you like it?
Oh yes!
Of course I like it. Very quiet too.
There are flowers in the garden.
Besides, a beautiful lady like you...
I beg your pardon?
Oh!
I think beauty is peace.
By the way, where is Mr. Holmes?
He is already sleeping.
Please meet him tomorrow morning.
Good night.
This is completely ruining the party.
I wish they would let us go now.
Obviously, they didn't touch
anything but the crown.
The person who was
in this safe room was?
It was only Mr. Zeal,
the son of Mr. Sampton.
Right there!
That is the only door
to enter the safe room.
This was definitely an inside job.
And, there are only two people
who can enter this room.
Besides, Zeal has a fiancée
who Mr. Sampton hates.
A fiancée?
Perhaps this was his last resort since
Mr. Sampton was against them.
Uh? Who is it?
I have to say hello to the client
who requested this investigation.
Uh?
Welcome, Mr. Watson.
Oh my goodness!
This house has so
many beautiful women.
I'm sorry to tell you when you've just
woken up, but I must go out now.
What kind of case is it?
Let me help you.
Ms. Shields' fiancée
is being accused.
Oh, she is Ms. Shields.
Nice to meet you.
He is my best friend, Mr. Watson.
I'm Mr. Holmes' friend, Watson.
Nice to meet you...
Well, let's hurry.
Don't mind him.
Oh, well...
Hey, I'm coming, too!
I'll never believe that Zeal stole it.
But according to the witnesses...
Also, it wasn't a good idea to leave
the house without telling anyone.
Are you saying you don't
care if he gets caught?
Oh, no...
Mr. Holmes.
Please clear Zeal of suspicion.
I'll do my best.
The most important question is,
where is the missing crown now?
Those insects of Scotland Yard.
They'll never find it no matter
how much they search.
Well, they'll have to start
releasing the guests soon.
Uh?
What?! Who is that young jerk?!
I can't find the crown anywhere.
Damn it!
We can't find it in the house.
The scoundrel must have
taken it with him when he escaped.
Inspector!
Mr. Holmes is telling us to let him in.
What?! Holmes?!
Is he trying to stick his
nose into my investigation...
just because he's been
getting popular recently?
Inspector Lestrade,
I have no intention of disturbing you.
I'm a private detective.
I will go anywhere if I receive
a request to investigate.
A request to investigate?
Who hired you?
That is confidential.
I can't tell you now.
Confidential?
Oh, you mean Zeal,
the one who ran away.
So? Did I hit the mark?
You guessed completely wrong.
It would take a good plan
to get this crown.
That's right.
This was not a job anyone could do.
By the way, the spare key was
in the same place as usual?
Yes, I'm sure it was.
That means...
As I thought, a mark
where the door was forced.
Your son said he became suspicious
when he saw that the door was open.
Yes, he did.
So, we can deduce that the suspect...
wouldn't have escaped
through this door.
Uh?
Did you find something, Holmes?
Footprints.
Footprints?
And this hair.
This is too much.
It's impossible to escape from here.
Well, that's not necessarily true.
What?
The scratch mark of a hook.
A hook?
When Zeal and Mr. Sampton
entered the room...
the suspect was hiding
behind the curtain.
What?
But he couldn't use the door,
now that the crown was found missing.
So, he quickly escaped
from the window.
They came this far?
What?
New footprints.
Take it easy, or you'll
get hurt Holmes!
Holmes!
Uh, I barely managed to make it.
I don't think they could escape
going along the cliff.
Well, that's not true, either.
I found the rope the
suspect used to escape.
And the hook that made
the scratch on the window.
Then the suspect is!
Somebody in the party?
That's right.
Once the guests are released...
the suspect will come back
to pick up the crown.
We just have to wait for them.
Ouch, this was too tight.
We shouldn't do things
we're not used to.
It seems like we've done
a good job up to this point.
There's got to be a better
way to make a living than this.
We were better off as pirates.
Don't complain.
Just prepare for our next task.
I guess they barely
managed up to this point.
Are you sure Zeal is not here?
You will be equally guilty
if you're hiding him.
If you doubt me,
why don't you check inside?
He's not a suspect!
That's up to me to decide.
Listen here.
You have to let me know
if Zeal tries to contact you.
I'll know if you're lying.
Stop the car!
What?
She's hiding something.
We'll keep watching.
Yes, sir!
How is it?
Is there any sign of movement?
No, not yet.
Oh, wait! Don't go just yet!
Oh, Inspector Lestrade.
I remember you told me you
wouldn't disturb my investigation.
I have a pretty good idea
where the crown is.
We just have to wait for the suspect
to come back to pick it up.
W... What did you say?!
Are you kidding me?!
No, not at all.
I want you to help me with this.
Is that all right?
Of course.
Our purpose is to investigate
and solve the crime.
I appreciate that Inspector Lestrade.
But I'll need to talk to her first.
Uh. Oh.
Oh, Holmes!
After I finish talking to her,
please follow me.
What should we do, Inspector?
We have no choice!
How long do
you want me to wait!
I hope Mr. Holmes is not tricking us.
Holmes, is he really coming?
There he is.
I can hear.
There they are.
Get down.
How goes it Watson?
Shh!
Everybody stand by.
Oh, this is it.
We did it!
The Professor will be
very proud of us.
That is the crown of Mazalin!
Start your engines!
Go! Go! Go!
Ah! They're from Scotland Yard!
Turn on the engine!
Got it!
Holmes!
Hurry up and turn on the engine!
Where are you going Holmes?!
We'll beat them!
I see!
Wait! Give the crown back!
Hang on!
All right!
Don't lose them! Go on!
Well, you're not bad!
Try and get us!
Huh?
You can't treat me like that!
I won't let you escape!
Wait, wait, wait!
Use all the coal you can!
B... but...
That's an order!
Yes, sir!
Go! Go!
Everyone!
Prepare to attack immediately!
Just keep going,
even through fire or water!
We are the experts on water!
You can't beat sailors!
We've been waiting for you!
This is bad! Hard to port!
OK!!
Oops!
Stay in pursuit!
We will take care of this!
Almost there! After them!
This is not good! Go faster!
This is the maximum speed!
Good going!
Now, we will catch you!
Chase them!
Hey, stoke more coals!
Don't hesitate!
The suspects are extremely close!
Here! Here!
Go! Go on!
What are we gonna do?!
Run!
A cliff!
Take the helm!
It's too late!
Fools!
Hey! That's not fair!
We did it!
Bye bye!
Everybody! Start bailing water!
Go! Go!
After you've bailed the water,
go after them!
Don't hesitate!
Well! Good bye!
Good bye! Good bye!
Isn't it about time
you returned the crown?
If you don't,
I will have to force you!
I knew I shouldn't
have relied on them.
Damn it.
Take this, the chivalry of my family!
I'm a sailor and I won't take it!
Uh! It hurts!
But chivalrous spirit
will never die!
Holmes!
I will never let you have the crown.
I will take and keep it
with great care!
Don't worry!
The boss finally showed up!
Here we go!
Oh, no! I don't wanna get wet!
We will drown like this.
Sailors will never die.
We did it!
The crown!
The secret weapon.
Look out!
I won't let you have it!
Hey! We're here to help!
Thanks!
Take that!
Damn you, Lestrade!
Inspector, I'll return
the crown with care.
Oh, the crown!
Why don't you give up now?!
Oh drat!
Let's get out of here!
Hurry! Go faster!
It will fall apart if
we push it any more.
That's an order!
Full throttle! Do it!
Chase them! Don't let them beat us!
What?!
Damn it! Don't lose them!
Go! Chase!
Oops!
Chase! Chase! Full throttle! Go on!
I'm glad, Mr. Zeal.
Thank you very much.
But if Ms. Shields
hadn't acted bravely...
things would have
turned out differently.
I didn't know she
was such a great person.
I was wrong to separate them.
Then father...
Yes.
I'm so happy!
Please don't forget about the brave
person who helped the both of you.
Ouch, that hurts...
Somebody must be
talking about me again.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
English subtitled version produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
There are a large amount of counterfeit
silver coins circulating around London.
Inspector Lestrade is in a big jam.
This must be the work of
Professor Moriarty.
While that was going on,
a little client paid a visit to Holmes
Whenever you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Little Martha's Big Mystery!?