FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Buzz Buzz!
The Fly Fly Mecha Operation
Oops!
Professor, I can't hold on any more.
Deal with it!
We're almost to the jewels.
This is nothing, just a trifle.
Oh... I hate that sound.
Phew... we finally made it.
Shh! Quiet!
P... Professor, somebody's there.
Hey, that diamond!
Who are you?!
Amazing...
What was that noise?!
Who's there?!
Oh, rats!
Hey!
No! No, we haven't
stolen anything... yet...
Oh well... Run!
Hey, wait!
- Thief!
- Get them!
- This is bad.
- After them!
Hurry! Go!
Professor, how come things
always end up this way?
As if I should know.
Inspector!
Holmes, why are you here?
I'm investigating the case at the
request of the store owner.
From the eyewitness's testimony,
there's no doubt!
This was the work of
Moriarty and his gang.
There's no need to investigate.
Those three again...
I heard there was something
left at the scene of the crime.
Hey! Bring it here.
Yes, sir.
This is what was left in the safe.
How irritating!
They left an announcement of
their next caper, as well.
Good work.
Let's see.
"This was a mere trial run.
Be forewarned:
The fine royal horse,
Shoscom Prince, is next."
So, those three
escaped through this window?
No, through the other window,
according to the witnesses.
Fragments of broken glass are
scattered only on the outside.
This means that the window
was shattered from the inside.
So, you're saying that they
intentionally broke this window first...
then escaped through the other one?
That's right.
This was simply a failed
attempt at cheap camouflage.
Oh, well.
I must be off to the royal household.
Tell the store owner not to worry...
the police are certain to
bring the jewel back shortly.
Well, now...
What is it, Holmes?
Where are you going?
Here they are.
These are footprints.
They must belong to the person who
escaped through the broken window.
What?!
There is no doubt.
There was somebody other than Moriarty
and his henchmen in that room last night.
Someone who has very small feet.
We're supposed to be eating
a piece of steak this thick.
Professor, your food's ready.
Shut up!
This is no time for eating!
Curse you, whoever you may be,
for stealing my prize!
Professor...
Moreover, a false accusation
has been laid upon me!
Professor,
are you not going to eat?
If not, I'll finish it for you.
Idiot! Who said I'm not eating?!
Well, you've become famous
in any case, Professor. Right?
O... Oh, yes, right, Professor.
Left behind a red rose and an
announcement of the next crime.
How neat!
You idiots!
Have you no shred of pride?
Never think that Professor Moriarty
can be beaten like this.
Next time, I shall be the one
to steal his prize!
You two!
Go find out what was
in that announcement!
Right now?
How?
Shut up!
Figure it out yourselves!
Hurry up and go!
Holmes! Holmes, where are you?
I know you're in there.
What are you doing here?
Watch out, Inspector!
You opened the door too roughly.
Darn it all!
What is this about?!
I'm conducting an investigation.
Investigation?
You'll only find old records in here.
I remember hearing about a famous thief
who would leave at the scene of a crime...
a red rose and an announcement for
his next crime as his trademark.
Oh, you're talking about
"Christopher the Mysterious Thief".
Do you of know him, Inspector?
Of course.
Around the time I
first joined Scotland Yard...
this mysterious thief managed to
fluster the entire city of London.
Bold and gorgeous...
though he was an enemy,
he was very charismatic indeed.
This is it, Holmes.
Inspector, do you mind
if I take this with me tonight?
No, I don't, but...
Don't tell me you think this current
case is related to Christopher.
He was a thief more
than twenty years ago.
Those three are trying to imitate
Christopher the Mysterious Thief.
I don't know if you should conclude
anything without a full investigation.
What?! Are you trying to insult me?!
By the way, Inspector...
you went to inform the royal guards
about the crime letter, didn't you?
How did they react?
Unspeakably!
Inspector,
do you really believe that we...
the royal guards,
will dance to the magpies' piping?
They said they have no intention
of altering Shoscom Prince's escort...
scheduled for the day after tomorrow.
They said "no"...
In any case, I'll borrow this for now.
Excuse me.
Remember,
return the book by tomorrow!
Yes, yes.
What could he be thinking?
Morning, Watson.
What are you up so early for, Holmes?
Actually, daybreak came
while I was reading this.
You stayed up all night?
Did you find anything?
A lot of interesting facts.
He surely was a thief among thieves.
Always leaving a red rose and a
letter at the scene of the crime.
He drove the police mad back then.
However, he disappeared
after one case twenty years ago.
What was the case?
The fine royal horse abduction affair.
What?!
This was his only
failed attempt at thievery.
I mean, he did steal the horse.
However...
because the bridle snapped
during his escape...
he fell into the Thames.
He's been missing ever since then.
Holmes, it was Christopher
who stole the jewel then!
I doubt it.
Nothing has explained
his twenty-year absence...
and most importantly,
he was said to have a large build.
Don't you think the footprints
we found are too small for a big man?
Are you leaving?
I have to return the book
to Scotland Yard.
We promised to return it
after one night, didn't we?
Oh, are you going out?
Yes, I'll be back by dinner.
Take care.
Thank you.
Brother, what are we doing now?
I'm tired of standing here.
I know. How are we supposed to find
out what's in his crime message?
The press don't even know.
Let's ask that policeman over there.
You idiot!
You dropped this.
Uh, yes, thank you very much.
The case about that jewel thief,
who left a red rose and letter...
stating his next crime...
Everybody's been talking about
it since yesterday.
Oh, yeah? Really?
It's said in the letter
that the next target is tomorrow.
The fine royal horse,
Shoscom Prince.
Oh, really?!
Yes, or so I've heard, but I'm
not sure if it will really happen.
Scary, isn't it?
Those two men... they're...
Thank you, Miss!
Thanks!
Excuse me, Miss.
Do you know those two men?
No, they just asked me for directions.
May I ask who you are?
Pardon me.
I am a detective, Holmes.
It's just that they looked like
some people that I know.
So, are you the famous Mr. Holmes?
It is an honour to meet you.
Miss... Miss...
Excuse me, Mr. Holmes.
I must go now.
I hope to see you again.
Just asked directions, did they?
I understand it is your duty
to pursue the thieves...
but make sure you
do not get in our way.
Do you understand?
I do!
Both of you!
You can follow us if you want to...
but make sure
you don't interfere!
Do you understand?
Oh, my... Yes, I understand.
Who does he think he is?
We're leaving!
Inspector.
Shall we go?
Under such tight security,
the criminal will hardly have...
the chance to appear, will he?
Actually, my instincts tell me that it's
just about time for their appearance...
Look!
What is that?
There you are, Moriarty!
What? Smoke?! What is this?
OK, ready?
What's that?
Be calm! Protect the royal horse!
Where are they?
What happened to Moriarty
and his gang?
We don't know!
What's going on?
Keep your eyes on the royal horse!
It's difficult with all this smoke!
How's the horse?!
Is Shoscom Prince safe?!
Captain, I'll go get reinforcements!
Good, go!
Watson, let's go!
Right.
What the devil is going on?
Professor, I don't know,
but this is not good.
Let's just go home.
You fool! There will never be
a better chance than this!
Ready? Let's go!
Got it! Pull up!
Hey, stop that!
What are you doing?! Let me go!
Oops, wrong one!
Shake him off!
Professor, it's not possible.
It's broken.
You, idiot! Fool!
Drat! I built it too hastily.
I guess I'll go then.
You there, down you go! Down!
What?! You worthless idiot!
Get your foot off of my face!
Darn it!
How lucky! The royal horse!
Here we go!
So long, Inspector Lestrade!
You villain, Moriarty!
Get him!
Yes, Sir!
Catch me if you can!
Stop right there, Moriarty!
Hey, what's going on here?
Hey, Mr. Royal Horse,
can't you run any faster?
All right, get him!
We've almost got him.
Go!
Come on!
Faster, I said faster!
What is this?
"I have stolen the royal horse."
What?!
Holmes, what's wrong
with that horse?
Look carefully at how
he runs and his speed.
You'll see that it's
no ordinary horse.
What? Then, that one is the...
Hold on!
Oh, no!
Ouch!
Here!
Hang in there! Hold on!
Yes, good horse.
There you go.
Ready to talk, Alline Christopher?
Holmes, Christopher?
So then...
You win, Detective.
What is...
Alline, is the daughter of Christopher,
the mysterious thief, aren't you?
Yes, I certainly am.
Please! I'm begging you, run faster!
Have you given up yet?
We're almost there.
Brother! I found him!
OK, let's drop this noisy fool off.
Ah! What are you doing?!
You're going to kill me!
I'll die!
Nice! Let's get out of here!
My father was a top merchant
and a fine gentleman.
But he passed away
after a terrible illness.
My mother and I have been
grieving deeply ever since.
One day, when I was cleaning his study,
I came upon his old diary.
In it, I saw his other face, known to all
as Christopher the Mysterious Thief.
You knew everything at that point.
I see, it must have been quite shocking
to learn that your father was a thief.
No, it was exciting to discover that my
father had such an exciting past!
What?
How bitter it must have been for him,
hurting his leg...
and having to retire
from the business!
So, I was determined to complete the
work he'd been forced to leave undone!
I see...
That's right. Almost! A little lower!
Wait!
Moriarty, you won't get away!
Oh, he's finally giving up the horse!
Shoscom Prince is back!
Shosom Prince,
I'm so glad you're safe.
Wait a minute... this horse?
This is a phony!
What?!
Would you straighten yourself out?
I hear you Professor, but nothing
seems to be working correctly.
You fool, that's because
your pitiful skills are...
Hey you!
Moriarty, what did you do with
the royal horse?!
You dirty thieves, return the horse!
I'm innocent! It was already
the wrong horse when I fell on it.
You lying rat!
No, stop! What're you doing?! Let go!
Never! Return the horse!
I told you I'm innocent!
I know you're lying!
Here!
Hey, let go! Don't bother me!
Too heavy.
My arms are falling off...
No, don't be silly!
That's more weight than
this machine can hold!
Ouch!
Brother, look out!
I told you so!
We made it!
You certainly look awful.
Have a look at yourself.
So, are you going to arrest me?
Well, let's see.
We're not policemen.
So, as long as you return
the jewel and horse...
I never meant to keep them anyway.
Then, will you promise that
you will never do this again?
I suppose I have no choice,
it was a lot of fun, though.
A good thief must also
know when to quit!
The case's closed.
A good thief must know when to quit...
I wish they could hear this.
Indeed, if they could.
Say, Professor.
Let's give up and retire
from this business.
You fool! I won't quit until
I'm known as the "Napoleon of Crime!"
Oh, we'll never get out from this.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Just before the start of the World
Aircraft Championship Race in Holland...
a high-performance engine
is stolen from Mac Bain...
a brilliant aeronautical engineer.
The cunning Professor Moriarty
aims to win the air race...
by using the stolen engine.
Which is thoroughly unacceptable!
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Grand Flight Championship of Chaos!?