FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
The Monster of the Thames River
Hey, the fog is getting very thick!
Keep a sharp eye out!
Yes Sir.
What?! What's wrong?!
Something bumped against
the bottom of the ship!
Stop!
No! Go forward!
What?!
Everybody!
Abandon ship right now!
Abandon ship!
The Monster of the Thames River
attacked a cargo ship.
What do you think of that, Mr. Holmes?
What do you mean?
The monster made thunderous sounds
and swallowed the ship with one gulp.
Dinosaurs are supposed to have been
extinct for 70 million years.
However, I wouldn't doubt it if
some had miraculously survived.
I think it could be possible.
Watson, as a scientist,
you are a surprising romantic.
How amusing.
Well, it's just kind of a dream.
I think it's not so strange to believe
that dinosaurs have survived.
But, I doubt they want
to eat cargo ships.
That was wonderful, David!
Bravo! Bravo!
Encore! Encore!
David, encore!
You're embarrassing me.
Don't be shy.
You won a gold medal
at the last competition.
You have great skill.
Please play for everybody
one more time.
I understand, Mary.
Then, I'll play for you with love.
Operation! Stand by!
Professor, we're ready!
Well, let's begin!
- Yes, sir!
The Loch Ness Monster
comes out now!
Bravo!
Thank you very much.
Hey.
All right.
Cheers to that beautiful
song and your love!
Here!
Oh, thank you!
Thank you!
Well, it's already late.
We have to go home now.
Have a safe trip!
- Good luck!
What is that?!
A monster!
The oar!
David!
Swim to the shore!
Mary!!
David!
It's dangerous, Miss!
David! David!
Where are you, David?!
David!!
Haven't you found anything yet?
Well, it's too dark here.
Oh, I felt something!
What?!
Search more thoroughly!
David...
Yes.
I'm sorry to bother you
so early in the morning.
I really wanted to see Mr. Holmes.
Here, come inside please.
Thank you.
May I see him right now?
Yes, he's waking up about now.
Inspector Lestrade searched
for him down river.
However, they couldn't
find the slightest trace.
But David did not sink to
the bottom of the river.
I know David is still alive.
Miss Mary.
We made a promise to be
married in the future.
David will keep that promise,
no matter what happens.
Mr. Holmes, I also believe...
in their bonds of love.
Excuse me.
Mr. Holmes!
Can you give me 10 minutes
to prepare to leave?
No make that 5 minutes.
Thank you Mr. Holmes.
I don't see anything strange.
We did it!
This time, not even Detective
Holmes will figure out this mystery!
Ouch!
Who put a table here?!
You did.
What? Did I? That can't be!
You said we have to prepare
the party to celebrate.
Oh, yeah, I remember that.
Then, let's make a toast.
Open the champagne.
This is tight.
Hurry it up!
What the?!
Smiley, what's wrong?
This is like a dream,
all this gourmet food.
I understand Smiley.
All we've been eating is the hard
crusts of bread with water.
But!
Thank you for being patient
and working for me to this day.
I appreciate it.
Professor!
I won't let you suffer any more.
Goodbye to sorrow,
hello to happiness.
We'll have wonderful days
continuously from now on!
As long as the Thames River exists!
Our victory is...
That's really noisy!
It's the brat!
Do you want me to shut him up?
Well, wait...
he's a rare guest.
Let's invite him to the table.
Bring him.
That's a flute, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
I remember you!
You are the genius boy
flute player David...
who won the championship
at the last competition.
If you know me, then please
return me to the surface!
Please!
That's impossible.
I want you to remain
a hostage just in case.
How come?
Didn't you find any clues?
Unfortunately, I still
haven't found anything.
As I feared.
Miss, please don't be disappointed.
I'm sure there is
some way to find him.
There was nothing at
the bottom of the river.
There is only one person who could
conceive and carry out a ruse like this.
Here goes!
Holmes, be careful!
I know.
Oh, the tide is on the ebb.
David!
Hey! Watch out!
What are you?!
Let me go!
I saw David over there!
Miss, it's just your imagination.
What was I doing?
Well, you gave me quite a scare.
I'm very sorry.
Watson, let's check from
the boat one more time!
Oh, wait!
Holmes, what's going on?
I believe we've found the
monster's hideout.
Take a look.
Let me see.
That steel plate must be
the entrance of the hideout.
But it's under water.
Under steel plates as well.
It won't be easy to open.
Let's get some help from
inspector Lestrade and the Navy.
This is...
Here's the trick...
the monster comes out, swallowing
the cargo ship loaded with goods.
Surprised?
This is an amazing machine.
But I'm sure somebody
will find this soon!
I'm afraid not.
Not only Inspector Lestrade,
but the famous Detective Holmes...
is having a hard time
investigating this case.
He's already given up.
Mr. Holmes?
Well, not because Holmes didn't have
the ability to figure this out...
it's just that my genius brain is
superior, and has brought me victory.
Fortunately we found
an old scrap ship.
We will decorate it and make it
look like a new ship now.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Well, let's move on quickly!
But be careful with those goods!
Inspector, how long will it take?
Well, I think they can finish loading
the goods in about one hour.
Then, we have to hurry too.
Oh, Holmes, are you sure we can beat
the monster just by doing this?
Everything is perfect.
Please do just as we have planned.
If the enemy made a
fortification under the river...
they have to have
a place to let in air.
But, so far I can't find
the spot anywhere.
I might have overlooked it.
Maybe we should go back again.
Mr. Holmes?
Hey!
Holmes!
I brought the longest
rope, just like you asked.
Thank you.
Did you find any clues?
I already found one.
There is no need for a
chimney in a warehouse.
Do you think you can
catch anything today?
So far, I've only seen a small barge.
You don't have to rush.
I'm sure a big target will appear soon.
Mary, I won't give up until the end.
Here you go.
I can hear David playing the flute.
David.
I'm sure this must be connected
to the underwater fortification.
It sounds very noisy.
Let me stop his playing.
Wait!
Beautiful music is great nutrition
for the genius brain.
Make sure he keeps playing.
Well, but I have a bad feeling.
Mr. Holmes, be careful.
Yes, yes.
Can you tell Inspector Lestrade...
to have the ship
leave in five minutes.
All right, I will.
Now begins the extermination
of the monster...
and we will rescue David.
Is anything wrong?
The flute stopped.
W... who are you?
I'm Holmes, I'm here to take you back.
Here, come quickly.
Yes.
Todd, can you go and tell him
to keep playing the flute?
All right.
What's that noise?
It sounds very suspicious.
Professor!
What?
I see a big ship coming close to us.
What?!
Lestrade!
The Inspector is guarding it himself.
That ship must be carrying
very valuable goods.
This is going to be a big catch.
Professor, what about his flute?
Fool!
This is not a time to worry about it.
Hurry! Hurry up!
Go into the action right now!
Wait for me!
Great, reverse the engine.
Move Point Two to the right.
The distance to the
target is thirty meters.
Turn on the light.
Inspector, it's here!
Great!
Now, ignite the fuses!
Close the lid tightly.
If water gets in, we're finished.
Abandon ship!
Hurry!
We did it! A great success!
What are the goods this time?
They had heavy security.
I'm sure it will be gold bullion.
Gold bullion?!
We can eat gourmet food again!
We did it!
Hey Holmes, it's them again.
Yes.
Don't let them go!
Moriarty! I will arrest you this time!
Curses!
You get more annoying every week!
Here we go!
Fools!
Why don't you come and catch us?!
What?!
Take that!
That's as far as you go!
Enjoy your rest!
Hey! Do a U turn! A U turn!
Go!
Don't let them go!
Go! Move! Move!
Even through fire and water!
I have a great respect for
Inspector Lestrade's fighting spirit.
Well, that's true.
You won another victory
with this case.
No.
Their love is the real victory.
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Foggy London...
a young man visited Holmes
while he was bored.
He asked Holmes to look for
three missing students.
When Holmes began the investigation...
he found traces
of them unexpectedly.
If you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Blundered Operation
at Loch Ness!