FAMOUS DETECTIVE HOLMES
The sound of the clock tower bell
Machi ni nagareteru
tokeidai no kaneno oto
Open the window
when the fog clears away
Kiriga haretanara
mado wo akete goran
A shadow reaching out
over the stone pavement
Ishidatamini kagega nobiru
That is a sound called love
Aito yuunano ashioto
Nothing can be hidden
away from my eyes...
Kakusenaisa bokuno hitomiwa
Even little things
Honno chiisana koto made
Nothing can be hidden,
for soon comes the happy ending...
Kakusenai sa yagate happy end
Will arrive in your mailbox
Kimino posuto ni todokuyo
A story that fell from the sky
Sorakara koboreta sutori
Little Martha's Big Mystery!?
Thank you.
I'm Inspector Lestrade
from Scotland Yard.
I was waiting for you.
This way please.
We've just gotten started.
There are so many silver coins.
If there are any counterfeit coins
mixed in, we can detect them easily.
I got a report.
There are some well made
counterfeit coins in circulation.
Yeah.
Oh, those coins have
already been investigated.
R... really!
I found it!
Just as we thought!
This is definitely counterfeit.
It looks just like a real coin, but...
Look at this!
This is a real one.
The edge looks slightly different.
I'm not sure.
It looks exactly the same.
Please come over here.
You can see the difference
if you compare the weight.
This is the fake one
and this is the real one.
See! It's different.
This is probably made from
an alloy of nickel and silver.
I found one over here!
We've already found two.
This means...
Oh, this one, too.
As I thought!
This is a much bigger
issue than I thought.
I found two more here!
What?
Oh, this one too!
Give me a container!
Can I have one too?
Wait a minute!
This one is fake, too!
Just a minute!
Inspector!
This is the biggest
counterfeit money scheme...
in the history of Scotland Yard.
The latest news! Counterfeit money
discovered all over!
An economic downturn has started
due to the counterfeit money.
Holmes, are you going
to leave this one alone?
I will do a little research.
There's only one person who
would plan this kind of thing.
Fools!
They are all panicking.
"The first ever perfectly
made counterfeit money."
Humph! They don't know anything.
They should call this
"a great work of art".
Brother, the cart is overflowing.
Shut up!
I'm concentrating now!
But, the Professor will get angry.
Don't be afraid of the Professor!
We're the ones working
and supporting him.
Professor!
Damn you!
Why don't you hurry up
and get to work!
Yes Sir!
Ouch!
You have to ship one more ton tonight!
My lovely little press machine.
Make more and more! Speed up!
I will fill this country with my coins!
Oh, no!
Stop!
Oh, this is great!
Brother, look!
I found this thing, too.
Oh, let me see.
Hey! Don't play with it!
Bring that engineer we locked up!
Yes, sir!
I refuse!
Now that I know you're
making counterfeit money...
you think I would help you?
I'm not asking you work for free.
I will pay you in real
gold coins, forty guineas.
I don't want money! Let me go home!
As soon as you fix my press machine,
you can go home.
But if you refuse, then I'll have
to find another engineer.
And you will never see London again.
I don't care either way.
I have no choice.
Oh! Then you'll do it?!
Yes, but in return, I want to write
a letter to my family.
They must be worried about me since
I haven't been home for a while.
A letter... all right.
However, you must keep this a secret!
Bring him a pen and paper!
I know what you're really thinking.
You're gonna tear up
the letter without telling him.
Mail the letter out.
But, you must thoroughly
check what he writes.
It's better than people talking about
a missing press machine engineer.
All the news is devoted to the
counterfeit money scheme.
Holmes didn't come
home last night again.
The investigation may have
come to a dead end.
That's correct!
Holmes, welcome back!
How'd it go?
I wasted my time.
I see.
As I thought, the suspect
is Professor Moriarty.
But he is not in London right now.
That's the only thing
I've been able to determine.
Hey, you look very tired.
Not really.
Not really?
Well, you didn't get any
sleep for the last three days.
I don't want you to catch cold.
Here you are.
Do you need to see Mr. Holmes?
Okay.
This way please.
He's on the second floor.
She's a bit small for a client.
Um... Is she visiting Holmes?
Yes.
This isn't a good time.
Mr. Holmes is very tired right now.
He's sleeping.
Why do you want see him?
Old man, are you a detective?
Well, I'm... do I have to be
a detective to help you?
Yes.
She came visiting after she
saw this newspaper.
Oh, let me see.
"Detective Holmes
preformed great deeds".
This is last week's paper.
Little girl, can you read this?
No, my neighbour
John read it for me.
Really... so what's your case?
I'm looking for Mrs. Holly.
Mrs. Holly... she must be a woman.
She's a cat.
A cat?!
Yeah.
She is a very big cat.
Really?
You must have been
taking care of her.
No, she's a stray cat.
She's really scary looking,
and has a scar from a burn on her ear.
A scar from a burn...
Did you ask your
parents to look for her?
My mum died a long time ago.
My papa hasn't come
back for a long time.
I see.
Watson!
Holmes?
I heard your story.
Here, young lady, come inside.
Okay.
Can you wait a moment?
Hey, are you seriously going
to look for a stray cat?
How can I send her away?
She walked all the
way from the East End.
The East End?
Can't be! It would take three hours.
I could tell by looking
at the mud on her shoes.
It must be something very serious.
I see.
I thought she was
from the neighbourhood.
This is?
Oh, that's last week's paper.
No, that's not it.
The help wanted
column is marked in red.
She brought this here.
"Press Machine Specialist wanted.
High Pay."
Press machine... she said her father
hasn't come home for a while.
Uh? Yes.
They used a large sized press machine
to make the counterfeit money.
Your father didn't come back
after he left for work...
and then you received this letter?
Yes.
"Dear Martha, I suddenly have to go
abroad because of work."
"Please don't worry about me."
"If you have any problems,
you should talk to Mrs. Holly."
She should talk to a cat
that's already disappeared?
Martha, what are you going
to talk to Mrs. Holly about...
after you've found her?
That I want to see my papa.
Holmes, Mrs. Holly could be
some kind of code.
All right! Let's look for Mrs. Holly!
Really?!
But...
You have to finish the cocoa, otherwise
Mrs. Hudson would be disappointed.
Yes!
Over there.
Martha came back!
Mr. Holmes, over here!
Huh, you really brought him?!
You must be John.
Can you take care of Martha
for a little while more?
Yes.
Mum!
Martha came home!
Mrs. Holly was always over there.
Inside that dent
in the roof, over there.
I can't see it from here. Watson!
Is Holly in that dent in the roof?
You can't see from here.
There's a tree blocking the view.
Hey, Martha, how do you
know when Holly was there?
When you can't see her from here.
There is a very small hole in the wall.
Over here!
See! It's here.
You can't see like that.
Put paper on it.
I see! A pinhole camera!
See!
This hole was opened with a pen.
S...
O...
SOS... I need help.
E, Y, F, O, R, D... Eyford...
the name of the place.
Holly...
Where are you?
E, C, that's everything.
What is that?
Watson, are you all right?
Oh, thank you.
Martha...
can I put looking for Holly on hold
and look for your papa first?
Sure, I'd like to find papa first, too.
All right! Be good and wait here.
Watson, we don't have much time.
We have to go right now.
Where are we going?
First of all, Scotland Yard!
Hey! Wait a second! Stop!
Inspector.
Mr. Holmes!
What's going on?!
I'll explain after we get on the train.
This is the last train to go to Eyford!
Wait up!
Hang on!
It's been three days!
When on earth will you fix it?!
I can start operating
the machine this evening.
This evening?
You better not be mistaken!
Note the words marked with keyholes.
Let's see... S. O. S. Eyford,
one H, false C...
One H is one hour.
I deduced that this means
one hour from Eyford.
I see! False C means false coin!
The false money!
I think the hideout for the
counterfeiters is one hour from Eyford.
Martha's father must
be imprisoned in there.
Well, leave the rest to me!
I'll issue a search order.
Take this!
This is bad!
Wonderful! A revival of the art!
I finished my job.
Why don't you let me go home?
Well, well, don't be such a hurry.
Make yourself comfortable.
You tricked me!
Your job is done.
Thank you for your hard work.
Take him.
Are you going to kill me?
Yes! We have no choice!
Oh, no!
I forgot something very important.
Don't move!
I forgot to tighten one
of the important screws.
What?
Hah! Don't try such a lame trick!
It's your choice...
but the machine will explode
without this screw.
B... Brother...
Give it to me.
Ahh! Oh, no!!
You won't escape!
B... Brother, I found the screw.
Idiot! Bring it to the Professor!
Open up!
Damn it!
Stupid! This machine is working fine!
Huh? Eh?
I'll go!
You fool! What are you doing?!
This door is!
Bring me a log!
Yes! Yes!
It's impossible to get down from here.
The train station was this close?
This way please.
This is Eyford station.
One hour from the station is about
10 miles by horse-drawn wagon.
It must be somewhere
around this area.
Are there any big
buildings around there?
There are only farms and ranches.
The area is so huge.
We'll have to split up and search.
Men, split into four separate parties!
Search suspicious looking
buildings one by one!
Go!
Wait a second, detective!
Is there any building close by,
making a big noise?
Close by?
Uhm... somebody in town
is drilling for oil.
I heard noises coming
from one of the buildings.
That's it!
Show it to me.
Ride thirty minutes out and
ride another thirty minutes back.
That's an old trick
used to hide a location.
Charge!
Damn it!
Fall! Fall! Fall!
- Pistol!
- Yes!
Bullets! Bullets!
Yes! Yes!
- Bullets... bullets... where?
- Hurry up!
Hurry up!!
Holmes!
Surround them!
Oh, so many people!
Run!
Here!
Scrum!
Now!
Follow 'em!
Holmes!
Hang on!
Thank you.
- Surrender! Open up!
- Hurry up!!
Yes.
Scrum! Hurry!
Damn it!
Scrum one more time!
You'll need dynamite
to break that door down!
Damn it! Load it up quickly!
Yes! Yes!
Professor!
Professor!!
What?
Look.
The screw!
Everyone!
Don't panic!
Let's panic, in this case.
Let's go.
Thank you very much.
You all saved my life.
No, we only assisted Martha and you.
That letter was very clever.
Do you think Moriarty
and his henchmen are dead?
Who knows?
They seem to like going underground.
Damn you, Holmes.
You'll pay for this!
Ah! L... Look at this, brother.
I'm already looking!
Papa!
Martha!
Papa! Papa!
I'm back Martha.
Welcome back.
Good day.
Goodbye!
When the morning comes...
Mezameta tokiniwa...
your bed is empty
Anatano bedo wa karappo
Beyond the balcony,
the town reveals its appearance
Veranda goshini mietayo machikado
Tell me what you find on your walk...
Naniwo mitsuketaka oshiete
sanpo no tochuude...
back from the
fountain in the park
Hikikaeshite kuru hirobano hunsui
24 hours a day,
something is dancing in your mind
Nijuyojikan, atamanonakade nanikaga...
That is how you are
Dansu shiteiruhito nandakara
Subtitled Version Produced by
PIONEER ENTERTAINMENT (USA) INC.
In association with
NEW GENERATION PICTURES
Executive Producer
HENRY GOTO
Producers
SATOSHI FUJII, REIKO MATSUO
& JONATHAN KLEIN
Subtitlers
BRETT JACOBSEN, DIANA TOLIN,
AKI MATSUMOTO & MAKOTO SHIRAI
Professor Moriarty keeps failing.
But this time he's
kidnapped Mrs. Hudson.
He is planning to use
Mrs. Hudson as a hostage...
to make unreasonable
demands on Holmes.
Poor little Mrs. Hudson,
I'll be sure to rescue you.
Whenever you find yourself in a mystery,
please come see us at Baker Street.
Mrs. Hudson is Taken Hostage